<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - chronograph</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Living for myself</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-31-for-myself.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have felt for quite some time now that I cannot live for myself. Every time I try to figure it out I end up feeling my only choice would be to end my life. Now, almost a year into reality I am questioning again if it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to believe all my actions have some other benefactor in mind which is unlikely. I tend to claim I have no friends and suck at making them. Aside from a few people, cisgender people are a strong source of envy for me so I don't end up befriending them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who reads this drivel is likely shaking their head at my bullshit. Which is fine. I don't really care. But it does make me think about what my life is actually like. To be someone in my shoes, with my bullshit, it's a lovely show isnt't it? All I ever wanted in life was to be a barefoot prancing little wood fairy but I cannot be any of those things. So this is what I settle for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I am to survive all this I'm quite sure I will need to find a reason to live for myself. Will that day ever come?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-31:/posts/2018-03-31-for-myself.html</guid></item><item><title>Is this really the life I'm stuck with?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what I'm doing. I have this drive to be something of a martyr, a public figure or at least a devout public servant. All of me screams in anger about my situation while dragging my stupid life towards this goal of living with a purpose designed to serve others and not myself. I am fine with this aim. I've never expected much for my life, at least not in a real way. I had small hopes before but nothing like this. This I am because a future in this body is bleak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pain limits me from having the life I always dreamed of. I'm capable of that dream, but not with this pain. I can't simply power through the pain. My prognosis is slow decay. And while I am trying hard to be as healthy as possible I cannot change everything at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write laying in bed wondering if I will conquer this. If I will find myself in another two, five years laughing with my hands on my hips pain free and able to live the life I always dreamed of. Maybe I'm just getting one step closer to acceptance of the life I am trapped in. Pushing myself beyond limits for everyone but myself. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-15:/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</guid></item><item><title>I just had a glimpse of how I might gain weight</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-11-glimpes-of-fat.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I adore empathy. In turn this really means I love imagination. It is through using my imagination and wholly attempting to live it, I am able to create such empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after gourging on food, I went out for another snack. As I was eating I realized my stomach was still mostly full, but I was cramming it in anyway. But I wanted to eat. I was compelled to eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it flashed before my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hate being skinny, so I finally pushed to be a person who eats a lot so I can gain weight. I start the habit of eating more and more. Eventually I can't stop. I have been so skinny my whole life I don't really care I now have a little too much weight. And suddenly, I'm well overweight but still sitting down and eating another food because in my mind, I am so satisfied I am not underweight. I will never be underweight again. Ever. So I eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if this means I am going to start the path of finally gaining weight. Not exactly in the extreme way this day dream played out, but still. Or is this simply a bout of fleeting imagination which will result in nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to see it as a sign, but I'd rather make it sign.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-11:/posts/2018-03-11-glimpes-of-fat.html</guid></item><item><title>Shedding responsibility and happy about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a few years I was a pseudo leader at a support group in my area for transgender people. I was the legally responsible emissary for a couple of years. I have since left and failed to hand over responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a recent meeting and spoke with someone who I am excited about handing the reigns over to. Well, they already had them a bit. So I'm more like empowering them and validating their value by giving them responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sad, for in a way, I never truly got to exercise the value I carried for the support group before I left. In my unreality, I was always too anxious and shameful to engage in the way I could have. So I watched and prodded from a place in the back, rather than right in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired to do something of value before I leave again, I am taking on a couple of responsibilities to get the group admin stuff moving again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to let go. I am happy there are others with similar views as me. I am happy knowing I made an impact on a group I feel is absolutely vital to my community.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</guid></item><item><title>Another sick day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No vomiting this time thankfully. However right before I set out to a friend's place I felt so dizzy and nauseous I had to lie down. I did the off and on sleeping thing for about four hours. And after some food and gobs of water I began to feel better. It's 2am right now. I have to do things tomorrow. Ugh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-25:/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</guid></item><item><title>Burning memorabilia while purging</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I burnt thousands of pages. A lot with sensitive medical data I would not like floating around. Others simply records of experiences I've lived in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This being the second time burning like this, I felt more prepared for the shift in perspective afterwards. Symbolically I destroy ties to the past I used to care deeply for. I will always be an archivist. However, my urges to do so with physical things is all but extinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me to thinking about what forms of physical archival fits my new perspective on life. Here's my list so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jewelry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tattoos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Film Pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trinkets small enough to enclose a fist over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical items (tools, storage, lifestyle enhancements)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the trend is keeping clutter out of life. Using small and or practical items to impart the symbol into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am feeling it is of little use to recall all of life with great detail. Distilling key memories and placing their importance into a small or  practical item is all that is needed to remember what made you the way you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you hold tightly to the memories, the less willing you may be to change. Too much focus on the past and you will stay there. Too much focus on the future and you may never get there. The present is the most practical place to be in any given moment. Although, never leaving the present makes it very difficult to grow and change with intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love change ^_^&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-21:/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</guid></item><item><title>Stuck in MA for a bit.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-20-stuck.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't know what I will write during the rest of the month, but I figured I'd at least outline what the plan is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am stuck in MA for a while. Since my parents are planning to sell the house this summer, I am spending a large chunk of my time getting rid of my crap. Ripping DVDs, throwing out stuff, donating, giving away, putting up for sale, cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also putting a lot of energy into staying away from depression and depletion. It is so easy in the winter to hibernate and do nothing because of how the cold effects my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I plan to be social with people here. I've got some people I would like to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully everything goes okay, I get back on the road before February, and things keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-20:/posts/2018-01-20-stuck.html</guid></item><item><title>Sick day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-11-sick.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A remarkable thing happened. I woke up at my mother's house the first day and felt nauseous. I threw up a couple times and spent all day in bed. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why? If this type of sick occurred in Vanessa it would have been horrifying. I am not prepared for that. I should be prepared for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I get myself back together for this week. I've got a ton of shit going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ugh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-11:/posts/2018-01-11-sick.html</guid></item><item><title>New Years 2018</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-01-new-year.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This new years eve was better than any other year of my life! What I love the most is how today is today, and while I am recalling yesterday for the sake of history, I am here today and that's it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I played my violin and made $50. The weather was just nice enough to really enjoy myself. Two moments stood out to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple dressed rather nicely began taking photos in front of me while I played. Two other women watched as I played. I couldn't believe it. Here I am playing this weird music while the couple almost dances in front of me, seemingly with no clue I am transsexual. How incredibly validating! However I guess that assumes if they knew, they wouldn't take photos with me right? Sigh...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next moment was when I was packing up. A woman from the candle shop I was playing in front of came out and offered me a free candle! I was planning to say hi anyway since she came out, complimented me and gave me a dollar. We chatted for a bit. It was very nice to know my music was appreciated by at least one of the establishments I bothered with my music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I was finally ready for a second set waiting the arrival of my friend. I sat by another busker who dropped me a dollar earlier and asked if I would play with him! Exactly what I've been hoping to do. Exactly what I told my other musician friend I was going to work on! We played a few songs together and it was awesome and scary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second set went just as well. I made a total of $100. Then my friend and I got food, met up with his friends, and spent the time in a tipsy painful state barely keeping it together. It was kinda awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How am I so lucky?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-01:/posts/2018-01-01-new-year.html</guid></item><item><title>A long overdue update. The world is a weird place</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-12-26-long-overdue.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been up to so much in the last two weeks. I have hardly had time to write about it all. I will recap in this post, but I am thankful I still managed to write more than what you'll see here in a different place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I noticed was how I met so many people and told so many stories I forgot who I told what and had strange moments of deja vu and poor recollection. Everything outside of now felt so distant and unimportant. I don't fully understand what that means but it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here's what you missed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="reunion"&gt;Reunion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reconnected with the girl I met back in May. This was a very important reunion for me. During our first encounter she said to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't know what you are do you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"No and I like to keep it that way".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately after saying that I felt how sad it was. That I wanted to remain distant from what I am. This small part stuck with me the whole summer and played a big role in my progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the second night we hung out I rode her motorcycle which really fucked me up and I crashed in front of her. Embarrassing for me, but she was a sweetheart about it. I am grateful for her energy, presence, and impact on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="busking"&gt;Busking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I went to St Augustine and tried busking for the first time. Before I could go out I sat in a coffee shop and tried to get psyched up. I spoke with a younger kid about programming which boosted my confidence before heading downtown. It's saturday so free parking amok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I landed first at the end of St George st by the castle. I setup and started playing. IT was hard and cold. I made $18. Then I crashed for a bit and warmed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then wandered around looking for another spot and sat next to a guy who looked like a performer. He was. Trumpet. We spoke about busking and it made me feel quite good. I found my second spot at Treasury and Charlotte. I made almost $30 this time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so fucking proud of myself. Performing in the concert changed everything about my confidence. I am filled with joy and happiness because I can play again. I can play for me and in front of people! IT feels so fucking good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After beaming, I drove out to Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orlando"&gt;Orlando&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a whole week jammed into one. My mother had given me a week at a hotel using her timeshare for a break in the van.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first day, Sunday I met up with a girl who and chatted over coffee. She told me about a trans event later that week which I was really excited to go to. While checking in to the hotel I befriended an employee who invited me to drinks that night. She is very pretty. It was quite awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, Monday, I wake up and went to a sales presentation for timeshare stuff. A challenge for me to make sure I don't get pressured to spend money. I invited the boy at the end over for pizza which was rough. Very interesting meeting people I don't really connect with. I learn a lot about myself that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday I spent a long time on the computer and mosied over downtown for ad ate with a girl I met way back in April. She canceled however so I just went back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday I relaxed more and landed at the trans event. There I met a bunch of people, drank and ate food. One girl caught my eye and we connected. So I followed her to another bar then took her back the hotel and spent time in the jacuzzi. Such a sweetheart she offered to take me to Universal Studios on Friday! Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday I finally got to meet up with my violin inspiration. The girl I met at a violin shop who I came out to because of national coming out day. Since I knew I might see her, I pushed myself to go busking before we met up. The universe clearly wanted me to go busking. It was really nice filling in more about her from the few moments we shared almost six months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday I went to Universal with my friend. We walked around together and thoroughly enjoyed it. After she left for work I spent another four hours in the park pushing myself to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday I spent lying in bed recovering. I packed up and spent a little time with the employee I met my first day. Then I landed in St Augustine so I could busk during the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="christmas"&gt;Christmas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas Eve I woke up in downtown St Augustine determined to make some cash. I got myself out around 11am. I setup at Hypolita and Spanish street. I got real hot in the sun and made about $20. After a break I setup at Cuna and Charlotte. I made $50 in an hour! Holy shit. After another break I setup at St Geroge and Orange st. I barely played because I hurt so bad I couldn't play anoymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This crushed me so much I hobbled back to Vanessa. I made some food and lied in bed for a really long time before going to Walmart to sleep. I hurt so badly I could barely sleep. And I didn't. I woke up at 1am even after taking my meds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we're in Christmas day now. I can't sleep so I roll over to Seven Eleven to get something to drink. The employee was so nice to me. He gave me water, ice and free food. Then I crawled over to the pier at the ocean and waited for sunrise. I fell asleep again but got woken up by the same employee bearing more food for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I am up and watch the sunrise. It was beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked around trying to pawn all the extra pastries, but no one wanted them. Not surprising. Sugar pastries. Ya. Well I did have a good conversation with one of the men. He was really considerate and willing to offer advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got out busking at Cuna and St George. I was feeling pretty good buy also very vulnerable. So many people had access to my music without needing to get close. IT was a very different feel than the other spots. But I actually got plenty of money quickly. And I was having fun. Lots of eye contact and smiles. And then...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girl I messaged on OKCupid when I first got into St Augustine was standing in front of me! WHAT?! She had told me she wasn't feeling well enough to meet up in the morning so I was very surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a great time together. Coffee, walking, food. It was so cool to have such a spontaneous encounter with someone who truly captivated me. I spent the night in the parking lot of her apartment and we spent the morning together too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fin"&gt;Fin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woah right? I've been social like 21 of the last 23 days...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the streak continues with events upcoming. So eager for the future. Thank you universe. Thank you Luna for choosing to be the way you are and fighting to make it a reality. It is precisely the way I chose to be that invites such amazing experiences. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-26:/posts/2017-12-26-long-overdue.html</guid></item><item><title>Downtown Orlando with a friend</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-12-21-orlando-downtown.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We got food and walked around :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-21:/posts/2017-12-21-orlando-downtown.html</guid></item><item><title>Two days of comfort and I'm already unhappy</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-12-19-box-comfort.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am lucky enough to be spending the week at a resort. My mother shared her timeshare with me. It has a wonderful jacuzzi, shower, kitchen, bed, balcony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the day in bed playing a video game, watching tv, and eating only enough. So yeah, I'm bringing this upon myself. But still, I'd much rather be living with nothing, moving around, and constantly meeting people for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would I feel if it were my own apartment? What if I get roomates at some point? Woah. I have not had roommates since 2009. Well, I'm looking forward to being social tonight and tomorrow. And hopefully I get cracking on some projects. Like practicing my christmas music to earn some cash at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess now that I've found people I want to be friends with, I am feeling lonely. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-19:/posts/2017-12-19-box-comfort.html</guid></item><item><title>MindBlown 2</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-12-10-concert.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today was the concert. I can hardly believe it was real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After attracting an older couple in a park nearby the venue with my violin and performing for them, I found a great parking spot. Cyrus rolled up and we chatted then walked up to the theater. People gathered, set up and eventually we practiced. It was sketchy at first. But the last time was pretty okay. After chatting up everyone I left and got food. Then the fun begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A boy I have been spending time with arrived and we walked inside. We sat for a bit unitl I had to disappear. In the back room I was a flutter and felt like I was causing a scene with everyone. This began my anxieties for the night. As the first act began, Odd?Rod, Cyrus took us to a back room and he gave me some money!!! I had no idea it was coming. I didn't expect it. I didn't even want it. He then provided some directions and inspiration. I sat there with the rest of the crew flittering, twitterpated, tapping with joy and gratitude. I almost said something to everyone but decided that would have been too much. When the band went on to play, I hid in a back room to practice and kill my jitters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance was a wild rush. I simply went into it and tried my best. The lights up, the audience hidden, my singer standing directly in front of me, the piano to my right. I focused as best I could and tried to keep my nerves intact. We played through it without major incident. I couldn't hear anything. No monitor, no vocals, barely the piano. I wore a dress borrowed, gold earring, black tights, my hair pinned to the side to keep it out of my playing. I thought I only played a B- but I got enough compliments to suggest otherwise. Unfotunately, the second half of the song relied on a techno track and it failed to play for some reason. Totally disappointing. But, that was how it went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After, I was a fluster, edgey, and handling it poorly. I got myself out to the boy who came with and began streaming tears after we sat down to watch the last act. I was filled with joy, self-loathing, gratitude, disappointment. How could this really have happened? In one week I lived an entire season's of events. If this boy had not been with me, I would have disappeared, but his presence, support, understanding, helped me gather up and go out for drinks after. I am so glad I did. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-10:/posts/2017-12-10-concert.html</guid></item></channel></rss>