<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - chronograph</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>I went to my first concert in a long time to see "This Will Destroy You"</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-11-this-will-destroy-you.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was super jazzed. They were doing a tenth anniversary tour of their self title album. My favorite album of theirs alongside their first, Young Mountain. If they were playing their new stuff I would not have gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I went because this album has played an important roll in my life. I started listening to it in Burlington Vermont during my one year at school. I was so deeply depressed and ashamed, I used to walk around listening to their music and some others all around the Winooski River. I would get high off my ass and sink into the music until nothing existed except my horrible thought habits swirling around the atmosphere of the music. I love those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I felt rather disconnected from any emotional experience during the show. I was happy. I was enjoying watching strangers nod and sway instead of moshing and dancing. I was present, but I felt rather flat. This feeling caught me off guard. I began thinking that being "real" is worse, because I am not experiencing the same level of emotional realness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After talking with some friends (yes I back date), I have begun to hope that this is simply a consequences of my recent realness. That I still need more time to come into and fill this life. I should have more patience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless. I was super super happy to get to go. I learned a lot. I enjoyed being slammed by these melodies I fell in love with almost a decade ago, and I drank a lot of water 😵&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-11:/posts/2018-05-11-this-will-destroy-you.html</guid></item><item><title>Sometimes I think my chronic pain is a lie, today I felt better about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I spent a couple hours picking up trash at my favorite outlook. I tried my very best to bend properly, go slow, and take care of my body. It was exhausting and I needed a nap after. Turns out, I also worked out a lot of muscles grown weak during the winter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I felt the burn. I felt all the glute, quad, hamstring muscles sore. It was a lot of muscles at once and impacted my walking pace and stair climbing noticeably. This is normal and expected. Muscles get sore when you work them out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went for a short walk and sat on the ground with a friend. In an effort to be impressive and flirt, I sat in position which were painful to me. I had taken a painkiller in preparation for this experience kinda knowing it would be ruff so in the moment, I felt okay enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours later and most of today I felt the consequences. I had a very real example of the difference between sore muscle pain, joint pain, and chronic pain. I am very happy to have had this moment. It makes me feel more validated in my experience of pain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like muscle soreness. It is a good feeling. Joint pain and chronic pain is not a good feeling. As I have said for years now "a body in motion hurts less". And today is seems more relevant than ever. Thanks body.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-25:/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</guid></item><item><title>A day in the sun cleaning up</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-22-cleaning-up.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Warmth is finally coming. We had a warm day today, so I took Vanessa up to my old outlook where I did some cleaning up while basking in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cleaned Vanessa's wheels, they were so gross. I also finally finished replacing the weather stripping on the plastic cover for the air filter. It is a damn good seal now. haha. Vanessa smells way better now, and I think I can stop worrying about it. I concluded the reason she smelt bad was because I failed to put that cover on properly once and bam, smelly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spent some time picking up trash in the area. This spot has a strong place in my heart. Each chapter of my life I have memories here and I like to keep it clean. I still have a lot more to pick up, the last time I did it was a while ago. But, it made me feel good when I saw a family, and later some kids, try to sit around the areas I had already cleaned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to have something to do with no pressure and also makes me feel like I did something good. I filled 5.5 grocery bags of trash, not including the shoe and car floor mat. I bet there is another 3-5 bags left.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-22:/posts/2018-04-22-cleaning-up.html</guid></item><item><title>What I've been up to</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-08-what-im-up-to.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I figured I would actually share what's going on, because I haven't been writing about this stuff enough. Partly because I am depressed. Partly because I don't know how I feel yet about sharing this stuff on the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been helping my mother pack up the family house. We're selling. May parents are getting divorced and everything is finally ending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have wedged myself into my support group again and trying to have an impact. Hopefully a positive one. We'll see about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two things are taking a considerable amount of my energy. And they're also things I don't really want to talk about much on the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couple in the fact that it's still way too cold for me to be comfortable and I don't do anything worth writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot wait until it gets warmer here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-08:/posts/2018-04-08-what-im-up-to.html</guid></item><item><title>Voices want to sound like robots again and so what</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-04-robot-voices.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Voices, whether analog or digitial are again sound like they have a robot filter on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/oTeq-3Nucc4?start=1037'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happens less in analog, but I'm starting to think it is related to how much pain I am experiencing. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-04:/posts/2018-04-04-robot-voices.html</guid></item><item><title>Living for myself</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-31-for-myself.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have felt for quite some time now that I cannot live for myself. Every time I try to figure it out I end up feeling my only choice would be to end my life. Now, almost a year into reality I am questioning again if it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to believe all my actions have some other benefactor in mind which is unlikely. I tend to claim I have no friends and suck at making them. Aside from a few people, cisgender people are a strong source of envy for me so I don't end up befriending them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who reads this drivel is likely shaking their head at my bullshit. Which is fine. I don't really care. But it does make me think about what my life is actually like. To be someone in my shoes, with my bullshit, it's a lovely show isnt't it? All I ever wanted in life was to be a barefoot prancing little wood fairy but I cannot be any of those things. So this is what I settle for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I am to survive all this I'm quite sure I will need to find a reason to live for myself. Will that day ever come?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-31:/posts/2018-03-31-for-myself.html</guid></item><item><title>Is this really the life I'm stuck with?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what I'm doing. I have this drive to be something of a martyr, a public figure or at least a devout public servant. All of me screams in anger about my situation while dragging my stupid life towards this goal of living with a purpose designed to serve others and not myself. I am fine with this aim. I've never expected much for my life, at least not in a real way. I had small hopes before but nothing like this. This I am because a future in this body is bleak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pain limits me from having the life I always dreamed of. I'm capable of that dream, but not with this pain. I can't simply power through the pain. My prognosis is slow decay. And while I am trying hard to be as healthy as possible I cannot change everything at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write laying in bed wondering if I will conquer this. If I will find myself in another two, five years laughing with my hands on my hips pain free and able to live the life I always dreamed of. Maybe I'm just getting one step closer to acceptance of the life I am trapped in. Pushing myself beyond limits for everyone but myself. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-15:/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</guid></item><item><title>I just had a glimpse of how I might gain weight</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-11-glimpes-of-fat.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I adore empathy. In turn this really means I love imagination. It is through using my imagination and wholly attempting to live it, I am able to create such empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after gourging on food, I went out for another snack. As I was eating I realized my stomach was still mostly full, but I was cramming it in anyway. But I wanted to eat. I was compelled to eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it flashed before my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hate being skinny, so I finally pushed to be a person who eats a lot so I can gain weight. I start the habit of eating more and more. Eventually I can't stop. I have been so skinny my whole life I don't really care I now have a little too much weight. And suddenly, I'm well overweight but still sitting down and eating another food because in my mind, I am so satisfied I am not underweight. I will never be underweight again. Ever. So I eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if this means I am going to start the path of finally gaining weight. Not exactly in the extreme way this day dream played out, but still. Or is this simply a bout of fleeting imagination which will result in nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to see it as a sign, but I'd rather make it sign.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-11:/posts/2018-03-11-glimpes-of-fat.html</guid></item><item><title>Shedding responsibility and happy about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a few years I was a pseudo leader at a support group in my area for transgender people. I was the legally responsible emissary for a couple of years. I have since left and failed to hand over responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a recent meeting and spoke with someone who I am excited about handing the reigns over to. Well, they already had them a bit. So I'm more like empowering them and validating their value by giving them responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sad, for in a way, I never truly got to exercise the value I carried for the support group before I left. In my unreality, I was always too anxious and shameful to engage in the way I could have. So I watched and prodded from a place in the back, rather than right in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired to do something of value before I leave again, I am taking on a couple of responsibilities to get the group admin stuff moving again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to let go. I am happy there are others with similar views as me. I am happy knowing I made an impact on a group I feel is absolutely vital to my community.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</guid></item><item><title>Another sick day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No vomiting this time thankfully. However right before I set out to a friend's place I felt so dizzy and nauseous I had to lie down. I did the off and on sleeping thing for about four hours. And after some food and gobs of water I began to feel better. It's 2am right now. I have to do things tomorrow. Ugh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-25:/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</guid></item><item><title>Burning memorabilia while purging</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I burnt thousands of pages. A lot with sensitive medical data I would not like floating around. Others simply records of experiences I've lived in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This being the second time burning like this, I felt more prepared for the shift in perspective afterwards. Symbolically I destroy ties to the past I used to care deeply for. I will always be an archivist. However, my urges to do so with physical things is all but extinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me to thinking about what forms of physical archival fits my new perspective on life. Here's my list so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jewelry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tattoos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Film Pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trinkets small enough to enclose a fist over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical items (tools, storage, lifestyle enhancements)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the trend is keeping clutter out of life. Using small and or practical items to impart the symbol into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am feeling it is of little use to recall all of life with great detail. Distilling key memories and placing their importance into a small or  practical item is all that is needed to remember what made you the way you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you hold tightly to the memories, the less willing you may be to change. Too much focus on the past and you will stay there. Too much focus on the future and you may never get there. The present is the most practical place to be in any given moment. Although, never leaving the present makes it very difficult to grow and change with intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love change ^_^&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-21:/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</guid></item><item><title>Stuck in MA for a bit.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-20-stuck.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't know what I will write during the rest of the month, but I figured I'd at least outline what the plan is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am stuck in MA for a while. Since my parents are planning to sell the house this summer, I am spending a large chunk of my time getting rid of my crap. Ripping DVDs, throwing out stuff, donating, giving away, putting up for sale, cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also putting a lot of energy into staying away from depression and depletion. It is so easy in the winter to hibernate and do nothing because of how the cold effects my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I plan to be social with people here. I've got some people I would like to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully everything goes okay, I get back on the road before February, and things keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-20:/posts/2018-01-20-stuck.html</guid></item><item><title>Sick day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-11-sick.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A remarkable thing happened. I woke up at my mother's house the first day and felt nauseous. I threw up a couple times and spent all day in bed. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why? If this type of sick occurred in Vanessa it would have been horrifying. I am not prepared for that. I should be prepared for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I get myself back together for this week. I've got a ton of shit going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ugh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-11:/posts/2018-01-11-sick.html</guid></item></channel></rss>