<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - chronograph</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>End of my first visit</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-06-first-visit.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I feel pretty good about my first visit. I very quickly purged technology from my mind and focused on the person I was with. We went out for a short hike at the Deleware Water Gap, ate ice cream and watched a tv show, and spent time at the library doing tech things. It was very nice and much more relaxing than the last time I saw my cousin. I am very glad she is doing well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My body is not happy though. The walk and and her uncomfortable furniture left my back aching and I am feeling is after the drive into PA. I definitely feel I am stressing and pushing to be social and see everyone. And what I really want to do is lie down for a week and then finish some stuff in Vanessa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is my one of my mother's brothers. I am looking forward to seeing him and his family because I haven't spent much time with them, and, when we had a short visit this summer it went really well. I really like being around family who are nice and supportive. It has a huge impact on unifying my past with the present. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-06:/posts/2018-10-06-first-visit.html</guid></item><item><title>Lunch with an old friend</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-24-lunch-with-old-friend.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am so lucky. To have so many people in my life still willing to catch up with me even after I've transitioned. This friend goes back to 2010 when I was in my darkest. Working with the greatest team of people I ever worked with while I couldn't truly enjoy them the way I could now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I want to write about from this interaction is about my party. I had mentioned I had a going away gathering with people from my support group. I described the setting. Frisbee, bubbles, chalk and sunset. His response was "That's a Luna party of I ever heard of one". Well, he said something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had such a rush of nostalgia, klexos. Ramming old memories into today. See, back then I used to do a lot more bubbles. All kidns of bubbles. Colored, smelly, big, small, huge. I made my own solutions and generally enjoyed bubbles a lot. I also played around with other toys for parties like lasers with patterns, sand that glowed (discontinued 😭), frisbees. Having these activities was a way for me to displace my anxieties in groups of people so I could focus on an activity and not the people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I am using these same devices to engage people, bring something more to the experience than the same old, and hopefully remind people how to have childlike fun in this chaotic world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so wild to me how different I am, yet the same. Realizing how much this old friend of mine knows about me isn't moot because of my transition. I am unashamed to be who I am now. All the same things I Wished to bring people back then I still want to bring to people now. It is okay that this is who I am. Not everyone will want need or like I am this way and that is fine. We need all kinds in this world. I can be this goofy hopeful idealistic inspirational nutball. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really want to point out just how important people like this old friend are for someone like me. Someone who was so repressed, who hid their true self so greatly, who needs to change more about their life than we think others will be comfortable with. To have people from before willing to be around after. People who can help me marry that past life with today's life. Resolution with myself. IT is huge. And it means a lot. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-24:/posts/2018-09-24-lunch-with-old-friend.html</guid></item><item><title>Talking with a stranger led to a disappointing sexual dismissal</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-23-convo-gone-sexual.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Walking back to Vanessa from the liquor store, someone with a deep voice said something from behind. I look back. A black man with facial hair, thin, six feet tall with a hoody and a bag from the same liquor store was a few feet away from me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You look sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh nah, I'm just tired I guess. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He replies by stating how surprised he was that a white would talk to a black. As I learn more and more about Boston it makes sense that might be his first reaction to my willingness to respond. He seemed friendly, and was being kind. We walked together until I got to Vanessa. I told him this is me, and he asked if we could share a drink for a minute. Sure why not. I got time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vanessa I get my wine bottle open and we sit on her slider door step and chat while we sip alcohol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This went fine, until it didn't. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He began getting sexual with me. I kept turning him down, albeit more gently than I'd have liked. He share some stories with me of his past life which increased my reservations. He went so far as to surprise kiss my neck. After I pushed him away he assumed I liked it because I was squirming. I made it clear it was because I was uncomfortable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I began getting ready to leave. HE began getting sad. Immediately his flip was switched and he felt dejected and depressed. Yikes. It was hard. I have too much empathy for people, and it was difficult for me to watch all those emotions in him tumble. But I also had to protect myself. Skeevy interaction for sure but a good lesson learned I think. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-23:/posts/2018-09-23-convo-gone-sexual.html</guid></item><item><title>Sunset with a new friend brings me excitement for my next chapter</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-23-sunset-with-friend.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I love people. Today I got to spend time with a new person who has captured my attention for a while. I really enjoy now, how I am able to differentiate between people who I am interested in, versus those who I tolerate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got together to walk an arboretum and see where it goes. We eventually peaked a hill with a fun view of the city. In our luddite similarity we opted to wander with our intuition looking for food before we come back to the hill for the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we left, I was describing how much I love sunsets, and how difficult it can be to predict if a sunset will be awesome or not. In brining it up I attempted to predict this one. The dense layer of high clouds were enticing. Since the sun was currently blocked, and this hill did not give us a solid view of the horizon I was timid about my epic prediction because I could not tell how the clouds might block the rays at the horizon. Regardless I predicted and explained how it would be epic as the sun set. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the sun moves towards the horizon, the rays will cast out towards the farthest of these high clouds and will create a huge display of color. As the sun gets lower the color will shift towards the horizon and get more brilliant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found food, walked back and the brilliance began. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of feet before we reached the peak of the hill, in almost instantaneous fashion, the sky got colored. All around us the sky was different. We bee lined for the peak. I sat in utter joy as the show we got was near exactly as I predicted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The range of colors was wide at first then slowly compacted to give us vibrant pinks and hints of purple. I was floored. Enjoying myself with a new friend, feeling comfortable, unashamed. Reticent to leave people I like. Eager to continue finding my purpose in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-23:/posts/2018-09-23-sunset-with-friend.html</guid></item><item><title>I sold my old car!</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-09-sold-mazda.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, I sold the car I should have sold 2 years ago after getting Vanessa. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made out okay, not as good as I would have if I sold it right away though. Sadly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did market research. I looked at Kelly Blue Book, got the car looked at for problems, and looked at the current market for my kind of car in my kind of range. This gave me an idea of what might sell the car fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used craigslist. I first listed it higher than I thought would sell. Every week I lowered the price if I did not get a buyer. I also adjusted the language after the 2nd lowering. I added MUST GO to the title of the post. The title had loads of details, the body had plenty of information and was totally honest, and I have very nice pictures of a very clean car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I hit the sweet spot number for a listing price I got many interested buyers. In three days I have five people look at it. I received my first offer after 4 days. I worked it out with that buyer and it was gone on the 7th day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt good about being able to haggle about the number, but given my impending desperation and my fears, I accepted a number $200 lower than I had hoped. We did do a back and forth on number. I think in the end I got a very good number considering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not disappointed at all in how any of it went down. My shame was at bay. When I goofed I fixed it. When I realized I had to prep the car better I did it. If I wasn't so desparate I might have done more, haggled more, or waited for a better offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a rearview mirror air freshner in that car sicne as long as I owned it. A painted bottled with a wooden top and string to hold it in place. It was never a good air freshner. After taking it down I realized, the reason it sucked was because I never actually opened it! I was supposed to twist off the wooden top and remove a plastic plug. HAHA. Turns out to be a very refreshing smell and I am excited to add it to Vanessa. Should help with the exhaust smells. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-09:/posts/2018-09-09-sold-mazda.html</guid></item><item><title>The end of summer recap</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-07-end-of-summer.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been in Massachusetts for a very long time. In this post I think I'll recap as much as I can before I get tired of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally came back in January to deal with some medical stuff. That switfly turned into a total overall of my year, deciding I would stay to help my mother sell the family home. This shift inspired me to commit more energy to my local support group. I spent the spring focusing on the group, and trying to stay happy. Once warmer weather began pouring in I committed energy to the house. A few months of effort and the hosue was sold. Now three weeks after the house is sold, I have prepped a bunch for my departure. Only a few final thigns to button up. I should be out of here before September 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="support-group-efforts"&gt;Support Group Efforts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I became more involved in a local support group than I expected. I took on some responsibility which included holding a key to the building we use. When I left in Vanessa I did not properly pass on the responsiblity to someone else. I also started a website and new process for accepting new members. In my absense, the website went down for a time, and no one responded to incoming members for a period of almost 9 months. I was determined to setup a process to ensure this never happened again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found someone new to take on the legal responsibility and key bearing. With this new person we began devising a system to support the most important functions of the group. We decided to use Values-Based Consensus. This system seems alright and theoretically removes power from individuals greatly. We began implementing this system and bi-monthly consensus meetings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so shocked by everything that has happened. There has been conflict. There has been progress. There has been people coming in and out, producing different levels of effort and interest. What has impacted me the most, is the amount of vulnerability it takes to be a leader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to be less visible than the other primary person because I always knew my tenure would be brief. I had thought if I was less visible the group would lose less momentum and motivation when I depart. I hope this is the case. Because of this, the extent of my involvment has not been clear to everyone which also created some issues. I knew taking this one would push me with regards to my leadership skills, interpersonal skills, openness, and vulnerability. I was certainly tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What brings me some pride has been my ability to bring people together. In the few conflicts which occured, I feel I was able to help find resolution without contempt. Everyone involved has always had an interest to do good, but our own struggles and fears get in the way sometimes. I hope I never forget the impact these events have had on me, and I continue to expand on what I learned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="selling-the-house"&gt;Selling the house&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told my mom as my energy began to come back that someone needs to take ownership of selling the house. It has to be their responsibility. Well, I finally got inspired once my hormones began to settle on a proper level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I planned and executed a yard sale. We made about $1000. It was a ton of work, but got rid of a bunch of stuff. After that I scheduled a dumpster to arrive. We got rid of a lot of hazardous waste, donated a ton of stuff and cleared out the basement all within two weeks time because of my planning. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what effort that was! The day after we emptied the basement someone came in with an offer. From there it was a race to the finish. We had just over a month to finish everything. Two more dumptsers were ordered, weeks of effort cleaning, organizing, and moving took place. The very last day there was a last burst of effort to clean the insides and we made it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process taught me a lot about discipline. My owernship in the process came barely a week after my first year of being real. And in that realness there was more engagement in life than I have ever had before. I was motivated to get things done because others depended on me, because if we didn't finish I could never leave, and if I never left I would never see the people and experiences I was looking for. I had to engage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this I pushed my body more than I had in a very long time. I spent many days in a ton of pain, almost crying while working because the pain was so bad. But I had to continue. There was great satisfaction when we hit milestones. And disappointments when I had to stop because of my body. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also keen on this because if we no longer have a family home, I no longer have a "home base" I can always return to. I have used this house the last two years as a rest from vanlife. And to cope with winters when I ran out of money or something. Now this is gone. While I have plenty of people willing to support me in many ways, this conceptual change feels very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="getting-ready-to-leave"&gt;Getting ready to leave&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am about two or three weeks from leaving. I have had a lot to do. Still a lot to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a phew really big tasks ahead. Sell my old Mazda, decide what to do with Vanessa, deal with all my stuff, and finish up work at the support group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today I accepted an offer on my car and I have two parties interested in the fridge. I can't wait until they are gone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanessa was a tougher choice. I had thought it was time to get a different van. But then the reapirs I had to do were safety related. Once I did them Vanessa felt like a whole new van. So I have decided to keep her until at least March. Depending on how well she does during the winter will decide whether I keep her or not. But before I can leave I am also replacing the windshield, getting the rust repaired and hopefully adjusting the door so the contacts work again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the support group. Things seem stable enough. I have planned my outro with a gathering. More people are coming than I expected. Honestly my engagement in the group and how others seem to view me is still hard to handle. I intellectually undertsand why I am appreciated at the group and by other trans people. That does not overpower my own internal bullshit however. It is easy for me to focus on my failings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="on-being-real"&gt;On being real&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being real is huge. Everything is so different. Everything keeps getting different. I continue to get more playful. I enjoy sharing myself with others, being myself, as odd as that sounds. I feel very little shame now. Shocking really. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have reinvigorated my interest in my music visualizer again. I got winamp installed on my laptop with Wine, and currently watching it while I type. There is something deeply satisfying about having it in my life again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also feel a much deeper peace with my femininity. Or at least, the amount of femininity I need to express at the moment. I am eager to find a wardrobe I am happier wearing, and I see that getting filled with more fun and playful clothing than I have now. I am not surprised I was wrapped with so much shame growing up because, if there is such a thing, my natural femininity is on the far side of things it seems. But again, it may just be for a time I need to spill it all over the world before I settle somewhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am eager to finish getting ready. Get back on the vanlife road. To stop beating up my body on a regular basis. To find out more about who I am. And eager as all fuck for my tits to grow back 😖&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-07:/posts/2018-09-07-end-of-summer.html</guid></item><item><title>I am free!</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-08-22-freedom.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The house sale is over. I am done. Hasn't fully set in, but I am very happy to get back to my own life.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-08-22:/posts/2018-08-22-freedom.html</guid></item><item><title>We have a buyer for the house!</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-15-buyer.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday last week someone put in an offer. After a quick we settled on a price. A week later we agreed on a terms sheet!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-house-is-sold"&gt;The house is sold!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are confident the new owners will have no issues with the banks, and we will do our part to vacate properly. The chances of the deal falling through are very minimal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="its-over"&gt;It's over.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packing, prepping, and emptying my childhood home is the reason for my snail pace in posting. So much energy focused on it. Combine that with my depression from winter and hormone imbalance and I didn't feel very good about life for a while. But with the summer, hormones, and success with the house I can't wait to finish up the summer. So much to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I can reflect over the first half of this year and build some solid reminders or mantras to help me stay more stable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-15:/posts/2018-07-15-buyer.html</guid></item><item><title>Help people, not ideas</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am offering some time and money to someone in my life who is heavily involved in a church. As I considered if they had enough help I played a quick story in my head where I volunteered my time on a regular basis. Yes, I am not religious and have no interest in becoming so. But I still would want to help this person out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then concluded that I like to help people and not ideas. This is a nifty little nugget I think I should hold on to. It does a good job describing me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another conversation I had described a philosopher as someone who presents ideas but does not hold to them. Someone who may put together new ideas but not be attached to them. My friend rejected this notion. I don't care who is right, only that I think I was describing me and my situation. I enjoy knowing many perspectives on the same issue so I can help people, not promote a specific idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say I don't have my own feelings on issues, but that my general approach is to engage with people on their terms not against my own beliefs or ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I can be friends with the person who voted for trump, the anarchist, the socialist democrat, the non politically correct. It is why I have always seen my value in this life as a stepping stone for others. But don't follow me. I am not trying to make a value judgement on my way of life. I wouldn't recommend other people live like me or think like me. I am not very good at taking care of myself. I put everyone else before me. I struggle to understand who I am, what I want, what I like, and where I want to go. I expect and practically seek solitude. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think this phrase, I help people, not ideas, is a solid phrase to help others understand why I am the way I am. And apparently I am writing about it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-07:/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</guid></item><item><title>My experience on the victim mentality</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-15-victim-mentality.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having come from the undercarriage of social life, the depressed anxious shamed part of society I was surrounded by the victim mentality for a large part of my conscious life. I held it, the victim mentality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people are born into situations either physical or social that lends them to learn towards victim rather than say, survivor. Not everyone is so lucky. I had to build my way out of the victim mentality and it is no small feat. Almost two decades of anxiety and depression were battled, a lifetime of self shaming and fear to overcome, an amalgam of bad habits wrestled with. I spent at least fifteen years in chaos. It took me six years to hit the tipping point. &lt;strong&gt;Six years of concerted, committed, careful, effort&lt;/strong&gt; to finally overcome the victim mentality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I finally committed to recovery, I wanted help, I sometimes looked for help, but I never knew what to do with it. &lt;strong&gt;I was too ashamed, stuck in too dark a place.&lt;/strong&gt; I wasn't quite ready. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say the help you receive before you are ready has little to no impact. I disagree. While a single instance may not amount to much, a long history of people being supportive makes the process a little smoother, a little easier once you finally take hold. If my memories were filled with people who were unsupportive it might have taken an even deeper amount of effort to figure it all out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="taking-control"&gt;Taking control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know lots of people talk about how to inspire that moment where you finally take hold of your own life and never let go again. I write for myself, and mostly so I never forget the process. I really believe this archival habit of mine is a strong element to my continued success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I have always been an archivist. I journaled here and there, but never deleted, never trashed. My digital journal alone began it's journey in later 2011. I finally gained steam around early 2013 and since then I have written on 50% of all days since 2013. That's a lot of writing. A lot of self reflection. And I am proud of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a quote from the very first entry on my digital journal from October 29th 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i think i did ok today despite having played games for multiple hours. i wonder how i will curb that mental trap. in fact, right now i want to play it again. maybe get high and slam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that might be ok. i need to put in place a schedule/regiment of when/how long i can play video games. hopefully it gets less and less as time goes on and then i play no games at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proud to say that I have all but given up video games. They rarely consume my time and when they do, I am intentional about it. So maybe it took seven years but whatevs. I made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="from-a-poem-i-wrote-a-number-of-years-ago"&gt;From a poem I wrote a number of years ago:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="internal" href="https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2016-05-02-lifeismoreinterestingthanthat.html"&gt;Life is more interesting than that&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impossible it seems to be understood wholly,&lt;br&gt;
To feel less alien and more human.&lt;br&gt;
Each of us orbiting in and out of relationships&lt;br&gt;
causing cataclysmic shifts in the arc of our lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you bump into someone here you are affecting not just the other person, but yourself as well. You choosing to interact does something to you however small. Every moment is sacred. Every interaction a cosmic mess and that's okay. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-15:/posts/2018-05-15-victim-mentality.html</guid></item><item><title>I went to my first concert in a long time to see "This Will Destroy You"</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-11-this-will-destroy-you.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was super jazzed. They were doing a tenth anniversary tour of their self title album. My favorite album of theirs alongside their first, Young Mountain. If they were playing their new stuff I would not have gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I went because this album has played an important roll in my life. I started listening to it in Burlington Vermont during my one year at school. I was so deeply depressed and ashamed, I used to walk around listening to their music and some others all around the Winooski River. I would get high off my ass and sink into the music until nothing existed except my horrible thought habits swirling around the atmosphere of the music. I love those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I felt rather disconnected from any emotional experience during the show. I was happy. I was enjoying watching strangers nod and sway instead of moshing and dancing. I was present, but I felt rather flat. This feeling caught me off guard. I began thinking that being "real" is worse, because I am not experiencing the same level of emotional realness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After talking with some friends (yes I back date), I have begun to hope that this is simply a consequences of my recent realness. That I still need more time to come into and fill this life. I should have more patience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless. I was super super happy to get to go. I learned a lot. I enjoyed being slammed by these melodies I fell in love with almost a decade ago, and I drank a lot of water 😵&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-11:/posts/2018-05-11-this-will-destroy-you.html</guid></item><item><title>Sometimes I think my chronic pain is a lie, today I felt better about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I spent a couple hours picking up trash at my favorite outlook. I tried my very best to bend properly, go slow, and take care of my body. It was exhausting and I needed a nap after. Turns out, I also worked out a lot of muscles grown weak during the winter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I felt the burn. I felt all the glute, quad, hamstring muscles sore. It was a lot of muscles at once and impacted my walking pace and stair climbing noticeably. This is normal and expected. Muscles get sore when you work them out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went for a short walk and sat on the ground with a friend. In an effort to be impressive and flirt, I sat in position which were painful to me. I had taken a painkiller in preparation for this experience kinda knowing it would be ruff so in the moment, I felt okay enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours later and most of today I felt the consequences. I had a very real example of the difference between sore muscle pain, joint pain, and chronic pain. I am very happy to have had this moment. It makes me feel more validated in my experience of pain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like muscle soreness. It is a good feeling. Joint pain and chronic pain is not a good feeling. As I have said for years now "a body in motion hurts less". And today is seems more relevant than ever. Thanks body.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-04-25:/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</guid></item><item><title>A day in the sun cleaning up</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-04-22-cleaning-up.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Warmth is finally coming. We had a warm day today, so I took Vanessa up to my old outlook where I did some cleaning up while basking in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cleaned Vanessa's wheels, they were so gross. I also finally finished replacing the weather stripping on the plastic cover for the air filter. It is a damn good seal now. haha. Vanessa smells way better now, and I think I can stop worrying about it. I concluded the reason she smelt bad was because I failed to put that cover on properly once and bam, smelly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spent some time picking up trash in the area. This spot has a strong place in my heart. Each chapter of my life I have memories here and I like to keep it clean. I still have a lot more to pick up, the last time I did it was a while ago. But, it made me feel good when I saw a family, and later some kids, try to sit around the areas I had already cleaned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to have something to do with no pressure and also makes me feel like I did something good. I filled 5.5 grocery bags of trash, not including the shoe and car floor mat. I bet there is another 3-5 bags left.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-04-22:/posts/2018-04-22-cleaning-up.html</guid></item></channel></rss>