<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - recovery</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>I need to get away from the internet, what can I do?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-02-what-to-do.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hate how you spend all your time in front of computer screens or on the internet wasting time? Here is a list of ideas you can peruse for inspiration. Some of these are quite unconventional. Read carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pluck all your body hair with tweezers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice moving one eye but not the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look up anatomy drawings and try to twitch all your muscles independently (Netter's atlas baby)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice character voices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn how to throat sing (proper name?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clean every little nook and cranny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take something apart and put it back together again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download Zim wiki and start your own personal wiki of your life or simply write in a journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go down memory lane and look at your old photos from 1992&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;philosophize about time, perception of time, habits around time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice and strengthen the muscles that wiggle your ears (start with extreme eye brow lifts to identify the muscles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read books! - use the library, find an e-reader with e-ink display, borrow from friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work on a puzzle if you have the flat surface area for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design tattoos for yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look through etsy for any futures hobbies you might want to get into&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;video chat with people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;re lace your shoes with a different pattern for funzies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice Taoist masturbation/sex stuff to connect with your body in new ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn to whistle in three different ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turn off all lights, get as dark as possible, and listen. Try to identify every sound you can hear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block out as much sound and light as you can, and imagine scary stuff happening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch a visualizer while you listen to music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice an instrument if you have one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write letters to people, hell even to strangers. Just put the letter in some random mail box. Write nice things, inspirational things, love things. Not to scare people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch documentaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explore things you don't understand, like maybe sexuality and gender (my faves)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch free online college lectures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you watch entertainment media, have paper ready to critique it while you watch instead of simply droning out in it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice breathing intentionally, like, breathe real slow for two minutes, or breathe slow then fast or something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn origami&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buy a van, convert it to an RV, quit your job and become a nomad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite pass time. Conceptualize context. Understand context. Play with context. Dive your mind into the tiniest concept of molecules and focus on water, fluidity, or really explore the fabrics nearby. Zoom out to the universe level and conceptualize the galaxies, the vastness of space time, the orbital patterns if our solar system. Think of how the moon waxes and wanes, how it effects our planet, the way it illuminates the night. Think about how what you choose to think informs your understanding of reality, what your life feels like, and how you perceive others and their actions. Context is queen.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-02:/posts/2018-02-02-what-to-do.html</guid></item><item><title>Are you a failure?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-01-stand-up.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Or do you simply believe the thought that you are a failure? If you HAVE failed in the past, can you not find ways to get better so you don't fail the same way again in the future? Failure is common but failure only comes knowing you didn't try your best. If you try your best it should not be considered failing. You put your all into that. Those failures should really be lessons learned. An opportunity to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you have been given the challenge of DPDR in your lifetime. Others get cancer, or abuse, or spinal injuries, or schizophrenia, or others. You have been given the chance to overcome this in your life. It is not easy. But everyone has their thing. And if you can stand up, brush yourself off, look around, put those fists up and keep fighting, I know you will find a way to conquer these demons. To find out why you think you hate yourself and banish those thoughts. To find all the reasons you love yourself, how you are good, and how you want to get better. To learn to deserve the love you receive and feel worthy of the good things you are lucky to experience. If this is something you want, you'll have to find it yourself. You'll have to fight, be patient, and learn a lot of new things. But this is your life. Your only life. Will you take your own hand?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-01:/posts/2018-02-01-stand-up.html</guid></item><item><title>Life is not hard, dealing with your self is</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-15-live-is-not-hard.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Life itself is not hard. Every living creature figures out how to do it. Our body and minds are designed to keep living as long as we can. Some species have apparently survived for tens of thousands of years, and some over a million right? Life, living, not dying, is easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-against-the-world.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealing with your &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt; is hard. Why is it that two people can experience the same traumatic event but respond so differently? How can some bounce back while others stay crushed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/survived-every-day.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is to say, that life is not to blame. No outside force is going to save you, fix you. YOU ARE GOING TO FIX YOU. Because you can, and you will, because you fucking love yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/afraid-to-fail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is your life, this dark, scary, sad, horrifying, anxious, depressed, dissociated, mess of a life, why not do and try everything to find as much joy, happiness, playfulness, fun, love, light as possible? This is your only life! Make it what you will, not the result of giving in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-think-you-have-time.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All it takes is a spark, an unending flame that boils inside you to never give up, never give in, and never forget to keep pushing, to keep trying, and to explore the world and all of reality so you can find what feeds you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that spark ignites, you'll know. Once you find a way to keep that flame burning no matter how sad, depressed, anxious, or fucked up you feel, you'll know. Once you have that day, where you are down in the pits but remember, oh right, I've got this flame, this urge, this desire, this need to recovery, and take another step out, you'll know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-get-better.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-15:/posts/2018-01-15-live-is-not-hard.html</guid></item><item><title>Questions from after a suicide attempt</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-13-asking-questions.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was written in the midst of a partial hospitalization after a serious bout with suicidality. Never stop asking yourself questions. These questions helped bring me to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="life-is-not-hard-dealing-with-yourself-is"&gt;Life is not hard, dealing with yourself is.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billions of people have lived and died all with their own experience of life, reality. Is it that life is hard intrinsically or that your experience, your perspective, is what creates the challenges you face? Is it intrinsically difficult to alter the way you respond to the minutia of what life brings? Can we assess our attachment to certain behaviors, thoughts, reactions, and make choices regarding their relevancy? Have you ever watched someone succeed at something you fail at and wonder how they are so lucky? What causes us to respond to events the way we do? and how do you close the gap to respond desirably?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that some others do not struggle the way I do? Are my problems permanent? Which are conquerable? Which can only be managed? Can you approach your problems from many angles to determine which type your problems truly are? And how is it that others simply move forward after traumas, hardship, and problems? What do they know that you don't? Is it as simple as saying I will choose this response? What even makes an even something you will struggle with? How long does it take for you to generally get beyond the struggle and moved forward? Can you find the tools to help minimize the amount of time you struggle so you can move forward? Is this related to change and how we cope with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between your self and other selves? Is it possible to see how another responds to certain stimuli and calculate the distance between your response and theirs? How often is the distance merely a  formation of habit? Are habits all that hard to change? How often is the distance a gap in knowledge or awareness of a concept? Is it really hard to open yourself to learning something new?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dissociation-and-its-role-in-my-life"&gt;Dissociation and its role in my life.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of my memories from childhood contain dissociation. I always felt shuffled along by the whims of my kith, doing and being what they wanted me to be. This sense of always watching and always thinking led me to the conclusions I have formed and the perspective I have acquired. I have wisdom because I have never truly lived my life. My sharing is never just for my expression. I live in the windows of others and calculate language to account for them, not me. I try not to dissociate. My transition is about trying to take hold of my association. I only ever feel associated alone. I don't feel like I can ever get rid of my dissociation. What I am, what I know, has crafted such a foundation that cannot be rebuilt. My dissociation is me. Without it I would be someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="positivity"&gt;Positivity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose I have limited my dissociation some in the last three years. Before was a total haze. Proof I can make progress. But how much more do I need? I have eliminated my judgments of others. I have found my sympathy for myself. I can understand my language choices better to accurately reflect my understandings and be heard by others. I sometimes have gender euphoria! I have support from nearly all my kith. My kith appreciate what I have to offer despite my reservations of compliments. I can take compliments without them knocking me down or sounding ill-received.  I was able to participate on my first day at this program. However my engagement was nearly all removed from the actual group. I didn't shut down those that chose to talk to me. I did not panic.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-13:/posts/2018-01-13-asking-questions.html</guid></item><item><title>Days of saving are over</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-11-27-saving-is-over.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/days-of-saving.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this, but I also want to pick it apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I am bedding with someone who inspires growth in me, how will I determine if this person is trying to save me? IS it okay to bed with someone who IS trying to save me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implication I believe, is that this person once was a savior/white knight. Now they realize how detrimental it was to their life, so they will no longer. Only bringing "healthy" people into their life. That is well and good. I'm curious though, does this preclude you from circling back to helping again? Or is it simply important to distinguish between the difference of saving and helping?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I, personally, Luna, find a way to connect with people who need a step up without doing more harm than good given what I am?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do hope I find more people who inspire me.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-27:/posts/2017-11-27-saving-is-over.html</guid></item><item><title>I am 6 months real now</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-11-26-six-months-real.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fuck I hate being real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six months now I have pushed, shoved, cried, tried, fallen, and gotten back up. I have changed a lot, discovering more of who I can be and stepping outside my boundaries. Let me tell you. I hate it. I would much rather be pain free than real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="heres-what-ive-found"&gt;Here's what I've found&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain. Painpainpainpainpain. Everything leads back there. I do too much, pain. I get anxious, pain. I get stressed, pain. It's all a sick loop. The more pain I am in, the more anxious and stressed I am. All of my mental health problems are triggered by pain. When my pain is minimal I am generally okay. And such a rare instance when that happens. The meds I am taking make pain killer ineffective. WTF was I thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being real makes me think I am worthy of a life. A regular life. A life where I keep good people with me, find others who inspire love, and maybe eventually settle into a place. But fuck like that will ever happen. I can understand someone who loved me sticking around if I developed this pain problem, but no one in their right mind would willingly enter into a live long love relationship with me now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I shall accept my role. I shall give my whole self to my trans siblings. For anything to lift them up. And yet, there may come a time, when I've completeld my bucket list, I may decide I've done enough. And why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="forward-on"&gt;Forward on&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I've been having some bad days with all this driving. And one of my meds ran out, but my new insurance doesn't start for a few days so I'm kinda stuck. It's the one pill I take that actually makes a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I will keep trying to remedies. I will keep fighting and changing. I will keep going. Like I have. And so long as I can cast the bad thoughts out I'll be fine right? RIGHT? Meh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope being real gets better&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-26:/posts/2017-11-26-six-months-real.html</guid></item><item><title>Reading "The Fault in our Stars"</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-11-21-fault-in-our-stars.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fault is not in our stars, but in ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of what I'm learning is that it's okay for me to love, to be loved, and to feel worthy of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once believed so strongly I did not deserve to be me. Because I have always planned to end my life you'd be better off not knowing me. I'm only to die, the only thing I am allowed is to give.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those feelings have not changed much, except my attachment to them. I am eager for, searching for a way to lose them. I can give, I can benefit, I can be me without causing pain and without ending my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't expect me to stop wishing for death however. This part of me is cemented in the foundation of my experience and I will inevitably talk about my death as a coping mechanism, strategy, and analogy for making progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it magically universal, poignant, I should choose to read this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many other facets of my life, I had little idea what this book was about, merely "a love story". With no clue of it's relevance to my health, I am thankful for the revelations of my ignorance, grateful for the inspiration the simple act of acknowledging the coincidence brings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking about changing my name again. For about two weeks I have entertained the idea, but so far have found comfort and unity in Luna Inanis Umbra.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-21:/posts/2017-11-21-fault-in-our-stars.html</guid></item><item><title>The definition of hope</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-11-17-definition-of-hope.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was not great, but tomorrow might be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/hope.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could remember who suggested this be the definition of hope. Likely Brene Brown. However this image has been adorable  and helpful for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you get to that point of believing tomorrow might be better, will probably take a lot of effort. And time. If you don't think this already, it might be real tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do believe that we all have the power within us to make tomorrow better. To fight against the crap and push towards a better life. Be hopeful. Create hope. Hope is a skill. Build that skill. Don't let pessimism, nihilism, or depression keep you from sleep walking through your life!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-17:/posts/2017-11-17-definition-of-hope.html</guid></item><item><title>I have come farther than I give myself credit</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-11-05-i-have-come-far.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amidst writing a post on reddit seeking help for reducing shame, I realized I would not get anything new from it. I have everything I need to keep revealing myself. I need to push myself and act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I learned deeply from my strict violin teacher growing up, you will never be perfect. But unlike her, I do not believe we have to aim for perfect. Her effect, and the effect of most others in my life taught me I should aim for perfect. What I found is that always aiming for perfect will shroud you from the progress you've made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-have"&gt;I have:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopped working in an industry that suffocated me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Came out, and began HRT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushed myself to squelch most of my anxiety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fought through my dysphoria enough to blend in most of the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a female voice which people compliment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bought a van, converted it enough to live in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reignited my affair with the violin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found a very real sense of living as a women, despite still fearing my femininity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began this journey from a deeply dark place. I have lifted myself out quite far considering. I must find ways to never forget this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will never quit. I will allow myself to be fully human and experience life. I will fight until life kills me.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-05:/posts/2017-11-05-i-have-come-far.html</guid></item><item><title>You own your knowledge</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-10-30-your-knowledge.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you are struggling and feel stuck, google "how to get unstuck". If you feel like you cannot change but wish to, google "how to change". If you need something in your life, simply learning ANYTHING about that subject is going to make a large difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within our perfectionism and fears we can find many reasons to keep ourselves stifled. Away from progress and hope. I've always found my fear of "learning something bad" as a detractor from my education. I feared I might pick up something damaging and unhealthy. Unfortunately you may, and you may need to take some thing you learn and push them to the side to make way for better, more accurate, or more helpful learnings. And that is okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, history, anthropology, psychology, science are all good examples where we keep learning new things, fixing old conclusions, and thus needing to cast out old understandings to integrate new ones. Science especially aims to encourage the acceptance of being wrong. So be wrong sometimes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="changing-myself"&gt;Changing myself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first began my journey of active survival I asked myself "What is change? How does it work? How can I change?" This spun me off on the creation of a metaphor for how changes, spending waking time watching change around me, and doing my very best to create some code that may help me change given what I know about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is amazing how this time investment has impacted me. Looking back on the four years or so I have had this information in me, I have changed greatly, astonishingly. I feel the undercurrent of this information help guide me towards calming confluence of epiphany. (eh I know).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I learned about habit training and how important tipping points are, while accepting "two steps forward one step back" as sacred. I exposed in myself the habits I detested. I grew to enjoy the process of fighting myself to be something better than I am. I learned that there is no shame in experimentation. To try something new will show you a new interest, or bring you a step closer to one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="which-brings-us-to-masturbation"&gt;Which brings us to masturbation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone once told me that what I am about to share with you is called philosophical masturbation, in the abstract sense. I can't tell you much more than that other than my interpretation of what she meant as a google search doesn't reveal much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe she meant that this kind of thinking: "If you want to change learn anything about change", doesn't answer anything. It is so raw and abstract it doesn't do anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I hope it inspires. You own your knowledge. You own what you put your mind in front of, and whether you invest your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I found myself agitated because I would love to learn car mechanics, lockpicking, Buddhist philosophies, martial arts, combat survival, manipulative arts, garment making, makeup, etc... But I don't have all that time! I have to pick and choose who I will become through my education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="but-mostly-i-want-to-be-strong"&gt;But mostly, I want to be strong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want the strength to stop wasting my time. I want the stability of mind to focus on the world I want to create. I want enough selfish nature to go after what I want. I want the self-worth to stand my ground with those I want in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I know, for me, I need to conquer my pain first in order to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what-do-you-need-to-conquer-first"&gt;What do you need to conquer first?&lt;/h3&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-30:/posts/2017-10-30-your-knowledge.html</guid></item><item><title>Finishing Re:Zero - another acknowledgement</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-10-25-accepting-what-i-am.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expect to see me as prideful or even arrogant in this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished watching an anime called &lt;a class="external" href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/rezero-starting-life-in-another-world-/rezero-starting-life-in-another-world-the-end-of-the-beginning-and-the-beginning-of-the-end-part-1-702401"&gt;Re: Zero&lt;/a&gt;. The transfeminine community seems to have fallen in love with one of its characters, so I felt compelled to understand why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, this is a solid anime. It speaks of relevant themes, shows great character development, while maintaining loads of mystery. Well that's my take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-am-powerful"&gt;I am powerful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I hate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am learning to accept it. Like the main character in the anime learning a similar lesson, it can be hard to know you have it and use it without feeling embarrassed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have effected so many lives. I will continue to do so. I am reminded regularly of this in me by the words and actions of those in my life. So many people open their hearts to me. So many willing to support me. It is clear I can deeply effect people. And it is my wish to see everyone grow into themselves, and create their happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I inspire empathy. I am that grounded, calm, open-hearted, loving, inspiring, hopeful, girl that makes you want to be nicer. I believe every moment holds grand weight. I carry intense responsibility and do my best to use it for the betterment of those I love. The window I see the world through inspires people so much and yet I did not choose it. Where I acquired this character I cannot know. But I suppose I can be grateful I have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-hold-myself-back"&gt;I hold myself back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this history of entering people's lives, then subconsciously reflecting back their needs, and allowing them to disappear after their resolution. I don't chase anything. I don't ask for much. And I deeply believe that if someone wants me in their life, it is up to them to keep it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run away from people I desire for I do not want to fuck up their life by falling in love with me. I believe I am meant to be alone. My purpose is to lift as many people as I can before I pass. As much as I want to be in someone's life intimately, lovingly, for a long time, I am unwilling to let them sacrifice their life to the tranny wrapped in chronic pain who's hoping to die sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel I am a burden. I am a compromise. I am pitiable. So I must become as independent, strong, and alone as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why"&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I try to resolve these conflicts, I inevitably end up thinking about my lack of identity. All that time, feeling unreal, in pain, with too much empathy, created this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can hope that after two or five more years of being real I will have created my identity, and these feelings will shift. I can hope that after all this effort to take risks, ride into the storm, and live as daringly as I can, that I will continue to gain strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I choose to follow the narrative that allows me to be fully human, I suppose I will get there. Maybe I will look back on this and see so plainly, so wisely, so happily, that I let myself continue to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="my-path-continues"&gt;My path continues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id="and-so-i-shall-follow-it"&gt;and so I shall follow it&lt;/h4&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-25:/posts/2017-10-25-accepting-what-i-am.html</guid></item><item><title>I never thought I would get this far</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-10-14-i-never-thought-i-would-get-this-far.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A cool person I spent time with for the second time, reminded me that she had seen a timeline I posted on /r/transtimelines a long while back. Amazing that she had recalled it. Yet the image of me snuck inside her memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on this moment I suddenly felt a great sense of pride. The person I was in that photo from 2015 was so different than now. The changes may seem subtle to outsiders, but to me, and to those close to me, they see a totally new level of calm, comfort, playfulness, and strength. I have never in my life been this healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I owe so much to reading Brene Brown's books. I'll never stop praising them huh? :p Especially, "The Gifts of Imperfections." In this book she describes what she calls as the guideposts to living wholeheartedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authenticity: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of What People Think&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-compassion: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Perfectionism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilient spirit: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Numbing and Powerlessness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gratitude and Joy: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Scarcity and Fear of the Dark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intuition and trusting Faith: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of the Need for Certainty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creativity: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Comparison&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play and Rest: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Exhaustion as a Status Symbol and Productivity as Self-Worth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calm and Stillness: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Anxiety as a Lifestyle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meaningful Work: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Self-Doubt and “Supposed To”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laughter, Song, and Dance: &lt;em&gt;Letting Go of Being Cool and “Always in Control”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these things truly matter; In a way I never could have understood before. I hope simply in reading these chapter titles, you garner a sense of what they mean and which you may need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ones I needed to work on the most, were self-compassion, play, laughter, and trusting faith. I see I have made progress in these areas. I am so proud of myself. And all I want is to keep exploring. Keep moving.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-14:/posts/2017-10-14-i-never-thought-i-would-get-this-far.html</guid></item><item><title>National Coming Out Day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-10-11-national-coming-out-day.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It's national coming out day. I've watched it roll by many years. I hadn't participated because it bothers me that the concept of coming out is seemingly strictly for sexuality and gender. To me, coming out is about no longer suppressing a part of you. I still do that a lot in many areas of my life. I guess I had to take care of the most pressing issues first, and I'll get to the others. Hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i-am-an-example-of-what-they-call-transsexual-female-transgender-woman-trans-feminine"&gt;I am an example of what they call transsexual female / transgender woman / trans feminine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, hiding a part of who they are is required for survival. Bullying, abuse, trauma, and many other negatively connotated words can cause a person to feel like they must hide a part of themself. As a culture we do a great job of liking some things and despising others. We want to voice our opinions and share who we are. There will always be people who feel like they must either hide or stand in the face of others. These things can be as simple as preferences in music, flavors, foods, clothing, movies, tv shows, the list could go on. What are your first thoughts while reading these statements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game of Thrones is the best show ever&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like Nickleback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love a pumpkin spice latte&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacon is the only food I need&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crop tops are my favorite!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I share this side of the story because I know so many people in my life who are riddled with stress, anxiety, pain, because of suppressed and repressed feelings/emotions/experiences. Often we don't know how much these elements weigh us down. I urge everyone to put space in their lives for introspection and self exploration. You are the only person who can help you overcome and rise up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i-also-have-a-genetic-condition-they-call-ehlers-danlos-syndrome-eds"&gt;I also have a genetic condition they call Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome (EDS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A connective tissue disorder that somehow effects my body's ability to produce collagen. Collagen is everywhere in your body. It is the structure that holds us together. Some use the analogy that collagen is like glue. I describe that my I'm stuck with Elmer's glue whereas most have Gorilla glue. For me, this condition manifests mainly as joint hypermobility. My ligaments are too loose, and the connective tissue surrounding my joints is weak and unstable. Because my ligaments do a terrible job of keeping my skeleton in place, my muscles overcompensate. They are constantly flexed, trying to support my joints, which causes them to spasm indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This condition has caused my pain for over fifteen years. My first attempts at getting help for my problems resulted in little attention. The suppression of myself had taught me it would be easier to hide from the pain than attract attention. It didn't take long for me to repress the feelings of pain and only perceive it as anxiety. Growing up I thought anxiety hurt, physically. I didn't know there was a difference between the two. I finally got "officially" diagnosed at age twenty six.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This condition causes considerable pain, daily. I never thought accepting my body as transsexual would unleash the repressed pain. Learning to cope with my body pain has been harder than the challenges of accepting who I am. Thankfully, ever year that passes I get stronger and stronger. And maybe one day, after the miracle of the universe has worked its magic, I may be considerably healthy again. I do more than hope, I act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-foundation-of-my-experience-is-dissociation"&gt;The foundation of my experience is dissociation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I don't really talk about. I have a kind of dissociation disorder that leaves me feeling like an observer to this life in front of me. My oldest memories are painted with the same disconnect. Probably the most difficult part of my life to describe, my dissociation is the root of my struggles but also my talents. The more I try to describe this awkward, frustrating, scary, part of my reality, the less connected I become. It is almost like I have to travel through a really long really small tunnel to get from my experience to the outside world. Inside is a world oscillating, swirling, clashing, constantly which takes considerable effort to harness and utilize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you describe to someone that you don't hold identities? And yet it appears you display them all the time? Or explain that I don't act in my own interest despite knowing I do? It is this subtle problem that I have all the things a normal human has, but they are buried in the mess of my dissociation. I sometimes claim I have always known everything I will ever know, but I need to go through the experience of figuring out what it was. What that likely means is that who I am has always been with me, and it takes considerable effort for me to harness it. I try hard to cement my grasp on my reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today I have found my way out of my depersonalization hell for five months. Five months I have been real. Feeling real is the most amazing wonderful awesome feeling I have ever felt. I've never had a feeling this big before. The truth of this part of my experience plays a huge role in how I interact with the world. Imagine having been trapped in a movie theater your whole life drooling over the thought of actually living the life you see in the movies and suddenly, you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-am-supposed-to-make-a-conclusion-i-guess"&gt;I am supposed to make a conclusion I guess&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming out, can be seen more abstractly than simply reserving it for gender and sexual minorities. The battle between suppression/repression and culture/community/expectations is real. We all hide some parts of our selves. We should hide less. Stand in the face of life and declare who you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not stagnant. I will change. I will express.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-11:/posts/2017-10-11-national-coming-out-day.html</guid></item></channel></rss>