<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - recovery</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stopping obsessive thoughts, another hopeful rant</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-08-15-another-hopeful-rant.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the internet, someone asked about how to stop obsessive thoughts and I went on a rant. So I figured I would share the outcome here. Sure some of it is repeat, but always a new way of saying the same thing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="find-a-focus"&gt;Find a focus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to try and find something you can deeply focus on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overactive mind is a symptom of an under utilized body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hobby, a sport, an instrument, a book. If it involves physical activity great. If it involves a fine tuned skill great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're trapped in observing mode. It's hard to get out of. But we can train. We can change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had DPDR for most of my life. At least a decade. Focused attention was the only safe place to be. That wasn't the only thing that got me out of DPDR. I still had to address my traumas. What I am suggesting is a good step. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="do-not-believe-everything-you-think"&gt;Do not believe everything you think.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not my body. I am not my thoughts. I am something more than this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DPDR, we already learn to feel disconnected from the world, and sometimes our thoughts. Or at least from certain thoughts. But it is easy, regardless of this to believe all that you are is your thoughts. That "I" is nothing more than the never ending stream of thoughts. Should you stop thinking, you would stop being. But this isn't really the case. There is more going on than your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the attempt to not believe every thought you have. Trying to sit back and be an observer to your thoughts, is part of the concept behind meditation. It is sad really, how it appears like meditation and the search for enlightenment look similar to DPDR. But they are different. Now that I am real, I can still sit back and observe my thoughts, I can let the bad thoughts roll by. I can catch myself when I get caught up in a horrible pattern that's only bringing me down. But I am now also able to live inside the stream of consciousness and let myself exist with analyzing. I can simply be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore OKAY to have all kinds of thoughts. Weird thoughts, repetitive thoughts, anxious thoughts. The more you can separate yourself from the thoughts, the more you might be able to "feel" to yourself (or interrupt your thoughts with other thoughts) that you don't want to believe those thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="narrating-your-own-life"&gt;Narrating your own life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once observing your thoughts, and no longer feeling like all you are is your thoughts, it begins to be easier to make a choice about how you narrate your own life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This speech captures much of this section - &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PhhC_N6Bm_s"&gt;This is water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have a story we believe of ourselves. A version of who we are we think we are. When you make a mistake do you tell yourself &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a piece of shit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fucked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you tell yourself &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gosh I tried hard, but next time I will do better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do we fall Bruce, so we can learn to get back up again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes happen, should I apologize for something?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hard as it seems to change our thoughts, which story we tell ourselves helps inform how we feel, and then act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is not hard. Dealing with your self is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could take a hundred people and put them through the same challenge. No two person will respond the same way. Living, staying alive, breathing, is not the hard part of life. The hard part is coping with you, dealing with you and yourself. We are our biggest critic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we can choose to change the story we believe about ourselves. I can go from thinking I am a piece of shit when I fail, to thinking failure only comes when you didn't try your best, for when you try your best it is not truly a failure and I will try again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult part of this is the beginning.  Which is where the next section comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-habits-fit-in"&gt;How habits fit in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding how habits work, are formed, and dismantled really helped me overcome a bunch of my obsessive thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is a great read or listen - &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.charlesduhigg.com/the-power-of-habit/"&gt;The Power of Habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part of changing habits in my eyes, is being able to zoom out and look at yourself, and your life from the perspective of years. I spent over a decade in DPDR. Therefore I should expect it to take me years to recover fully. Is it practical for me to think I could come back in just 6 months?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deeper you can instill this notion, that recovery is slow and not a straight line, the more likely you are to be nice to yourself when you falter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my 6 years of recovery, I have slipped back into depression 5 times. I restarted smoking 3 times. I fucked up taking my medications 4 times. I felt close to giving up many times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I zoomed out, and looked at my whole story, I realized this was how it all worked. I would make progress, but stumble, I would go slowly, because of where I started, and I could envision a future where I overcame it all. I would try to imagine what a recovered version of myself would look like 5 years from now and aim for that. And I would feel better. I would feel okay that today, I slipped up. But so long as I keep trying, going back to trying. I would get there eventually. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respect the process. Accept the process. Find any way you can to enjoy today because once you are "recovered" you'll never get to experience the joy of watching yourself recover again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope any of this is helpful my friend.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-08-15:/posts/2018-08-15-another-hopeful-rant.html</guid></item><item><title>The weight I feel</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-07-16-weight.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am feeling just how heavy all the important things are in life. The responsibility I could take on should I choose to. And this is a good feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am at my happiest it seems I am eager to take on the responsibilities of life. I am happy to be part of the ever expanding network of souls all interconnected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people find most of life mundane, repetitive, boring. I see every moment of life sacred, huge, and exhilerating... When I am taking my medications properly. haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously this post is about taking your meds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have proven to myself five times now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I simply cannot be happy if I am not taking my medications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a failing of mine. I am not bad for needing medications. IT just so happens the medication I need is related to a hormone disorder. So long as I take my medications I believe I can conquer every hurdle, every challenge, every fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep at it!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-07-16:/posts/2018-07-16-weight.html</guid></item><item><title>A year of realness: thoughts for long term sufferers of DPDR</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After 29 years of life I finally became real. In my one year of realness I have changed significantly, some ways desirable, many ways I'm still horrified of. I wanted to share some thoughts on how my long term depersonalization has impacted my entrance into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost I am still generally afraid to make changes of conviction in my life. My decades of unreality stripped me of my sense of self, desires, preferences. Today, when my mind tries to tell me what I'm attracted to or desire my first reaction is to retract and understand WHY I want that. Contrary to how I'm told I should behave, it feels deeply unsettling to me to make a choice unless I know it's my REAL choice. Sadly I learn over and over I can never know enough about me and the universe to fully comprehend the cause for my preferences. If your DPDR prevents you from self expression, I'd expect it to continue for some time after reality. The length I think will depend on how long you were unreal. I couldn't even buy a new pair of socks without freaking out when I was in DPDR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another consequence of my longevity in limbo seems to be a general susceptibility to ideas. I felt this in my unreality that any idea could infect me so I became rather timid about what I took in. My new sense of realness made me feel empowered to explore but I have suffered the consequences. I still have yet to form a strong enough conviction and fortitude to withstand confronting unhealthy ideas for any extended period of time. Be wary about your path. Respect the power of ideas. Learn intently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more personal issue stems from empathy. Since I had no sense of self nearly all my thoughts were directed toward others. This habit of thinking gave me some great insights into human behavior but also gave me some blind spots. As I've become more self oriented in my thoughts I've found more anger, selfishness, frustration, and pettiness. It sucks. Is it more than what the average person experiences? Will these emotions settle into the landscape and not feel so prominent over time? Regardless I feel pretty bad a lot of the times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate feeling anger but I think it's my surest sign of self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still unsure if being real is better. I spent so long in nihilism and suicidal ideation that I still don't see a way for me to have a fruitful or positive life. But know that this is not necessarily because of my DPDR experience. I am transsexual with a genetic chronic pain condition which is exacerbated by my hormone treatment. While my brain obviously operate more effectively on estrogen my body does not. This conflict makes me feel undeserving, useless, and unattractive. People fall for my personality because I hide the truth of my pain so when they later learn the reality of how I suffer they just feel bad for me instead of running away. I don't know if I wish they ran away or not. Most of the time I wish they did. I am no longer suicidal but I desperately want life to kill me. Would I be able to weather this storm easier if I hadn't had DPDR? Certainly. Was my DPDR caused by my transsexuality and chronic pain as a defense mechanism? Likely. Do I fear my life may still end at my own hand? Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are suffering from DPDR or recently found reality please look at a calendar and remind yourself how long you were unreal as you grow. I spent 9,940 days unreal. I have been real for 395 days. I have been real for only 4.1% of my life. That's it. I'm gonna be messy for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will not be a fast recovery if you spent five, ten, twenty years in DPDR. The fact that you got out is remarkable. Never forget that. Here's to hoping this post makes me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-06-23:/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</guid></item><item><title>I am one year real</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-28-one-year-real.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday was the day. I had a party where I invited some people close to me to come out and play in a park by the ocean. It was easier than I expected to have them all in the same place. Unfortunately some of the people I really wish were there couldn't be because of distance. But I was happy with how many were close enough to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still feel real. I know I am real. I have the kindling to a sense of self. But the flame is still weak and I have a long way to go. I still despise and suck at self expression. What I want to express is always dictated by others and feels irrelevant to me. I still don't know who I am. And I am disgusted at the process. But I do it because I must. I am human after all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this realness I have gained a lot of new skills. I can now say no better. I can test people and ideas. I can protect myself more. I can allow myself to experience life without overwhelming empathy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is honestly hard to reflect in a meaningful way lately/right now. I am so busy trying to help my mom, trying to keep moving forward. I know that's supposed to be a good thing. It is such a strange thing however, because I spent so much time reflecting, thinking abstractly and philosophically, that to merely exist feels like folly. OR something. It's just strange in a way I used to denigrate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="one-thing-is-clear"&gt;One thing is clear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have conquered the thought habits of shame. I am more hopeful than not. I am more flexible than not. I am more open to the idea of survival than not. And that is the most important thing. That is the foundation for all my future progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-28:/posts/2018-05-28-one-year-real.html</guid></item><item><title>A moment of clarity</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-09-some-clarity.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I awoke from something awkward and awful. Half past five in the morning is a lovely time to be filled with dread and unknowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I envisioned my behavior at my last job as toxic. I wanted to be a good monkey, but I failed. Then I found my way inside the last two years. I see myself from a rather disappointed place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start and stop my medications. I feel invigorated and productive only to crash into binge watching and internet lurking. I am sociable and friendly before cowering alone. I hold hope tightly then let it spill across the bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="i-try-and-try-again-to-find-firm-ground-but-sink-every-time"&gt;I try and try again to find firm ground, but sink every time.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I a bipolar sociopath?&lt;br&gt;
A depressed emotionally detached chronic pain addict?&lt;br&gt;
A ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come across intelligent and capable. I suppose those things are true, but I mean to imply I hide my chaos very well. I position myself as this caring, empathetic, selfless soul who must help others. Any hope at living selfishly is rejected in a heartbeat. I must remain trapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should hold tightly to the fact I have only been real for a year. That's it. This sensation of connection with my life is that young. As my friend said "the rest will come". I am filling in the spaces now. Finally. And I do have proof of that. So I suppose this moment is expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="does-that-mean-i-am-getting-better-slowly"&gt;Does that mean I am getting better slowly?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt this moment will amount to any obvious change quickly. It may not even be defining. Maybe it is another step of many similar moments which I am building my recovery. Maybe by writing this down, and making sure I capture this moment in my mind by writing about it I will help ensure it gets added to the glue. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-09:/posts/2018-04-09-some-clarity.html</guid></item><item><title>What can I focus on to keep recovering?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-01-things-to-do.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I know I address this in different ways periodcially, but here's another list which might inspire you to keep working your way towards recovery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a quality therapist who's aim is to reduce suffering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research the topic of anxiety &amp;amp; recovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and maintain a list of Life goals to direct your actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn/Practice Mindfulness/Meditation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise, Eat Healthy, Drink water, Sleep well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a few mantras to help instill your dreams/goals/beliefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about relationships/shame/vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin a new hobby that will help you meet new people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go outside on a daily basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read books instead of browse the internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List all of your anxieties in terms of what you fear, then write a list of actions/goals you could take to address the underlying fear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-01:/posts/2018-03-01-things-to-do.html</guid></item><item><title>Coping with negative emotions</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-24-coping-with-dejection.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Quick tip here. We all experience thoughts about negative things. This can range from guilt to shame, to suicidality. Yikes. For someone like me, where I spent years allowing suicidal thoughts exist in my mind, it can be tough to not let them win. Here's my way of releasing those thoughts and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mantras"&gt;Mantras&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not my body. I am not my thoughts. I am something more than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've seen me write this before. But this helps separate myself from the issue directly. Because...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not the problem. The problem is the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great sentence one of my older therapists shared with me. I beleive it comes from &lt;code&gt;Narrative Therapy&lt;/code&gt;, which I love and you should check out if you're interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/kill-a-part.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="release"&gt;Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next is to find a way to release these thoughts into the world. If kept inside, the boil, ferment, spoil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to a rubber duck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comes from the programming industry. The tale goes, that a programmer should first try to explain their problem to a rubber duck before seeking a real person. This is because, simply attempting to explain the problem outside your head will help you lead to conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write it down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to a rubber duck, writing it down is a safe easy way to let it out. This comes with some fun variations. If you change the audience you imagine yourself writing for, you will process the problem differently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try writing your problem to:
    1. Your self
    2. Your best friend
    3. Your mother
    4. A support group
    5. The entire internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be surprised how you change your wording to explain the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share with a real human&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find someone you trust and feel safe with. Make sure to ask yourself: "What kind of response am I hoping for?" Are you essentailly seeking validation, to vent, or are you looking for solutions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="do-not-let-your-negativity-win"&gt;Do not let your negativity win! 🤗&lt;/h2&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-24:/posts/2018-02-24-coping-with-dejection.html</guid></item><item><title>Where do I start?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-16-the-plan.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You're trapped. You feel you cannot get out of this hole you are so deep in. When you're down here, at the bottom, what does it take to get up? How do you begin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="breathe"&gt;Breathe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's take a look at a high level of an approach to recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desire - do you even want to recover?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore - seek out new information to help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage - actively pursue recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat - Cycle, rest, plateau, climb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know. You've heard it before. That's precisely the issue isn't it! Some of these concepts really help but sometimes we are in a resistive mood. We get stuck in a stubborn place and stand still begrudgingly. Change is hard. So read on anyway. Remind yourself of these things or learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this post focuses on DPDR, the issues are abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="where-are-you-now"&gt;Where are you now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your body, your brain is built for dissociation. We know this because you experience it. Some people struggle with anger. Others, maybe like yourself, struggle with depression. What a wonderous thing to accept the way you are rather than despise it. Try as you might, but you will never experience the other side. THIS IS OK. What a world it would be if you could change on a dime, or there wasn't an infinite possibility of humans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've been stuck in DPDR for so long your brain is super good at it. This is the fight. This is your struggle. You train your mind, body, and soul to resist a natural yet encouraged state of being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="desire-do-you-want-it"&gt;Desire - Do you want it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've got to want it. You've got to be willing to change who you think you are. You've got to push outside your comfort zone regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I am.&lt;br&gt;
I will never get out of this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe these thoughts, and you will, indeed, stay this way. Trapped by our history, it seems because I have been this for so long, I am unable to be any different. This is a fallacy! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not my DPDR, I struggle with DPDR.&lt;br&gt;
If I can overcome this, I will be awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This peeks at the heart of identity. I am something versus I have something. Let the problem be the problem. You are not the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can find the drive and commitment to engage in your own recovery you've got the most important piece down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="explore-there-is-always-something-new-to-learn"&gt;Explore - there is always something new to learn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing would be to learn a lot about habits, change, recovery, identity, shame, vulnerability. Be willing to explore any potential childhood trauma which may source this in you. Find your weak points and build your understanding. When you have the tools to repair a car it's a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every chapter of my life I've felt like I have "tried everything." Laughable. In a universe which is unlimited, can one truly say they have tried EVERYTHING? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="engage-conquer-those-fears"&gt;Engage - conquer those fears&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then engage. With the previous thoughts in mind, ACT! I know you can do it. I know you can face your fears and be caring towards yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accept the chapter you are in. You are at that critical point in the character's story where they finally say "ENOUGH!" and truly begin their quest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you begin yours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="tips-for-engagnement"&gt;Tips for engagnement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mindfulness is a super awesome help. Imagine you have three raisins. In silence, pick up one raisin. Look, touch, smell it. Put it in your mouth and chew. Don't count just chew. Don't swallow just chew. It will go down when it's ready. Follow the raisin into your stomach. Now. Pick up the next raisin and do the same thing. -- You can totally build the skill of present minded action outside of dpdr. You likely experience it in small ways already so we know you're capable of it. Now it's time you habitualize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use a stim toy. Tungsten ring which I've had almost a decade I sometimes spin on tables and watch. Kinda like a totem from inception. I watch I zone out. When it's done I come back. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The other thing is more Pavlovian. I bought a small bottle of smelly stuff. I spent a couple months imprinting positive, in the moment, connected feeling into the smell. Now, when I find myself fading I smell it to come back. It really helps. Like a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fucking go for it. I knwo you can do this. 💕&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-16:/posts/2018-02-16-the-plan.html</guid></item><item><title>I need to get away from the internet, what can I do?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-02-what-to-do.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hate how you spend all your time in front of computer screens or on the internet wasting time? Here is a list of ideas you can peruse for inspiration. Some of these are quite unconventional. Read carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pluck all your body hair with tweezers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice moving one eye but not the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look up anatomy drawings and try to twitch all your muscles independently (Netter's atlas baby)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice character voices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn how to throat sing (proper name?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clean every little nook and cranny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take something apart and put it back together again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download Zim wiki and start your own personal wiki of your life or simply write in a journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go down memory lane and look at your old photos from 1992&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;philosophize about time, perception of time, habits around time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice and strengthen the muscles that wiggle your ears (start with extreme eye brow lifts to identify the muscles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read books! - use the library, find an e-reader with e-ink display, borrow from friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work on a puzzle if you have the flat surface area for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design tattoos for yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look through etsy for any futures hobbies you might want to get into&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;video chat with people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;re lace your shoes with a different pattern for funzies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice Taoist masturbation/sex stuff to connect with your body in new ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn to whistle in three different ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turn off all lights, get as dark as possible, and listen. Try to identify every sound you can hear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block out as much sound and light as you can, and imagine scary stuff happening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch a visualizer while you listen to music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice an instrument if you have one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write letters to people, hell even to strangers. Just put the letter in some random mail box. Write nice things, inspirational things, love things. Not to scare people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch documentaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explore things you don't understand, like maybe sexuality and gender (my faves)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch free online college lectures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you watch entertainment media, have paper ready to critique it while you watch instead of simply droning out in it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice breathing intentionally, like, breathe real slow for two minutes, or breathe slow then fast or something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn origami&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buy a van, convert it to an RV, quit your job and become a nomad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite pass time. Conceptualize context. Understand context. Play with context. Dive your mind into the tiniest concept of molecules and focus on water, fluidity, or really explore the fabrics nearby. Zoom out to the universe level and conceptualize the galaxies, the vastness of space time, the orbital patterns if our solar system. Think of how the moon waxes and wanes, how it effects our planet, the way it illuminates the night. Think about how what you choose to think informs your understanding of reality, what your life feels like, and how you perceive others and their actions. Context is queen.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-02:/posts/2018-02-02-what-to-do.html</guid></item><item><title>Are you a failure?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-01-stand-up.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Or do you simply believe the thought that you are a failure? If you HAVE failed in the past, can you not find ways to get better so you don't fail the same way again in the future? Failure is common but failure only comes knowing you didn't try your best. If you try your best it should not be considered failing. You put your all into that. Those failures should really be lessons learned. An opportunity to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you have been given the challenge of DPDR in your lifetime. Others get cancer, or abuse, or spinal injuries, or schizophrenia, or others. You have been given the chance to overcome this in your life. It is not easy. But everyone has their thing. And if you can stand up, brush yourself off, look around, put those fists up and keep fighting, I know you will find a way to conquer these demons. To find out why you think you hate yourself and banish those thoughts. To find all the reasons you love yourself, how you are good, and how you want to get better. To learn to deserve the love you receive and feel worthy of the good things you are lucky to experience. If this is something you want, you'll have to find it yourself. You'll have to fight, be patient, and learn a lot of new things. But this is your life. Your only life. Will you take your own hand?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-01:/posts/2018-02-01-stand-up.html</guid></item><item><title>Life is not hard, dealing with your self is</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-15-live-is-not-hard.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Life itself is not hard. Every living creature figures out how to do it. Our body and minds are designed to keep living as long as we can. Some species have apparently survived for tens of thousands of years, and some over a million right? Life, living, not dying, is easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-against-the-world.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealing with your &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt; is hard. Why is it that two people can experience the same traumatic event but respond so differently? How can some bounce back while others stay crushed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/survived-every-day.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is to say, that life is not to blame. No outside force is going to save you, fix you. YOU ARE GOING TO FIX YOU. Because you can, and you will, because you fucking love yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/afraid-to-fail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is your life, this dark, scary, sad, horrifying, anxious, depressed, dissociated, mess of a life, why not do and try everything to find as much joy, happiness, playfulness, fun, love, light as possible? This is your only life! Make it what you will, not the result of giving in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-think-you-have-time.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All it takes is a spark, an unending flame that boils inside you to never give up, never give in, and never forget to keep pushing, to keep trying, and to explore the world and all of reality so you can find what feeds you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that spark ignites, you'll know. Once you find a way to keep that flame burning no matter how sad, depressed, anxious, or fucked up you feel, you'll know. Once you have that day, where you are down in the pits but remember, oh right, I've got this flame, this urge, this desire, this need to recovery, and take another step out, you'll know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-get-better.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-15:/posts/2018-01-15-live-is-not-hard.html</guid></item><item><title>Questions from after a suicide attempt</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-13-asking-questions.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was written in the midst of a partial hospitalization after a serious bout with suicidality. Never stop asking yourself questions. These questions helped bring me to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="life-is-not-hard-dealing-with-yourself-is"&gt;Life is not hard, dealing with yourself is.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billions of people have lived and died all with their own experience of life, reality. Is it that life is hard intrinsically or that your experience, your perspective, is what creates the challenges you face? Is it intrinsically difficult to alter the way you respond to the minutia of what life brings? Can we assess our attachment to certain behaviors, thoughts, reactions, and make choices regarding their relevancy? Have you ever watched someone succeed at something you fail at and wonder how they are so lucky? What causes us to respond to events the way we do? and how do you close the gap to respond desirably?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that some others do not struggle the way I do? Are my problems permanent? Which are conquerable? Which can only be managed? Can you approach your problems from many angles to determine which type your problems truly are? And how is it that others simply move forward after traumas, hardship, and problems? What do they know that you don't? Is it as simple as saying I will choose this response? What even makes an even something you will struggle with? How long does it take for you to generally get beyond the struggle and moved forward? Can you find the tools to help minimize the amount of time you struggle so you can move forward? Is this related to change and how we cope with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between your self and other selves? Is it possible to see how another responds to certain stimuli and calculate the distance between your response and theirs? How often is the distance merely a  formation of habit? Are habits all that hard to change? How often is the distance a gap in knowledge or awareness of a concept? Is it really hard to open yourself to learning something new?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dissociation-and-its-role-in-my-life"&gt;Dissociation and its role in my life.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of my memories from childhood contain dissociation. I always felt shuffled along by the whims of my kith, doing and being what they wanted me to be. This sense of always watching and always thinking led me to the conclusions I have formed and the perspective I have acquired. I have wisdom because I have never truly lived my life. My sharing is never just for my expression. I live in the windows of others and calculate language to account for them, not me. I try not to dissociate. My transition is about trying to take hold of my association. I only ever feel associated alone. I don't feel like I can ever get rid of my dissociation. What I am, what I know, has crafted such a foundation that cannot be rebuilt. My dissociation is me. Without it I would be someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="positivity"&gt;Positivity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose I have limited my dissociation some in the last three years. Before was a total haze. Proof I can make progress. But how much more do I need? I have eliminated my judgments of others. I have found my sympathy for myself. I can understand my language choices better to accurately reflect my understandings and be heard by others. I sometimes have gender euphoria! I have support from nearly all my kith. My kith appreciate what I have to offer despite my reservations of compliments. I can take compliments without them knocking me down or sounding ill-received.  I was able to participate on my first day at this program. However my engagement was nearly all removed from the actual group. I didn't shut down those that chose to talk to me. I did not panic.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-13:/posts/2018-01-13-asking-questions.html</guid></item><item><title>Days of saving are over</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-11-27-saving-is-over.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/days-of-saving.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this, but I also want to pick it apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I am bedding with someone who inspires growth in me, how will I determine if this person is trying to save me? IS it okay to bed with someone who IS trying to save me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implication I believe, is that this person once was a savior/white knight. Now they realize how detrimental it was to their life, so they will no longer. Only bringing "healthy" people into their life. That is well and good. I'm curious though, does this preclude you from circling back to helping again? Or is it simply important to distinguish between the difference of saving and helping?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I, personally, Luna, find a way to connect with people who need a step up without doing more harm than good given what I am?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do hope I find more people who inspire me.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-27:/posts/2017-11-27-saving-is-over.html</guid></item></channel></rss>