<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Volunteering at an organization</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-27-volunteering.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week I volunteered at an LGBT organization. This was the first time I volunteered like this. I am super glad I did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to know what to write here for I do not want to overshare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I did well. I was given a task which I took responsibility for and within three days I had finisehd it. I hope it has a helpful impact. And that's all I can hope. The last day I helped set up for an event. I even participated in the event by playing my violin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned in participating in the event I am rather reserved with new people. Proteting my emotions and the reality of my inner world. The others around me seemed very willing to expose themselves. Maybe that is because I already went through a phase of that level of vulnerability. Maybe being on the road keeps me wary. Maybe I was so timid because I am unsure of exactly how to act while I volunteer at places like this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a lot for me to step into the door. I was afraid I would do something wrong or be bad, or that the org would be too dysfunctional to work with. But everything went fine. I am now excited to find other places to volunteer at, to learn from, and keep working out how to give back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This volunteering took a lot out of me. I spent an extra week in a place too cold, and found myself suffering from the pain I took on while helping. But I am so happy I did it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-27:/posts/2018-10-27-volunteering.html</guid></item><item><title>First time with dry needling</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-18-dry-needling.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I cried and cried from pain relief. Just north of DC I had an experience with a Neuromuscular therapist who was recommended to me. He did some Myofascial Release therapy and dry needling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dry needling&lt;/code&gt;, or, Trigger point needling is when someone sticks an accupuncture needle directly into a muscle that's all fucked up, wiggles the needle around a bit in hopes of getting that tissue to release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Myofascial Release&lt;/code&gt; therapy is not a massage, but when some does this slow pushing and moving on your skin or pressure into a muscle to get your body to relax tissues that have been held tight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I had an osteopath who would make me laugh with joy in relief from my pain. I thought that was remarkable, so did he. But here, with people trained in MFR and dry needling, I cry, I sob with pain relief. Even thinking about the experience will get me to well up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assesment for me is always the fun part. I get to talk about how I see things, what I know, and how my body is fucked up. Who doesn't like talking about themselves? Something I always try to get a new person like this to appreciate is what I already know. I prefer when they talk to me like I'm advanced because I love to ask questions when I don't know. This guy was amazing. He explained a whole lot. Taught me some great movements and was really kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he did some MFR. On my back I pointed out the problem area. The beginning was fine, I think he was feeling his way around. But then he went to my spine. With two hands vertically on my spine he began to pull things apart along my hinge point, which is my L1 vertabrae. Within seconds my heart began pounding. A moment later I was bwaling my eyes out. Such intense relief. And as always I was flooded with emotion about my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my life. Caught in perpetual pain, always needing help for relief. And see, this exposes just how much pain you hold in you all the time. Accept it loser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so easy to get lost in how much I hate this life, but these sadder thoughts merely float around the core feeling of intense relief. So it's not all that bad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dry-needling"&gt;Dry needling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part was scarier than I anticipated. I have had accupuncture. This is not that. This is way more trying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He chose to work on my Quadratus Lumborum. The left needle goes in. That's fine. Tiny thing goes in quick. But then, he wiggles it around and suddenly I feel exactly the muscle, exactly where the needle is and it hurts. A lot. The needle comes out and the pain beings to subside. He continues to press into the area to get those miscles to relax. Yikes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I slowly get up and do some overhead side stretches. Immediately, I am more flexible. So much more I laugh and cry at it. Instead of feeling the pull of my stretch at the attachment points on my muscles I feel the muscle tissue stretching. A distinclty differnt sensation that leaves you feeling good rather than bad. Both of us were amazed the difference one needle gave me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we went back in for a needle in the other side. MY right side hurt a LOT more. I was pulling in, cringing from the pain and crying out because it hurt so intensely. I never cry out from pain. This was hard. And it took a good while longer for the relaxing to occur after. But still the eventuality of it gave me a great comfort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a long time laying down afterward feeling this new body I am in. It is not cured. It is not pain free. But the range of movement, the comfort, the filling of my body, and the minimzed intensity of my neural pain is significant, and I am joyus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue seeking treatment like this 😍&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-18:/posts/2018-10-18-dry-needling.html</guid></item><item><title>Brothertiger - High Tide</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-18-high-tide.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine showed me this song early in the year. Ever since this song has become my anthem. The most cathartic example of my dissociation and it is about time I shared it here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not felt so viscerally reflected by song lyrics in a very long time. I am lucky to know it. I am thankful for my friend for showing it. I hope if you struggle with DPDR you too find some connection to the words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/joPlQUp1wHo'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;You run through the forest
Away from it all
You soak in the current
With your back to the wall
You swim through the tides
When the summer calls
You follow the sounds of
The waterfall

I follow to the edge
And I fall to the floor
I swim in circles
And I drift evermore
It seems I can’t remember
Who I was before
I’m floating in an ocean
That I can’t explore

But I can hang on to the surface
In flowing, oscillated time
My lungs are filling up with water
But I won’t sink to the void

I climbed to the top
Of the fiery wall
I swallowed my emotions
And embraced the fall
Exploring through the silence
Of the shadows call
I’m swimming through the current
And I feel it all
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-18:/posts/2018-10-18-high-tide.html</guid></item><item><title>Will I keep this name forever?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-17-changing-name.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am faced with a government paperwork issue that will be much easier if I change my name legally. Another one of the issues I have been avoiding for my transition. So what should I do about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked the name Luna Inanis Umbra three years ago. It came to me shortly after I remembered the meaning behind the tattoo on my hand. At the time I still felt unreal. I did not feel I was "allowed" to pick a name for myself. So I picked something symbolic so I had some complex deep answer to why that name. OTherwise I might end up picking a name because I, &lt;em&gt;shock&lt;/em&gt; "liked it". That was not okay. Since I have a love of latin, it was pretty simple to translate into something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always figured I wouldn't change it legally for a while because if I become real, I may not need the name anymore. And here I am, real for over a year, and I still am okay with it. But will I feel that way in another year, or five? That I don't know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="moving-foward"&gt;Moving foward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I am stuck now thinking about how everything will be easier if I change my name, trying to decide what to do. Do I deal with my birth name on my future documents and try to change it all again later? Do I alter my chosen name to be more positive than dark? Do I choose a completely new name? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One friend suggested I could change the middle and last name to something other than Inanis Umbra. Those two are the dark parts of the name. Others seem to like Luna as a first name for me. And for the most part I like it too. I have gotten some very nice metaphor from people that are rooted in understanding my relationship to the moon. So maybe brightening the rest of the name is okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe I shouldn't be such a floof and just pick some simple girl name, change my middle name like I had originally planned with my mother, and just get it over with. Sometimes I go by Vanessa at places that ask for your name because sometimes people mess up Luna. Or maybe I pick a name with the first letter of my birth name so I can keep the same initials. Or maybe I change some of it. Fuck I don't know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel I need to make a decision soon. Every week I delay, the longer the paperwork will take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sucks-having-to-pick-your-name"&gt;Sucks having to pick your name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know so many trans people who have had to pick a name, and I must say, it is much easier when your birth name is just fine. Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-17:/posts/2018-10-17-changing-name.html</guid></item><item><title>Going to a support group in Maryland</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-17-md-support-group.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Something I appreciate from everyone I talk to about local support groups for transgender people is how important they are to finding a social circle. The support is nice, but having a place for us all to go so we can meet is invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight I went to a support group with my friend. There I found a group very similar to the one I spent so much time at. A group growing, sometimes shocked at that size, trying to find ways to support the growth, and a wide variety of expressions and peoples. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the meeting I mustered up the courage to tell the whole group a brief sentence about my situation and an invite to get food. I had never done this before. My heart was pounding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I left on this trip I have yet to push myself into new spaces again. This was the first time I was with new trans faces. And I was happily rewarded and comfortable in the face of vulnerability and risk. Four people joined my friend and I for some munch and glug. I was so happy to have the opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-f-u-t-u-r-e"&gt;The F U T U R E&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke with them about my long term goals of finding a way to give back to the trans community. Something I feel I am finally ready to begin forming and putting into my plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have so many ideas in my head about where I might end up. I can feel that this vanlife journey is going to uncover how exactly I will give back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I have thought of so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tucking undergarment product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trans Lifeline operator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fund for laser hair removal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local trans outreach support organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support group fascilitator/organizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homeless shelter / halfway house exclusively for trans people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social instituation for maintaining connections within the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given how much of a "in the mud" kind of person when helping people I can't imagine working on higher level things, like legislation, politics, or government. Those things are for different people than I. But who knows, maybe I will evolve into that person over time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I hope I do is remember that the focus is not what I want, but what the trans community NEEDS. I am not in this for self indulgence, but for having a real impact on our lives for the better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-17:/posts/2018-10-17-md-support-group.html</guid></item><item><title>Playing my violin in a park for the first time this year</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-16-violin-in-park.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today was weird and hard. Playing in an open space is so different than the comfort of Vanessa. This wide open park with plenty of people walking through, but very few walking by. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played quietly for fear of disturbance. I felt my technical classical pieces were too high class and uppity. But I played them anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt the pressure of needing to be perfect and cringed at my mistakes. I worried I was always out of tune. Thankfully the violin was shifting to the weather and went out of tune itself a lot. OR was it??? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got too cold and my fingers couldn't play well so I played one of the harder songs and quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman from the playground 1000ft afar yelled out to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was really beautiful thank you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only person to address me while I played. For someone to yell out like that really calmed me. Thank you person. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-16:/posts/2018-10-16-violin-in-park.html</guid></item><item><title>Chickies Rock County Park PA</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-12-chickies-rock.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After leaving my grandmother I stopped at the Susquehanna River for the sunset. Here I went exploring a bit, played my violin and chatted with a couple people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One was a mid twenties man studying for a nursing program who enjoyed my music and started a chat. From Iraq originally it was very cool to hear his persepctive on some of the idiosyncrasies of US culture. And he was sweet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At sunset I tried to play my violin but it was too darn cold. I didn't play much. But a man with his dog listening was interested in the vanlife and had plans for it so we chatted a bit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had strong urges to come out to people. To tell them what I am. But I did not. It never was truly relevant to the conversation, and if so, only in a tertiary way. I am not entirely sure why I still feel the urge to tell people all the time. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-12:/posts/2018-10-12-chickies-rock.html</guid></item><item><title>Loving extended family</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-12-extended-family.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am lucky. Very luck I feel. The beginning of my trip has had me visting three different types of extended family. Aunt/Uncle, Cousin and Grandmother. They are all very kind towards me and don't care one bit about my transition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember growing up feeling afraid of all my extended family. There was some light bullying from a few of them, but mostly I was just so afraid fo be myself around them because I felt I didn't really know them. Couple that with how strongly I tended to be an observer and I didn't develop much with my extended family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I am getting the opportunity to meet them, seemingly for the first time, and they've all been wonderful. Instead of feeling trapped in my past, I feel welcomed in the present. I get to see who they all really are, and get to recover further through their generosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aunt and uncle I visited last week were, honestly, a scarier visit at first. While I had seen them for an afternoon this summer I have very few experiences with them. MY fears were mostly based off an old memory of fourth of july about 20 years ago. They were fun people, but also more wild than I was familiar with. Fireworks in the backyard and drinking, and my accidental jello shot just left me feeling guilty and afraid. While they are more energetic, fun people, they are nice as can be, understanding, and easy to be around. And sadly I didn't get to experience that growing up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandmother is another one that surprised me. And I think I should jsut be learning that all my extended family are going to surprise me haha. She is a wonderful person who has been kind and udnerstanding, wise and with a "real" persepctive on life. Something I experience inside my communities is a very intense idealistic progressive persepctive that, I feel, often doesn't take into account the reality of today. My grandmother can see both sides of it. And in that, has a very awesome perspective. Notably, I went swimming with her. I wore a new bathing suit and went into a women's locker room for the first time. I felt very lucky and comfortable thanks to her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-meaning-of-support-from-extended-family"&gt;The meaning of support from extended family&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know so many trans people who lose a lot of family when they come out. We are taught that family sticks together. And when they don't it hurts real bad. This is why many in the trans community have learned to build chosen families. This is harder still mostly because we are taught that family is somehow better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAving extended family support a trans person is huge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it has helped me marry my past life with my current life. I can slowly reintegrate my old memories into the person I am today. I feel less ashamed about my past. I accept myself more today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to finish life without this but it feels pretty darn good to have it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if only I can finish this all up and be a better family member to them. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-12:/posts/2018-10-12-extended-family.html</guid></item><item><title>Railroad Museum of Pennsylvania</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-10-railroad-museum.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I went to see trains with my grandmother! What a cool place. I do wish I had much more time to go over everything as I am learning I really like to soak in this stuff. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-10:/posts/2018-10-10-railroad-museum.html</guid></item><item><title>A sample of some of my cousin's amazing art</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-06-cousins-art.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My cousin is amazing. She spends a lot of time making art. I just had to take some pictures to remember her, our time together, and how wonderful they are. Take a look&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-06:/posts/2018-10-06-cousins-art.html</guid></item><item><title>End of my first visit</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-06-first-visit.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I feel pretty good about my first visit. I very quickly purged technology from my mind and focused on the person I was with. We went out for a short hike at the Deleware Water Gap, ate ice cream and watched a tv show, and spent time at the library doing tech things. It was very nice and much more relaxing than the last time I saw my cousin. I am very glad she is doing well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My body is not happy though. The walk and and her uncomfortable furniture left my back aching and I am feeling is after the drive into PA. I definitely feel I am stressing and pushing to be social and see everyone. And what I really want to do is lie down for a week and then finish some stuff in Vanessa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is my one of my mother's brothers. I am looking forward to seeing him and his family because I haven't spent much time with them, and, when we had a short visit this summer it went really well. I really like being around family who are nice and supportive. It has a huge impact on unifying my past with the present. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-06:/posts/2018-10-06-first-visit.html</guid></item><item><title>Tappan Zee Bridge NJ [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-03.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/tappan-zee-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5-more"&gt;... +5 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/tappan-zee-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/tappan-zee-3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/tappan-zee-4.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/tappan-zee-5.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/tappan-zee-6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-03:/posts/2018-10-03.html</guid></item><item><title>Finally Fall - Leaving MA once again</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-03-finally-fall-left.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am waking up in Connecticut. I don't have much going on in my head or heart. I am ready. I am moving. And I have a plan for where to go and when. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am eager to get to get to warmer weather and feel more comfortable about showering. I am eager to learn the new logistics of having a sink and grey water. I am eager to see people with all this sense of self and reality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sad to have left all these people. People I've known for a long time. People I didn't get to know well enough. People who I just met. But since my heart is in Vanessa I am dragged away by a sense of adventure and purpose. I must finish this journey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="age-and-possiblity"&gt;Age and possiblity.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am thinking about age. In youth I heard so many people suggest their life was ruined, over, or void of possiblity. I felt that way. Even when I was doing interseting things I felt my life was going to be shit. Now I can see how most people's greatest acheivements occur after 30 after 35 even. It takes a long time to build enough to do those great things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 30 this year. I can see the goals I've had in mind for over a decade, and how I need more time to learn what I need to learn in order to actualize those goals. And so this journey I am on is a conscious choice to bring me closer to those goals in the way that I know how. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this chapter brings me more new. I am afraid after all, that I will stagnate. When I have so much to do I cannot. I need to heal. I need a better body. I need more practice. More skills. More interactions with different kinds of people. More challenges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us hope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/angels-dont-worry.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-03:/posts/2018-10-03-finally-fall-left.html</guid></item></channel></rss>