<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Amanda Palmer - In My Mind</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-07-10-in-my-mind-palmer.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q9WZtxRWieM'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-07-10:/posts/2018-07-10-in-my-mind-palmer.html</guid></item><item><title>Help people, not ideas</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am offering some time and money to someone in my life who is heavily involved in a church. As I considered if they had enough help I played a quick story in my head where I volunteered my time on a regular basis. Yes, I am not religious and have no interest in becoming so. But I still would want to help this person out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then concluded that I like to help people and not ideas. This is a nifty little nugget I think I should hold on to. It does a good job describing me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another conversation I had described a philosopher as someone who presents ideas but does not hold to them. Someone who may put together new ideas but not be attached to them. My friend rejected this notion. I don't care who is right, only that I think I was describing me and my situation. I enjoy knowing many perspectives on the same issue so I can help people, not promote a specific idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say I don't have my own feelings on issues, but that my general approach is to engage with people on their terms not against my own beliefs or ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I can be friends with the person who voted for trump, the anarchist, the socialist democrat, the non politically correct. It is why I have always seen my value in this life as a stepping stone for others. But don't follow me. I am not trying to make a value judgement on my way of life. I wouldn't recommend other people live like me or think like me. I am not very good at taking care of myself. I put everyone else before me. I struggle to understand who I am, what I want, what I like, and where I want to go. I expect and practically seek solitude. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think this phrase, I help people, not ideas, is a solid phrase to help others understand why I am the way I am. And apparently I am writing about it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-07-07:/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</guid></item><item><title>A year of realness: thoughts for long term sufferers of DPDR</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After 29 years of life I finally became real. In my one year of realness I have changed significantly, some ways desirable, many ways I'm still horrified of. I wanted to share some thoughts on how my long term depersonalization has impacted my entrance into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost I am still generally afraid to make changes of conviction in my life. My decades of unreality stripped me of my sense of self, desires, preferences. Today, when my mind tries to tell me what I'm attracted to or desire my first reaction is to retract and understand WHY I want that. Contrary to how I'm told I should behave, it feels deeply unsettling to me to make a choice unless I know it's my REAL choice. Sadly I learn over and over I can never know enough about me and the universe to fully comprehend the cause for my preferences. If your DPDR prevents you from self expression, I'd expect it to continue for some time after reality. The length I think will depend on how long you were unreal. I couldn't even buy a new pair of socks without freaking out when I was in DPDR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another consequence of my longevity in limbo seems to be a general susceptibility to ideas. I felt this in my unreality that any idea could infect me so I became rather timid about what I took in. My new sense of realness made me feel empowered to explore but I have suffered the consequences. I still have yet to form a strong enough conviction and fortitude to withstand confronting unhealthy ideas for any extended period of time. Be wary about your path. Respect the power of ideas. Learn intently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more personal issue stems from empathy. Since I had no sense of self nearly all my thoughts were directed toward others. This habit of thinking gave me some great insights into human behavior but also gave me some blind spots. As I've become more self oriented in my thoughts I've found more anger, selfishness, frustration, and pettiness. It sucks. Is it more than what the average person experiences? Will these emotions settle into the landscape and not feel so prominent over time? Regardless I feel pretty bad a lot of the times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate feeling anger but I think it's my surest sign of self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still unsure if being real is better. I spent so long in nihilism and suicidal ideation that I still don't see a way for me to have a fruitful or positive life. But know that this is not necessarily because of my DPDR experience. I am transsexual with a genetic chronic pain condition which is exacerbated by my hormone treatment. While my brain obviously operate more effectively on estrogen my body does not. This conflict makes me feel undeserving, useless, and unattractive. People fall for my personality because I hide the truth of my pain so when they later learn the reality of how I suffer they just feel bad for me instead of running away. I don't know if I wish they ran away or not. Most of the time I wish they did. I am no longer suicidal but I desperately want life to kill me. Would I be able to weather this storm easier if I hadn't had DPDR? Certainly. Was my DPDR caused by my transsexuality and chronic pain as a defense mechanism? Likely. Do I fear my life may still end at my own hand? Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are suffering from DPDR or recently found reality please look at a calendar and remind yourself how long you were unreal as you grow. I spent 9,940 days unreal. I have been real for 395 days. I have been real for only 4.1% of my life. That's it. I'm gonna be messy for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will not be a fast recovery if you spent five, ten, twenty years in DPDR. The fact that you got out is remarkable. Never forget that. Here's to hoping this post makes me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-06-23:/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</guid></item><item><title>Approved for Lupron</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a month now I have been waiting for my doctor to see if I could get my insurance to cover Lupron as my primary anti-androgen. I was told a week ago or so that I was approved and I will start taking Lupron injections soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting because Lurpon acts in either a monthly or quarterly dose. It would be very hard for me to miss my doses and fuck up my hormones again. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am also trying to not get my hopes up. I have no boobs again and what if this doesn't work again? What if the side effects are worse? What if? So I am just waiting patiently until the end of the month when I have my appointment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I am hoping it goes very poorly. But, I think that's just my dysphoric depression eating at me. And if it goes well, I will be ecstatic and happy to be girl again. I can't wait to get back on the road.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-06-21:/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</guid></item><item><title>I am one year real</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-28-one-year-real.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday was the day. I had a party where I invited some people close to me to come out and play in a park by the ocean. It was easier than I expected to have them all in the same place. Unfortunately some of the people I really wish were there couldn't be because of distance. But I was happy with how many were close enough to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still feel real. I know I am real. I have the kindling to a sense of self. But the flame is still weak and I have a long way to go. I still despise and suck at self expression. What I want to express is always dictated by others and feels irrelevant to me. I still don't know who I am. And I am disgusted at the process. But I do it because I must. I am human after all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this realness I have gained a lot of new skills. I can now say no better. I can test people and ideas. I can protect myself more. I can allow myself to experience life without overwhelming empathy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is honestly hard to reflect in a meaningful way lately/right now. I am so busy trying to help my mom, trying to keep moving forward. I know that's supposed to be a good thing. It is such a strange thing however, because I spent so much time reflecting, thinking abstractly and philosophically, that to merely exist feels like folly. OR something. It's just strange in a way I used to denigrate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="one-thing-is-clear"&gt;One thing is clear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have conquered the thought habits of shame. I am more hopeful than not. I am more flexible than not. I am more open to the idea of survival than not. And that is the most important thing. That is the foundation for all my future progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-28:/posts/2018-05-28-one-year-real.html</guid></item><item><title>Why must I keep trying?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-17-wishing-for-progress.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been on the verge of wanting to make more progress in my transition. I am still trapped by so many things. I want to keep moving forward. I want to become stronger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I get right in front of one of my walls it is always the physical pain I experience that laughs at me. I can no longer tell if I want to learn how to be expressive, or if I should give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be expressive, to have gender, to be able to look at cis people without assuming something negative. But I feel my chronic pain is a never ending tunnel into all the old ways of being. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't I just accept this is my limit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fucking hate this shit. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-17:/posts/2018-05-17-wishing-for-progress.html</guid></item><item><title>My experience on the victim mentality</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-15-victim-mentality.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having come from the undercarriage of social life, the depressed anxious shamed part of society I was surrounded by the victim mentality for a large part of my conscious life. I held it, the victim mentality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people are born into situations either physical or social that lends them to learn towards victim rather than say, survivor. Not everyone is so lucky. I had to build my way out of the victim mentality and it is no small feat. Almost two decades of anxiety and depression were battled, a lifetime of self shaming and fear to overcome, an amalgam of bad habits wrestled with. I spent at least fifteen years in chaos. It took me six years to hit the tipping point. &lt;strong&gt;Six years of concerted, committed, careful, effort&lt;/strong&gt; to finally overcome the victim mentality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I finally committed to recovery, I wanted help, I sometimes looked for help, but I never knew what to do with it. &lt;strong&gt;I was too ashamed, stuck in too dark a place.&lt;/strong&gt; I wasn't quite ready. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say the help you receive before you are ready has little to no impact. I disagree. While a single instance may not amount to much, a long history of people being supportive makes the process a little smoother, a little easier once you finally take hold. If my memories were filled with people who were unsupportive it might have taken an even deeper amount of effort to figure it all out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="taking-control"&gt;Taking control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know lots of people talk about how to inspire that moment where you finally take hold of your own life and never let go again. I write for myself, and mostly so I never forget the process. I really believe this archival habit of mine is a strong element to my continued success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I have always been an archivist. I journaled here and there, but never deleted, never trashed. My digital journal alone began it's journey in later 2011. I finally gained steam around early 2013 and since then I have written on 50% of all days since 2013. That's a lot of writing. A lot of self reflection. And I am proud of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a quote from the very first entry on my digital journal from October 29th 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i think i did ok today despite having played games for multiple hours. i wonder how i will curb that mental trap. in fact, right now i want to play it again. maybe get high and slam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that might be ok. i need to put in place a schedule/regiment of when/how long i can play video games. hopefully it gets less and less as time goes on and then i play no games at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proud to say that I have all but given up video games. They rarely consume my time and when they do, I am intentional about it. So maybe it took seven years but whatevs. I made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="from-a-poem-i-wrote-a-number-of-years-ago"&gt;From a poem I wrote a number of years ago:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="internal" href="https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2016-05-02-lifeismoreinterestingthanthat.html"&gt;Life is more interesting than that&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impossible it seems to be understood wholly,&lt;br&gt;
To feel less alien and more human.&lt;br&gt;
Each of us orbiting in and out of relationships&lt;br&gt;
causing cataclysmic shifts in the arc of our lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you bump into someone here you are affecting not just the other person, but yourself as well. You choosing to interact does something to you however small. Every moment is sacred. Every interaction a cosmic mess and that's okay. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-15:/posts/2018-05-15-victim-mentality.html</guid></item><item><title>Happy 2 years Vanessa 😍</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the love so far, the experiences, and more to come. I'm sorry you were hurt recently, please trust I will take care of you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-13:/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</guid></item><item><title>Starting Finasteride</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-12-finasteride.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I begun taking Finasteride as my testosterone suppressant. The spironolactone had fucked with me enough that I put my foot down to try something else. While, this chemical is not very effective, it is a stepping stone to trying Lupron. So I will try to track my progress with taking Finasteride to see if I notice a difference. But hopefully I well get on Lupron soon. That is much more appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I get my tits back 😡&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-12:/posts/2018-05-12-finasteride.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa got in a minor accident</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-11-accident.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My mother was driving, we were shortly off the highway and a merging truck did not yield to us. My mother had no option to change lanes and the clipped my slider door and scraped toward the back. Very minor, but damn am I pissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not been in an accident since I was sixteen. I have no clue what's happening or whether they can even repair Vanessa back to original without simply replacing parts. And of course that's what I'd prefer because fuck them for their claimed blatant arrogance in assuming we were going to move over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it's time to deal with another thing on my plate that is full of uncertainty and I'm sure, more hassle than I imagine... I'll post pictures after it's all over. Sigh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-11:/posts/2018-05-11-accident.html</guid></item><item><title>I went to my first concert in a long time to see "This Will Destroy You"</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-11-this-will-destroy-you.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was super jazzed. They were doing a tenth anniversary tour of their self title album. My favorite album of theirs alongside their first, Young Mountain. If they were playing their new stuff I would not have gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I went because this album has played an important roll in my life. I started listening to it in Burlington Vermont during my one year at school. I was so deeply depressed and ashamed, I used to walk around listening to their music and some others all around the Winooski River. I would get high off my ass and sink into the music until nothing existed except my horrible thought habits swirling around the atmosphere of the music. I love those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I felt rather disconnected from any emotional experience during the show. I was happy. I was enjoying watching strangers nod and sway instead of moshing and dancing. I was present, but I felt rather flat. This feeling caught me off guard. I began thinking that being "real" is worse, because I am not experiencing the same level of emotional realness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After talking with some friends (yes I back date), I have begun to hope that this is simply a consequences of my recent realness. That I still need more time to come into and fill this life. I should have more patience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless. I was super super happy to get to go. I learned a lot. I enjoyed being slammed by these melodies I fell in love with almost a decade ago, and I drank a lot of water 😵&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-11:/posts/2018-05-11-this-will-destroy-you.html</guid></item><item><title>Gallery Page updated</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-05-08-gallery-update.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I finally updated the gallery page to be more friendly-ish...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implemented lazyloading of images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no-js collapse of albums&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;handles no-js okay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it only loads 800kb to start, instead of 20mb+ yay&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-05-08:/posts/2018-05-08-gallery-update.html</guid></item><item><title>Sometimes I think my chronic pain is a lie, today I felt better about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I spent a couple hours picking up trash at my favorite outlook. I tried my very best to bend properly, go slow, and take care of my body. It was exhausting and I needed a nap after. Turns out, I also worked out a lot of muscles grown weak during the winter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I felt the burn. I felt all the glute, quad, hamstring muscles sore. It was a lot of muscles at once and impacted my walking pace and stair climbing noticeably. This is normal and expected. Muscles get sore when you work them out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went for a short walk and sat on the ground with a friend. In an effort to be impressive and flirt, I sat in position which were painful to me. I had taken a painkiller in preparation for this experience kinda knowing it would be ruff so in the moment, I felt okay enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours later and most of today I felt the consequences. I had a very real example of the difference between sore muscle pain, joint pain, and chronic pain. I am very happy to have had this moment. It makes me feel more validated in my experience of pain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like muscle soreness. It is a good feeling. Joint pain and chronic pain is not a good feeling. As I have said for years now "a body in motion hurts less". And today is seems more relevant than ever. Thanks body.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-25:/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</guid></item></channel></rss>