<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Power of Vulnerability</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-19-vulnerability.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/iCvmsMzlF7o'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-19:/posts/2018-02-19-vulnerability.html</guid></item><item><title>Why the Stories We Tell Ourselves Shape Us</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-17-stories-we-tell.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/hQ2XMKHsg9I'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-17:/posts/2018-02-17-stories-we-tell.html</guid></item><item><title>Where do I start?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-16-the-plan.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You're trapped. You feel you cannot get out of this hole you are so deep in. When you're down here, at the bottom, what does it take to get up? How do you begin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="breathe"&gt;Breathe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's take a look at a high level of an approach to recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desire - do you even want to recover?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore - seek out new information to help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage - actively pursue recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat - Cycle, rest, plateau, climb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know. You've heard it before. That's precisely the issue isn't it! Some of these concepts really help but sometimes we are in a resistive mood. We get stuck in a stubborn place and stand still begrudgingly. Change is hard. So read on anyway. Remind yourself of these things or learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this post focuses on DPDR, the issues are abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="where-are-you-now"&gt;Where are you now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your body, your brain is built for dissociation. We know this because you experience it. Some people struggle with anger. Others, maybe like yourself, struggle with depression. What a wonderous thing to accept the way you are rather than despise it. Try as you might, but you will never experience the other side. THIS IS OK. What a world it would be if you could change on a dime, or there wasn't an infinite possibility of humans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've been stuck in DPDR for so long your brain is super good at it. This is the fight. This is your struggle. You train your mind, body, and soul to resist a natural yet encouraged state of being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="desire-do-you-want-it"&gt;Desire - Do you want it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've got to want it. You've got to be willing to change who you think you are. You've got to push outside your comfort zone regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I am.&lt;br&gt;
I will never get out of this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe these thoughts, and you will, indeed, stay this way. Trapped by our history, it seems because I have been this for so long, I am unable to be any different. This is a fallacy! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not my DPDR, I struggle with DPDR.&lt;br&gt;
If I can overcome this, I will be awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This peeks at the heart of identity. I am something versus I have something. Let the problem be the problem. You are not the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can find the drive and commitment to engage in your own recovery you've got the most important piece down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="explore-there-is-always-something-new-to-learn"&gt;Explore - there is always something new to learn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing would be to learn a lot about habits, change, recovery, identity, shame, vulnerability. Be willing to explore any potential childhood trauma which may source this in you. Find your weak points and build your understanding. When you have the tools to repair a car it's a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every chapter of my life I've felt like I have "tried everything." Laughable. In a universe which is unlimited, can one truly say they have tried EVERYTHING? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="engage-conquer-those-fears"&gt;Engage - conquer those fears&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then engage. With the previous thoughts in mind, ACT! I know you can do it. I know you can face your fears and be caring towards yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accept the chapter you are in. You are at that critical point in the character's story where they finally say "ENOUGH!" and truly begin their quest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you begin yours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="tips-for-engagnement"&gt;Tips for engagnement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mindfulness is a super awesome help. Imagine you have three raisins. In silence, pick up one raisin. Look, touch, smell it. Put it in your mouth and chew. Don't count just chew. Don't swallow just chew. It will go down when it's ready. Follow the raisin into your stomach. Now. Pick up the next raisin and do the same thing. -- You can totally build the skill of present minded action outside of dpdr. You likely experience it in small ways already so we know you're capable of it. Now it's time you habitualize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use a stim toy. Tungsten ring which I've had almost a decade I sometimes spin on tables and watch. Kinda like a totem from inception. I watch I zone out. When it's done I come back. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The other thing is more Pavlovian. I bought a small bottle of smelly stuff. I spent a couple months imprinting positive, in the moment, connected feeling into the smell. Now, when I find myself fading I smell it to come back. It really helps. Like a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fucking go for it. I knwo you can do this. 💕&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-16:/posts/2018-02-16-the-plan.html</guid></item><item><title>Becoming code again?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-14-becoming-code.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, so in getting sucked into my old support group again, I have added responsibilities to my plate instead of removing them. Ugh. What am I doing?!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well it's not so bad. I guess it makes sense I would return despite my distance because I am alive. So how does this relate to coding?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent about three days hack and slashing some html/css/js to revitalize the website for the support group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yuck.  Yup. I am doing website work for the group again. Hopefully this time I won't be doing the bulk of the work. I'll simply be managing and inspiring. Eventually, I'll only be inspiring. LOL. Wouldn't that be nice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my efforts to engage in this again, I've had conversations about code, project management, and explored new tools to help me along the way. And guess what? I'm starting to enjoy it again? Dammit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shall see where this leads eh?.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-14:/posts/2018-02-14-becoming-code.html</guid></item><item><title>Endemic</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-14-endemic.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t have to shut my eyes 
I didn&amp;#39;t need to tell those lies
I should have been more honest
with myself

Caught staring beneath that light
Wishful thinking, I&amp;#39;ll be alright
I should have been more honest
with myself

My world may have gone a tumbling
I may have tried to end this fling
But I won&amp;#39;t stop this suffering
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-14:/posts/2018-02-14-endemic.html</guid></item><item><title>I drew some pictures for two people today</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-14-v-day-drawings.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/media/for_him.jpg" class="postimg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/media/for_her.jpg" class="postimg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-14:/posts/2018-02-14-v-day-drawings.html</guid></item><item><title>I need to get away from the internet, what can I do?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-02-what-to-do.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hate how you spend all your time in front of computer screens or on the internet wasting time? Here is a list of ideas you can peruse for inspiration. Some of these are quite unconventional. Read carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pluck all your body hair with tweezers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice moving one eye but not the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look up anatomy drawings and try to twitch all your muscles independently (Netter's atlas baby)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice character voices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn how to throat sing (proper name?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clean every little nook and cranny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take something apart and put it back together again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download Zim wiki and start your own personal wiki of your life or simply write in a journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go down memory lane and look at your old photos from 1992&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;philosophize about time, perception of time, habits around time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice and strengthen the muscles that wiggle your ears (start with extreme eye brow lifts to identify the muscles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read books! - use the library, find an e-reader with e-ink display, borrow from friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work on a puzzle if you have the flat surface area for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design tattoos for yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look through etsy for any futures hobbies you might want to get into&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;video chat with people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;re lace your shoes with a different pattern for funzies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice Taoist masturbation/sex stuff to connect with your body in new ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn to whistle in three different ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turn off all lights, get as dark as possible, and listen. Try to identify every sound you can hear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block out as much sound and light as you can, and imagine scary stuff happening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch a visualizer while you listen to music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice an instrument if you have one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write letters to people, hell even to strangers. Just put the letter in some random mail box. Write nice things, inspirational things, love things. Not to scare people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch documentaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explore things you don't understand, like maybe sexuality and gender (my faves)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch free online college lectures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you watch entertainment media, have paper ready to critique it while you watch instead of simply droning out in it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practice breathing intentionally, like, breathe real slow for two minutes, or breathe slow then fast or something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn origami&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buy a van, convert it to an RV, quit your job and become a nomad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite pass time. Conceptualize context. Understand context. Play with context. Dive your mind into the tiniest concept of molecules and focus on water, fluidity, or really explore the fabrics nearby. Zoom out to the universe level and conceptualize the galaxies, the vastness of space time, the orbital patterns if our solar system. Think of how the moon waxes and wanes, how it effects our planet, the way it illuminates the night. Think about how what you choose to think informs your understanding of reality, what your life feels like, and how you perceive others and their actions. Context is queen.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-02:/posts/2018-02-02-what-to-do.html</guid></item><item><title>Are you a failure?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-01-stand-up.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Or do you simply believe the thought that you are a failure? If you HAVE failed in the past, can you not find ways to get better so you don't fail the same way again in the future? Failure is common but failure only comes knowing you didn't try your best. If you try your best it should not be considered failing. You put your all into that. Those failures should really be lessons learned. An opportunity to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you have been given the challenge of DPDR in your lifetime. Others get cancer, or abuse, or spinal injuries, or schizophrenia, or others. You have been given the chance to overcome this in your life. It is not easy. But everyone has their thing. And if you can stand up, brush yourself off, look around, put those fists up and keep fighting, I know you will find a way to conquer these demons. To find out why you think you hate yourself and banish those thoughts. To find all the reasons you love yourself, how you are good, and how you want to get better. To learn to deserve the love you receive and feel worthy of the good things you are lucky to experience. If this is something you want, you'll have to find it yourself. You'll have to fight, be patient, and learn a lot of new things. But this is your life. Your only life. Will you take your own hand?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-01:/posts/2018-02-01-stand-up.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa is back</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-31-vanessa-back.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have Vanessa back. Things were fine. It was the belt tensioner. I should have seen this coming. I heard light squeaking in the belt the last month or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway. I got in and drove off. I parked, opened the door. But Vanessa kept beeping at me like I forgot something. I check. The lights are off, the key is out, why won't she shut up!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does she really miss me that much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems like there is a short somewhere, which is preventing the warning beep from stopping. I worry it's part of the ignition circuit. But it could be related to a jolt when the belt was first tossed. Maybe I have fried a fuse somewhere. I shall dig soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I am very happy to have Vanessa back in my arms.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-31:/posts/2018-01-31-vanessa-back.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa threw her belt twice :(</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On my way home, I felt it. The heat stopped coming out. The cold creeped in quickly. I noticed the battery light on the dash. The steering felt stiff, barely noticable at highway speeds but unmistakable. And finally, the temp gauge began to rise fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had thrown my drive belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened before. But not in the winter. I was already exhausted. But I found a place to stop and took out a spare belt and tools. Inside the engine bay I noticed the other belt wasn't severely damaged, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With great effort I put on the new belt. In the cold this took a while. I got in the cockpit. Key in, engine turning, and I felt something off. I go back to the engine bay and the new belt was off already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give up. It's too cold, I can't do more. I'm calling a tow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what why she can't hold a belt?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</guid></item><item><title>Shedding responsibility and happy about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a few years I was a pseudo leader at a support group in my area for transgender people. I was the legally responsible emissary for a couple of years. I have since left and failed to hand over responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a recent meeting and spoke with someone who I am excited about handing the reigns over to. Well, they already had them a bit. So I'm more like empowering them and validating their value by giving them responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sad, for in a way, I never truly got to exercise the value I carried for the support group before I left. In my unreality, I was always too anxious and shameful to engage in the way I could have. So I watched and prodded from a place in the back, rather than right in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired to do something of value before I leave again, I am taking on a couple of responsibilities to get the group admin stuff moving again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to let go. I am happy there are others with similar views as me. I am happy knowing I made an impact on a group I feel is absolutely vital to my community.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</guid></item><item><title>Another sick day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No vomiting this time thankfully. However right before I set out to a friend's place I felt so dizzy and nauseous I had to lie down. I did the off and on sleeping thing for about four hours. And after some food and gobs of water I began to feel better. It's 2am right now. I have to do things tomorrow. Ugh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-25:/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</guid></item><item><title>Burning memorabilia while purging</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I burnt thousands of pages. A lot with sensitive medical data I would not like floating around. Others simply records of experiences I've lived in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This being the second time burning like this, I felt more prepared for the shift in perspective afterwards. Symbolically I destroy ties to the past I used to care deeply for. I will always be an archivist. However, my urges to do so with physical things is all but extinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me to thinking about what forms of physical archival fits my new perspective on life. Here's my list so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jewelry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tattoos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Film Pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trinkets small enough to enclose a fist over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical items (tools, storage, lifestyle enhancements)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the trend is keeping clutter out of life. Using small and or practical items to impart the symbol into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am feeling it is of little use to recall all of life with great detail. Distilling key memories and placing their importance into a small or  practical item is all that is needed to remember what made you the way you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you hold tightly to the memories, the less willing you may be to change. Too much focus on the past and you will stay there. Too much focus on the future and you may never get there. The present is the most practical place to be in any given moment. Although, never leaving the present makes it very difficult to grow and change with intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love change ^_^&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-21:/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</guid></item></channel></rss>