<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Recapping my time in Boston</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-07-23-recapping.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have not been writing as much. I have seen this as a good thing lately. First time in almost ten years where writing has not been a consistent thing FOR A GOOD REASON. Other times I have faultered on writing was due to extreme depression. This time around it is because I am active, focused, and committed to the life I am living. It is a wild feeling to be this way. I am so exhausted on most days writing isn't even something I can do. Today I am writing because the weather is finally cool enough to afford me enough comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have returned to Boston, I have reconnected with my local support group, began working on repairing and prepping my new van to live in, spent time building connections with new people, worked on new projects, spent more time than I expected on my sewing project, and struggled to sleep because of the heat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found myself feeling more confident than ever. I no longer carry anxiety or shame. I experience all the other healthy things like nervouseness and guilt, but not in unhealthy ways or in extremes. This confidence has given me a lot to work with, and given me a lot of new experiences. I will admit my greatest place of nerves does come from being around cis people and people I am attracted to. I can still feel the ache of transhpobia around cis people. They are still, a form of "better" than I am. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been more driven to push through my pain. Thankfully I have painkillers now to help me do things I really want to do or must do. Because of this I have felt more empowered to push into my pain threshold and do grander things. I will take the painkillers and I will wallow in my pain afterwards. I hope I am building a resillience and forittude against this and will lead to less pain in the future. I have felt more intense pain lately, and felt discouraged lately. At htis point it is hard to tell if it is the heat not letting me recover, or the extra pushing really isn't doing me any good. Time will tell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have another 10 weeks left. Or maybe I only have 10 weeks left. Not a lot. With a lot to do. Trying to prioritize. Pick my values and focus properly. But eager to do so many things I am remiss to leave things out. What am I willing to let suffer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to have more writings of the fact on the day and sharing things I think and learn. But I have dubbed this chapter "Overload in MA", so I won't expect much writing from me. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-07-23:/posts/2019-07-23-recapping.html</guid></item><item><title>Outlive your Haters</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-07-23-self-care.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;On a short hike, a friend struggling to make it back
refused to take a break.
Self care is not a reward.
Push your limits,
And learn the difference between the two.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/6wlFFuL8wrs'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-07-23:/posts/2019-07-23-self-care.html</guid></item><item><title>The Fells Bear Tower [rise]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-07-15-rise.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2019-07-15-rise-the-fells-bear-tower-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="3-more"&gt;... +3 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt really nice watching a sunrise, and intentionally too. I went with a new friend. So rare to do this with another person. Thanks friend &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2019-07-15-rise-the-fells-bear-tower-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2019-07-15-rise-the-fells-bear-tower-3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2019-07-15-rise-the-fells-bear-tower-4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-07-15:/posts/2019-07-15-rise.html</guid></item><item><title>Fixing the new van's coolant leak</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-06-17-fixing-coolant-leak.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I totally lucked out. This coolant leak issue really concerned me. Coolant goes everywhere in the van and a leak could be minor or catastrophic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I added water to the system to fill up the resavoir. Then I got the engine hot, stopped an opened the hood to see the most obvious leak ever coming out of the hose leading in to the auxillary water pump. Yeah these vans have two water pumps because the lines are so long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the screw clamp holding the hose on almost slipped off. And because the hose was not cut perfectly straight the clamp wasn't even totally around the hose. My first attempt to reseat it failed. The second time I totally reseated it properly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put water in the resivoir again and drove. Coolant low showed up again. I checked and no leak. So the thermostat must have opened and pulled in more liquid lowering the tank. I added more water. Things seem fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the transmission is also less noisy now. I wonder if coolant was never reaching the transmission and that effects the torque converter, or if I am overthinking it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I fixed my coolant leak all by myself. Now just time to do a flush and get it all back to normal. Super pumped about it. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-06-17:/posts/2019-06-17-fixing-coolant-leak.html</guid></item><item><title>2 vans to MA...</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-06-02-driving-to-ma.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I can't get rid of Vanessa yet. I need a place to live while I get the second van rocking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a friend fly out to the new van to drive both back to MA. It was a journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was mostly exhausted and kept forcing us to stop. I felt a bit dellusional trying to stay focused. The plan was to get to the first RMV and register the new van. We got to the first one and found out this branch does not do registration. DOH. So we go to the next one only to find they don't have a printer service like other RMV locations and its already past 4pm. Dejected and beat up we decide to chill out and not fight to get it done. Instead we get dinner and pack out to the house the van will stay at while I have 2 vans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brtually long day with a disappointing ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things I felt and experienced during the drive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great acceleration, feels clean and smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suspension is awesome despite apparently being original&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Idling rough(?) concerns me, need info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rear door locking mechanism failed on me!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recorded 32.263 mpg ! while Vanessa got 26.912 mpg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can't wait to fix the TCU issues, I can live without AC, but not hot air constantly pushing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weird being in white versus red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay time to go lots to do. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-06-02:/posts/2019-06-02-driving-to-ma.html</guid></item><item><title>I bought my second van!</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-29-i-bought-a-van.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yikes. I am mostly intimidated and frightened by the whole process. But I feel fairly confident I purchased a van with much better guts than my first van. And! It grew up in South Carolina and has nearly zero rust! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2006 172k miles 140" WB 2500 High top &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows on Slider door and rear doors, power windows/locks/mirrors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I did every right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave it a solid look over taking notes. I tested everything. I took it for a test drive. I brought it to a mechanic who gave it an excellent look over. I negotiated the price. I left feeling like I was not ripped off. I think I got a deal. But definitely did not get a steal. So I am okay with the outcome I guess. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shock...&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-29:/posts/2019-05-29-i-bought-a-van.html</guid></item><item><title>Risk Therapy: What I still fear</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-26-risk-what-i-fear.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This theme of posts is really about what I fear. If I am afraid of it, doing it will feel like a risk. It is harder to se things I Am comforatable with as taking a risk. So I thought it might be a good exercise to write down what I still fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fear the exchange of value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fear losing interest in someone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fear exposing my inner truth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fear exposing contempt for others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fear being given too much power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The exchange of value&lt;/strong&gt; is hard for me. How much do I value something versus how does the other value it? This is mostly related to trying to buy a new van. How do I stick to my own idea of the value of something even if the other doesn't value it the same? Can I accept gifts of value without feeling compelled to return the favor? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Losing interest in someone&lt;/strong&gt; is a hard thing to experience. On both sides it can be painful. I specifically am generally capable of being let go. But when I let go of others it hurts me deeply. OF course I know that holding on can be more painful than letting go on time. But it is difficult to know exactly how you want to handle the situation, and what ethics to follow. And to notice your own emotions telling you interest is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exposing my inner truth&lt;/strong&gt;. Shit I hate doing it. Sadly I fear that by exposing my inner truth it will make people like me. IT feels like a different form of fear of power. My inner truth means confidence. MY inner truth means I have a life of my own. My inner truth means being more express of my preferences. Damn all that is scary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exposing contempt for others&lt;/strong&gt; always makes me feel shitty. I do not like feeling contempt. But sometimes that is how I feel. I know it is not the end of the world, but I do not have a healthy framework for dealing with this emotion when I feel it. I hope to conquer that fear soon. IT always feels ugly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fear of too much power&lt;/strong&gt; reminds me of Batman. In the Christian Bale Batman movies, Ras Al Guhl teaches Bruce he is afraid of his own power and what it can bring. I relate to this. And in turn I fear having more power than I want, and then abusing it. I do not want to abuse my power, but I do think I should be allowed to feel my power. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-26:/posts/2019-05-26-risk-what-i-fear.html</guid></item><item><title>Real Day 3 (2 years)</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-25-real-day-3.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am two years a real person (thx DPDR).  But I call it my 3rd real day, since the day I became real was so important. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day I became real I had an epic dream showing me all my traumas and triggers waiting me in a panic nearly crying. I've never had a dream like that before or since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I had a party with some of the very important people who helped me find reality in the place I last tried ending my life. The first time I've had a party for myself in over a decade (?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I am getting a tour of the Capitol building in DC. On the precipice of a new chapter thanks to medical professionals and the risks I've taken I am eager yup see where year three will take me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming real too me five years after over a decade of full-time dpdr, but a lifetime of dpdr qualities. At some point I finally found my fire to stop trying to end my life and instead start taking risks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear is the original sin, if not the only sin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must overcome your fears to be real. You must learn to take risks, be vulnerable, and aim for something in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay strong statement. But that's what got me there. Maybe this kind of thinking could help you get there too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be well. In a violent, trying world the best we can do is fight along side it. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-25:/posts/2019-05-25-real-day-3.html</guid></item><item><title>Risk Therapy: Talking with Capitol Police</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-25-risk-capitol-police.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I woke up to watch the sunrise on capitol hill. Being parked on the eastern side a lone block away from the capitol I decided to search for the right place near the building. As I began my walk I realized I would certainly come by some capitol police and I would talk with them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one I encountered was a young man standing in front of the supreme court house. I asked if he knew where good sunrise spots would be. He didn't know the area well. IT was also clear to me I had less anxiety and more will over the situation than he did. I wondered what kind of training he had and how capable he would be. If he could have that job could I? What are the requirements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving towards the capitol I found myself gawking at the immense building. While scanning its huse length I saw more bodies in gear than I expected. Since it was me and them and there were no other humans around it was a bit intimidating. I knew they were watching me and I them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I stopped at the right side of the building where a police hut was located, as well as a few officers. IT took a minute for me to muster the courage to go talk with them. But I wanted to break the ice. Maybe they knew of better spots. They didn't. But what should I expect from the average person? Whenever I spoke with more than one at a time, one always seemed to chirp up and handle the conversation. I appreciated that. Also since I was only interested in banter and maybe some advice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I felt like I got much more than that. There was something interesting about knowing they were scrupulous of me as I them. And I could be more disarming than they could of me. I knew they carried guns, had training, and if threatened would like come down on me hard. But I could hide my nature from them, being as pleasant and kind as possible to suck information from them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point I was walking the length of the building looking for the right spot. At least four officers gathered near the end with construction. I felt their eyes as I passed by, probing me for my intent. I was glancing around a lot and looking intently around, but never at them or at any doors to the building. Then I doubled back and I finally gave them a good glance. I wanted to see what they did how they looked, their stance their energy. As soon as I did one called out from rather far asking if I needed something. Instead of responding immediately I turned my path towards them and took some steps toward so I didn't have to yell the same, full well knowing it might be seen as intimidating. Pleasently, I informed them I was just looking for the best sunrise spot and all this was so fascinating to me. All the eyes of the group were on me, and we managed to mention the cooler weather and the excitement of summer before I disengaged, wishing them a well morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that I ever would or even could, but I considered for a moment what it might feel like if I myself had training. Were I capable of turning a switch and reacting to a threat with violence. I know I do not have that in me now. I have never created it. But speaking with the police charged with protecting our most important buildings really had me thinking about this. Life is violent. Violence never ceases. And were violence to visit me I would have no specific skills trained to protect me. Mostly because I think I would be willing to accept the fate and hopefully die. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-25:/posts/2019-05-25-risk-capitol-police.html</guid></item><item><title>Risk Therapy: Asking for coffee help</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-23-coffee-help.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This one I anticipated success, and felt confident about deploying it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a coffee shop bathroom there was an advertisement. It said something along the lines of "Coffee is not rocket science, and we can help you make good coffee". The ad looked like an old one as a way to prove the company has survived long. Good for them. But I felt like testing them on whether they actually would spend the time to talk about how to make a good coffee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt it important to ask because I wanted to let myself be the ignorant one in the setting. I wanted to show up with the vulnerability of "I am not good at this thing, help me be better". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully the baristas were generally ecstatic to discuss making good coffee. They weren't fully aware of the ad which I used as my ice breaker, but nonetheless thought it was a fun thing to talk about. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-23:/posts/2019-05-23-coffee-help.html</guid></item><item><title>Risk Therapy: Asking for exactly what I want</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-23-myofascial-therapy-risk.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I suck at asking for exactly what I want. Generaly my psychology says I do not deserve what I want. After all I am a disgusting tranny who is merely allowed to live for fear of imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I told my myofascial therapist exactly what I wanted him to do. But I actually failed at it. I tried to tell him, but I was not blunt enough about it. I felt myself feeling dejected internally despite acting chipper on the outside. I still got great benefit from the session but I feel like I failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a reason I was not blunt enough was because I was afriad of being let down. I wanted to ask him to do a thing he did months ago. And I fear if he did it again it would not feel as good. IF I don't ask, I can't be let down, right? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-23:/posts/2019-05-23-myofascial-therapy-risk.html</guid></item><item><title>Risk Therapy: Asking for A High Five</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-21-high-five.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a fun one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight while I driving, I encountered an intersection with construction. The street I wanted to enter had two lanes, the outer one shut down for the construction. In the median between the opposing lanes a worker stood there as the light turned green. Approaching the worker I thought of a plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excuse me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looks up and at my direction merely a few feet away&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Care for a high five?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;  he looks at me confused&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a smirk appears and he steps up to my car. &lt;strong&gt;Sure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We double high five it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a beautiful night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You too. haha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-21:/posts/2019-05-21-high-five.html</guid></item><item><title>Risk Therapy</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-05-19-risk-therapy.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking a lot about This Jia Jiang's &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.rejectiontherapy.com/blog/category/100+Days+of+Rejection"&gt;100 days of Rejection Therapy&lt;/a&gt;. Get an overview at his (&lt;a class="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-vZXgApsPCQ"&gt;TED talk video&lt;/a&gt;). OR &lt;a class="external" href="https://youtu.be/zmIeo2bZVoQ"&gt;watch a playlist of every rejection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He specifically sought rejection by coming up with requests he hoped would be rejected. I love the idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My idea is based off of it, and in some ways is exactly the same. The difference is simply the ideas I play with I hope get positive response sometimes. I am not specifically seeking the absurd or obviously rejectionable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead I am seeking moments of vulneraibility and risk which are pointed towards my own fears. I hope to really think about processing what I am afriad of and what risks I can take to push beyond them. Let's see if this lasts. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-05-19:/posts/2019-05-19-risk-therapy.html</guid></item></channel></rss>