<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Creating a css theme toggle</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-04-24-theme-toggle.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it! As you should see in the sidebar/header there is now a toggle which allows you to display a dark theme. If you have javascript enabled the site will remember your choice using a cookie. If you do not have javascript enabled the site will warn you that the choice cannot be saved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me show you how I did it. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-brief-overview-of-the-concepts"&gt;A brief overview of the concepts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize the no-js checkbox trick for changing css&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert nearly all color values into css variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set css variables using the state of the checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two major concerns with ensuring the variables stick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally, define your variables only in the theme toggle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise you must use more specific selectors to override variables for specific components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an example of both in my css which I will explain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="no-js-toggle"&gt;No-JS Toggle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My toggle is directly based off this &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.w3schools.com/howto/howto_css_switch.asp"&gt;how to at W3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, you place a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;input type="checkbox" id="chk"&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in your code. You create a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;label for="chk"&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; which acts as your button. Then using some fancy css selector trickery, you can change values based of the &lt;code&gt;:checked&lt;/code&gt; status of the checkbox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between the W3 exmaple and mine will be clear. In their example they places the checkbox &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the label. I place mine in the root and the label lives wherever I want. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="code"&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View on &lt;a class="external" href="https://codepen.io/sqmortplantic/pen/MRzjGL?editors=1100"&gt;Codepen.io&lt;/a&gt; (it has some extras to make it actually look good)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;checkbox&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;theme&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;sidebar&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;content&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nn"&gt;#theme&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class="o"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;--theme-bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;white&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nn"&gt;#theme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:checked&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;--theme-bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;black&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nc"&gt;.content&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;--theme-bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class="nn"&gt;#theme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:checked&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;.sidebar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;--bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;--theme-bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nc"&gt;.sidebar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nt"&gt;--bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;brown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nt"&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;--bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3 id="explanation"&gt;Explanation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the checkbox is selected, the selectors change the values of the variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The selectors for the theme are applied to all the siblings of the checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every element beside the checkbox has access to the variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a more specific selector to change the value of a variable already defined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows for the difference of theme-defined variables and default variables for a given component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-04-24:/posts/2019-04-24-theme-toggle.html</guid></item><item><title>I know you can find your way back in</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-04-10-you-can-do-it.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Look. I know this experience is fucking horrifying. I lived it most of my life. And for at least half of it I just wished I was dead, tried a couple times, and the only real progress I ever made in my life was when I thought "If I'm just gonna kill myself why NOT do the thing?" So I would try the thing, life would get a little better and I would stagnate again. Until eventually I found a few things that truly helped. But more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="life-is-not-hard-dealing-with-your-self-is"&gt;Life is not hard. Dealing with your self is.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was equally one of the most horrifying and relieving things I learned in my teens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is not hard. Your body is gonna stay alive and you don't have a damn choice about it. Living is the easy part. The hard part is dealing with you, your inner you, your mind, your perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take 100 people and put them all through the same experience and you get 100 different outcomes. Some might crumble, others might soar. Some might slip into depression, others might take a few days off and get back on it. It is you, your unique set of experiences, physiology, traumas, circumstance which help determine your response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-universe-is-free-to-experience-any-kind-of-all-kinds-that-it-can"&gt;The universe is free to experience any kind of all kinds that it can&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be it some anxiety plus a bad trip, or chronic dysphoria, physical injury, other other cause of this, we are the group of humans who get to experience DPDR, and thus get to overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people will experience murder in their life, or major battery, or life changing car accident, a stalker requiring moving out of state, or any number of bizarre, sad, challenging, painful experiences in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't get to choose some parts of our life. But we do get some choice in how we respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="we-get-dpdr"&gt;We get DPDR.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I got to say, after all these years, at age 29, overcoming DPDR, I get these moments of feeling like a god. I came back from THAT. And amidst all the hard days, slips, stumbles, punches I have more resolve and fortitude than I've ever had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I will carry on,&lt;br&gt;
Drifting around in the dawn always&lt;br&gt;
I will carry on&lt;br&gt;
Shadow, you can follow me  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will always have to struggle with the 20+ years of my life where I drifted amongst the waves, tumbling around believing I didn't deserve anything better. Just as someone who overcame their own trauma will always have to fight that part of their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fueling-the-fire"&gt;Fueling the fire&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important, if the only, thing you really need to find is the fire to fight this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need different fuel for it, but I Think a lot of us find it in anger. Be angry about living this way. And use that as fuel to stoke the fire of commitment to find a way back in to your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that fire gets a solid amount of fuel to burn bright and long enough to give you a taste of what could come if you take the long path it will never fully fade again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-fire"&gt;My Fire&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning I mentioned what I found. I've written about this before here and on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in brief it all began with a few thoughts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know I need to change, so why not learn how change works?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a habit of thinking this way, so how do I change habits?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am ashamed of who I am so how do I overcome shame?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will use my media consumption as a tool for exploring my own empowerment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do other people have that I don't? How can I get what they have?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-know-you-can-do-this"&gt;I know you can do this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you can find your fuel. I know your fire can turn back on. Plz never stop seeking a way back in to your life.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-04-10:/posts/2019-04-10-you-can-do-it.html</guid></item><item><title>Walking your own path</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-04-03-reflection.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If you can see your path laid out in front of you step by step, you know it is not your path. Your own path you make, with every step you take. That is why it is your path." - Joseph Campbell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to be confused with the path you envision for your self by your self. I have been reading Braving The Wilderness by Brene Brown. Predominantly it is about understanding the idea of "true belonging". In brief, it seems she concludes, as May Angelou did, that belonging is something that comes from within. Do you feel as if you belong to your self?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time I do not feel I belong to myself. When I began searching for my true self I was confronted also with repressed physical chronic pain. First beginning in my early teens, switfly became locked away as I began to be seen as a "complainer" and no one found a cause. Every year on HRT my chornic pain seems to worsen, and after years of up and down on hormones I concluded I could not live without it, but thus I must endure the pain. It is hard for me to belong to my body because of this pain which is the first obstacle I face before I can even reach dysphoria. Because of this I feel trapped. I cannot make progress on transition because of it. I would claim I am not full time even after five years of hormones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also know I am not living some other path that someone else may have laid before me. Despite my crawl I am taking my path step by step. And while I have dreams of being farther along, it is clear I have made great progress already. Hopefully coming out of this depressive chapter I will allow myself to sit in this achievement more often than I have so far this year. I accept this is my life. I accept I will not be the vision of "normalcy" I weakly clung to growing up. And I feel I have healthy expectations of what's possible for me and my life in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Brothertiger - Bottom of It

...
I&amp;#39;m trying to live in the moment 
Capture it on my mind 
But I&amp;#39;m always waiting for somethin&amp;#39; 
That&amp;#39;ll bring me a stable life

I stubbornly go through the motions 
I&amp;#39;m hanging on to life 
Gonna get down to the bottom of it 
In time

But I will carry on 
Drifting around in the dawn always 
I will carry on 
Shadow, you can follow me
...
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="bandcamp-player"&gt;
    &lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 300px; height: 420px; margin: 0 calc(50% - 150px);" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2918845448/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=de270f/tracklist=false/track=290970613/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://brothertiger.bandcamp.com/album/a-chain-of-islands-ep"&gt;A Chain of Islands EP by Brothertiger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;input id="css-checkbox" type="checkbox"&gt;
    &lt;label class="css-toggle" for="css-checkbox"&gt;
        &lt;span class="left"&gt;Show full lyrics&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="slider"&gt;&lt;span class="inner round"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;div class="show-on-toggle"&gt;
        &lt;div class="highlight"&gt;
            &lt;pre&gt;
Shadow on the floor and  
I open up my eyes  
To the sun streaks in the morning  
I don't wanna rise

Following through the door and 
I don't wanna get behind 
Can I get back to you tomorrow? 
When I feel alright 

Everything that was broken 
It all comes back in time 
Didn't always know what I wanted 
And I still can't make up my mind 

My eyes they are wide open 
I swallow all my pride 
Gonna get down to the bottom of it 
In time 

But I will carry on 
Drifting around in the dawn always 
I will carry on 
Shadow, you can follow me 

I'm trying to live in the moment 
Capture it on my mind 
But I'm always waiting for somethin' 
That'll bring me a stable life 

I stubbornly go through the motions 
I'm hanging on to life 
Gonna get down to the bottom of it 
In time 

I always say to you, 
"I'll get away from this." 
Can I get away from this? 
Before I sleep? 

I always say to you, 
"I can handle this." 
Can I handle this 
impossible dream?
            &lt;/pre&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;      
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    label.css-toggle .left { font-weight: bold; }
    input[type=checkbox]:checked + .css-toggle + .show-on-toggle { display: block; }
    .show-on-toggle { display:none; }
&lt;/style&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-04-03:/posts/2019-04-03-reflection.html</guid></item><item><title>Taking a break from searching.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-04-01-searching.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For months now my primary goal has been to try and find a new van to live in. I have seen many and missed out on a few. Now I must take a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This search has exhausted me. Given the time I have other things to take care of. Then I will ascend as the weather warms and continue my search. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this means I will start writing more. I have been depressed lately. And in excess pain. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-04-01:/posts/2019-04-01-searching.html</guid></item><item><title>My theme song</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-03-17-theme-song-recording.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="history"&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I begun writing the song shortly after I got Vanessa. It took about 9-12 months to finish it. I know I finished it before I became real. And sharing it with people definitely helped me become real. I am confident the latter half of the song came after my third trip in Vanessa where I was in Florida for a while. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ye590cFD6jc'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Vanessa &amp;amp; Luna - Keeping it real together.
Vanessa &amp;amp; Luna - No one will get in our way!

Cause we are alone now and totally free,
to be whatever we want to be,
and we know that we will survive,
cause we&amp;#39;ve got nothing to lose.

The world is a weird place.
Life is a heart beat.
People are different,
yet always the same.

Vanessa &amp;amp; Luna... We&amp;#39;re coming your way.
Vanessa &amp;amp; Luna... But don&amp;#39;t think we&amp;#39;ll stay.

Cause we&amp;#39;re on a road trip,
to figure me out.
To open my doors,
and cast away doubt.
And if we don&amp;#39;t make it,
&amp;#39;ll be alright.
Cause we chose to live life,
and put up a fight!

Vanessa &amp;amp; Luna
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-03-17:/posts/2019-03-17-theme-song-recording.html</guid></item><item><title>I am getting better at not over-explaining myself.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-03-07-explaining-yourself.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think I am learning the lesson more and more: You do not have to explain yourself to everyone. You don't need to justify your needs, your questions, your desires to every person. When I felt undeserving of everything I always felt I had to explain myself in order to appease others, to create a reason for me to be valid. But as I have been reaching out to a lot of strangers lately I have been finding myself writing out those sentences explaining myself, and then realizing they are not necessary and deleting them. It feels good. It feels good to know I care about myself more than I used to. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-03-07:/posts/2019-03-07-explaining-yourself.html</guid></item><item><title>I am without steam</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-01-09-without-steam.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am ever drifting through the days. I am tired of where I am. I am tired. I have so many things to do and I think I am nearing the end of life with Vanessa. Although every time I feel this I go on another couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not been writing much which upsets me. I have no routine other than sleeping a lot and lying down. IS this the increase in my hormones? Is it depression? Hopefully moving on to another city will help determine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OH, also I have not been to a PT in a few weeks, first time in months. Maybe this is the issue...&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-01-09:/posts/2019-01-09-without-steam.html</guid></item><item><title>A jam packed day with a little turbulence</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-30-excitement.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a wild experience. A number of things happened which trickle into tomorrow, so some of this will be about new years eve day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ancient-city-poets"&gt;Ancient City Poets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the third time I've performed here. The last time was almost a year and a half ago when I became real. This time I planned. I was going to say something vulnerable and I wrote a poem specifically because I was going to perform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a class="internal" href="{filename}2018-12-20-waves.md"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Amongst the Waves&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="internal" href="{filename}2018-07-10-sorrow.md"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sorrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with a preface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In preparing my preface I realized something. I am not bad at vulnerability. Van life taught me so much about resiliance. I am not generally capable of holding myself together. I can be vulnerable at the right time with the right people. My body may not like being vulnerable, but I know how to push through it all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt good to say those things and be that clear about it. I also grew fonder of the poem Sorrow. I really like it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a fist bump and nice words afterwards and a strange conversation outside. The morning after at a coffee shop, someone recognized me from the poetry reading and complimented me. I told him I play my violin so maybe he'll see me tonight. I got two cards because of the poetry reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="street-performing"&gt;Street performing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I setup shop in arguably on of the best spots downtown. Only ten minutes in or so and I had mad ten dollars. A drummer showed up asking when I would leave, but then asked if we could play together. I was into it. Never played with a drummer before. So I played mostly video game music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drew crowds. Fantastically, Mike Tyson's Punch Out got us the biggest applause. WHAT? Are you serious? I don't really get it. But hey, we made 37 dollars in about a half hour or so. He gave me 20. I left to rest and eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled over to my favorite spot. The end of Saint George street. It is very intimate and loads of people pass to go to the parking garages. I doubld my money there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some interesting things happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A younger woman stopped with a polaroid camera. Turns out she left the picture in my case. That was a nitfty gesture!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A woman recorded me for a moment, dropped some money and asked me to play happy birthday. I totally nailed it with double stops and thinking the words in my head.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A woman and I made nice eye contact one moment and ten seconds later she comes back to ask what I was playing. She also plays the violin but with effects pedals and performs in other settings. She is only two hours away, on my path, and willing to hang out when I get there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some girls started dancing in front of me almost celtic like. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-morning-after"&gt;The morning after&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt really good after all that success so I stopped by a local place to get drinks. I went there because I know some people who work there. I drank a bit more than I should have so when I got to the van I passed out with a light on! Couple that with a dying batter and alternator issues and the battery was dead by morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had someone hooked up to me for 30 minutes, no good. I read the voltage of my battery after and it read 0.4v haha. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am safe where I parked and a friend will hlep me tomorrow. Then I will focus on replacing the alternator geeze.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-30:/posts/2018-12-30-excitement.html</guid></item><item><title>Jackonsville Beaches Pier [rise]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-28-rise.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9-more"&gt;... +9 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-4.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-5.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-28:/posts/2018-12-28-rise.html</guid></item><item><title>Crescent Beach Park [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-25-set.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4-more"&gt;... +4 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-4.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-25:/posts/2018-12-25-set.html</guid></item><item><title>Talking with a disabled vet</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-23-kindness.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon, as I pull into a parking spot to check the squeal in my engine, an old gentleman approached on a bike wearing a military jacket. He was kind, hard to understand, and curious to help. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He openly talked about having cancer, living on a boat, being harrassed by police, and of experiences being a sniper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I listened I began thinking about an old high school thing I used to play with &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which tense are you in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past, Present, Future, we bring forth each of these into our mind, into the present. This man was obviously trapped by his mind constantly bringing the past into the present. Fill right now with all the horrors of the past. And his horrors would be devilishly hard to let go of. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's what I found myself talking with him about, letting go. How that old life is not this life. I told him of my journey some about trying to find myself and how that is the best thing in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly it got very dark when I asked him this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You had a role to play back in the military, what role do you play now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dying of cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to say much after that in the moment. I don't know the extent of his circumstance, and as much as I wanted to inspire hope of survival it didn't seem approrpiate. We hugged. A number of times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think to my character sheet. I think about why I am being the way that I am. I feel resolute in this moment. I feel connected to my purpose as designed by the confluence of my experiences and my conscious choices. It is the only way I feel strong enough to keeping moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-23:/posts/2018-12-23-kindness.html</guid></item><item><title>Jacksonville Main St. Bridge [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-21-set.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-21-set-jacksonville-main-st-bridge-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1-more"&gt;... +1 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-21-set-jacksonville-main-st-bridge-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-21:/posts/2018-12-21-set.html</guid></item><item><title>Amongst the waves</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-20-waves.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Swallow hard, breathe, now hold.
The tide is shifting and you are ready. 
Swelling, not only inside, 
your eyes are wide open this time.

Swayed not by the crash nor pulled by the tow.
For a moment lament the strength you now hold.
Not too long ago you&amp;#39;d have been swept away
as you play amongst the waves.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-20:/posts/2018-12-20-waves.html</guid></item></channel></rss>