<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>I am without steam</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-01-09-without-steam.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am ever drifting through the days. I am tired of where I am. I am tired. I have so many things to do and I think I am nearing the end of life with Vanessa. Although every time I feel this I go on another couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not been writing much which upsets me. I have no routine other than sleeping a lot and lying down. IS this the increase in my hormones? Is it depression? Hopefully moving on to another city will help determine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OH, also I have not been to a PT in a few weeks, first time in months. Maybe this is the issue...&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-01-09:/posts/2019-01-09-without-steam.html</guid></item><item><title>A jam packed day with a little turbulence</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-30-excitement.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a wild experience. A number of things happened which trickle into tomorrow, so some of this will be about new years eve day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ancient-city-poets"&gt;Ancient City Poets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the third time I've performed here. The last time was almost a year and a half ago when I became real. This time I planned. I was going to say something vulnerable and I wrote a poem specifically because I was going to perform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a class="internal" href="{filename}2018-12-20-waves.md"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Amongst the Waves&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="internal" href="{filename}2018-07-10-sorrow.md"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sorrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with a preface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In preparing my preface I realized something. I am not bad at vulnerability. Van life taught me so much about resiliance. I am not generally capable of holding myself together. I can be vulnerable at the right time with the right people. My body may not like being vulnerable, but I know how to push through it all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt good to say those things and be that clear about it. I also grew fonder of the poem Sorrow. I really like it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a fist bump and nice words afterwards and a strange conversation outside. The morning after at a coffee shop, someone recognized me from the poetry reading and complimented me. I told him I play my violin so maybe he'll see me tonight. I got two cards because of the poetry reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="street-performing"&gt;Street performing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I setup shop in arguably on of the best spots downtown. Only ten minutes in or so and I had mad ten dollars. A drummer showed up asking when I would leave, but then asked if we could play together. I was into it. Never played with a drummer before. So I played mostly video game music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drew crowds. Fantastically, Mike Tyson's Punch Out got us the biggest applause. WHAT? Are you serious? I don't really get it. But hey, we made 37 dollars in about a half hour or so. He gave me 20. I left to rest and eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled over to my favorite spot. The end of Saint George street. It is very intimate and loads of people pass to go to the parking garages. I doubld my money there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some interesting things happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A younger woman stopped with a polaroid camera. Turns out she left the picture in my case. That was a nitfty gesture!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A woman recorded me for a moment, dropped some money and asked me to play happy birthday. I totally nailed it with double stops and thinking the words in my head.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A woman and I made nice eye contact one moment and ten seconds later she comes back to ask what I was playing. She also plays the violin but with effects pedals and performs in other settings. She is only two hours away, on my path, and willing to hang out when I get there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some girls started dancing in front of me almost celtic like. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-morning-after"&gt;The morning after&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt really good after all that success so I stopped by a local place to get drinks. I went there because I know some people who work there. I drank a bit more than I should have so when I got to the van I passed out with a light on! Couple that with a dying batter and alternator issues and the battery was dead by morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had someone hooked up to me for 30 minutes, no good. I read the voltage of my battery after and it read 0.4v haha. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am safe where I parked and a friend will hlep me tomorrow. Then I will focus on replacing the alternator geeze.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-30:/posts/2018-12-30-excitement.html</guid></item><item><title>Jackonsville Beaches Pier [rise]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-28-rise.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9-more"&gt;... +9 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-4.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-5.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-28-rise-jacksonville-beaches-pier-6.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-28:/posts/2018-12-28-rise.html</guid></item><item><title>Crescent Beach Park [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-25-set.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4-more"&gt;... +4 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-4.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-25-set-crescent-beach-park-5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-25:/posts/2018-12-25-set.html</guid></item><item><title>Talking with a disabled vet</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-23-kindness.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon, as I pull into a parking spot to check the squeal in my engine, an old gentleman approached on a bike wearing a military jacket. He was kind, hard to understand, and curious to help. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He openly talked about having cancer, living on a boat, being harrassed by police, and of experiences being a sniper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I listened I began thinking about an old high school thing I used to play with &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which tense are you in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past, Present, Future, we bring forth each of these into our mind, into the present. This man was obviously trapped by his mind constantly bringing the past into the present. Fill right now with all the horrors of the past. And his horrors would be devilishly hard to let go of. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's what I found myself talking with him about, letting go. How that old life is not this life. I told him of my journey some about trying to find myself and how that is the best thing in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly it got very dark when I asked him this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You had a role to play back in the military, what role do you play now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dying of cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to say much after that in the moment. I don't know the extent of his circumstance, and as much as I wanted to inspire hope of survival it didn't seem approrpiate. We hugged. A number of times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think to my character sheet. I think about why I am being the way that I am. I feel resolute in this moment. I feel connected to my purpose as designed by the confluence of my experiences and my conscious choices. It is the only way I feel strong enough to keeping moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-23:/posts/2018-12-23-kindness.html</guid></item><item><title>Jacksonville Main St. Bridge [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-21-set.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-21-set-jacksonville-main-st-bridge-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1-more"&gt;... +1 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-21-set-jacksonville-main-st-bridge-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-21:/posts/2018-12-21-set.html</guid></item><item><title>Amongst the waves</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-20-waves.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Swallow hard, breathe, now hold.
The tide is shifting and you are ready. 
Swelling, not only inside, 
your eyes are wide open this time.

Swayed not by the crash nor pulled by the tow.
For a moment lament the strength you now hold.
Not too long ago you&amp;#39;d have been swept away
as you play amongst the waves.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-20:/posts/2018-12-20-waves.html</guid></item><item><title>Crescent Shore Park [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-19-rise.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9-more"&gt;... +9 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-4.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-5.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-6.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-7.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-8.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-9.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-19-rise-crescent-beach-shore-10.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="youtube-videos"&gt;youtube videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Clgv4era3A'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/PztK-mt_h6s'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-19:/posts/2018-12-19-rise.html</guid></item><item><title>Fort Matanzas National Park</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-12-fort-matanzas.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wow this was cool. Not only is this a strange place, they have a free boat ride over the river and a tour guide to tell you some cool stuff about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matanzas is apparantly a word for slaughters. So there is a whole region here in Florida named after slaughters. And it doesn't freak anyone out. I can't think of any English named places like "The masacre" "The Killings" "The deaths" "The Slaughters"... apparently there are some thigns like that in other countries. But how strange it is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently this little fort never had to kill anyone and succesfully shooed away all ptoential invaders. Build to protect the southern side of St Augustine from attack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nice and relaxing experience. There was also a small path to walk which is where the tree picture comes from. Gosh the nature around here is so different. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-12:/posts/2018-12-12-fort-matanzas.html</guid></item><item><title>Matanzas Inlet, ~ St Augustine [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-12-set.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-12-set-matanzas-inlet-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2-more"&gt;... +2 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-12-set-matanzas-inlet-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-12-set-matanzas-inlet-3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-12:/posts/2018-12-12-set.html</guid></item><item><title>Fort Caroline Park</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-11-fort-caroline.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I found this very interesting. Not only have they never located the actual Fort Caroline, the place is presented rather starkly. I felt a general, yup, we killed people a lot vibe which I haven't felt at other memorials/parks like this. None the less it was an interesting walk and view. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to see the counterpart fort to this one tomorrow. Fort Matanzas. Apaprently these two forts have  history together. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The French had Fort Caroline. The Spanish has Fort Matanzas. The French tried to sneak up on the spanish but failed got caught and slaughtered. lol. Fucking humans...&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-11:/posts/2018-12-11-fort-caroline.html</guid></item><item><title>Reddie Point, Jacksonville [set]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-06-set.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-06-reddie-point-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2-more"&gt;... +2 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-06-reddie-point-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/2018-12-06-reddie-point-3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-06:/posts/2018-12-06-set.html</guid></item><item><title>A wild day, and meeting new people</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-12-02-change-encounters.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I woke up and I recorded the sunrise. I am hoping to make a timelapse out of it. Hard process when you've never done it before. Of course the hardest part being settings, and not making it go fast 😝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="calling-in-the-alarm"&gt;Calling in the alarm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While watching the sunrise I heard an alarm at a building across the way. No one was dealing with it, so I called the police. I Told them about it, recorded a video of it on my phone in case it shut off by the time they got there and I watched what happened. Police showed up, walked around. Another police showed up. A firetruck showed up and left. Then after a time, someone, likely the owner, came out of the building and it was over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about how strange it was to be the person who calls it in. I made all that happen. I effected all those lives. I likely had the owner woken up to deal with it. I had to remind myself to be okay with it. IF something was truly gone awry and it could hurt people, better off me calling it in. In MA there was recently a string of home explosions due to leaky gas...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="adventure"&gt;Adventure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually setup my violin in a spot I like for its distance from the hustle. I wasn't trying to make money and I wasn't really feeling it. I was struggling to stay focused and play beautifully anyway. So I took a break. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I lay on the ground, violin in hand, staring at the sky, a man walks up and asks rather abruptly if I can play the Harry Potter theme song. I only vaguely know it, but I stood up and said I'd give it a go. HE played it, I tried to play along. This amused him. His breath, at barely 1pm was noticible so I easily softened up on my anxiety. HE and his wife and friend were out on a funday in town. After playing a few more things for them, he offered me a drink. How could I say no?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were obviously torched. The woman was not. Before drinks we had to stop and get desert waffles. Wow. Then off to the bar. There the conversation was a lot of joking, a few questions, and a bunch about Gainseville. At one point one of the men mentioned how Against Me! came from Gainseville, and how Laura Jane Grace lives in St Augustine. Hmmm.. Are they telling me something? Later, other LGBTQ things came up. Hmmm... but thankfully I got no subtle hints from anyone they knew. If they knew, they were angels about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were complimenting me on my skills in the violin, saying I could easily join a band in Gainseville if I wanted. I told them I'd need a haircut first, nodding over to the woman, for she is a hair stylist. She said she would. I go to her house tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another friend arrives and we head off to another bar where I speak exclusively with the woman. We talk about feminism, and helping, and culture, wow, rather lefty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the rain came. And I left Vanessa's fan lid open DOH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="rain"&gt;Rain&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to Vanessa as fast as I could getting drenched along the way. The inside of Vanessa had some serious wet. Thankfully I left a bag directly underneath the fan so my bed didn't get soaked. But all that hustle really took me out. Within ten minutes of me getting back to the van, I was out. For three and a half hours. Damn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of the evening trying to dry out my shoes and other items. Using my new fat magnest I hung my shoes and stuff on the ceiling and turned on the new buddy heater I got on full blast directly underneath. I hid in the front of the van while the back became a sauna. It helped a lot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="thank-you"&gt;Thank you&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universe, for giving me this opportunity. They seemed like such normal people. Healthier people. Functioning people. Despite being on a bit of a bender. Right as I was feeling sad and tired, you came and perked me up good. Thank you. Thank you man for interupting me and being extroverted enough to jump in like that.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-12-02:/posts/2018-12-02-change-encounters.html</guid></item></channel></rss>