<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vanessa threw her belt twice :(</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On my way home, I felt it. The heat stopped coming out. The cold creeped in quickly. I noticed the battery light on the dash. The steering felt stiff, barely noticable at highway speeds but unmistakable. And finally, the temp gauge began to rise fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had thrown my drive belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened before. But not in the winter. I was already exhausted. But I found a place to stop and took out a spare belt and tools. Inside the engine bay I noticed the other belt wasn't severely damaged, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With great effort I put on the new belt. In the cold this took a while. I got in the cockpit. Key in, engine turning, and I felt something off. I go back to the engine bay and the new belt was off already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give up. It's too cold, I can't do more. I'm calling a tow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what why she can't hold a belt?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</guid></item><item><title>Shedding responsibility and happy about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a few years I was a pseudo leader at a support group in my area for transgender people. I was the legally responsible emissary for a couple of years. I have since left and failed to hand over responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a recent meeting and spoke with someone who I am excited about handing the reigns over to. Well, they already had them a bit. So I'm more like empowering them and validating their value by giving them responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sad, for in a way, I never truly got to exercise the value I carried for the support group before I left. In my unreality, I was always too anxious and shameful to engage in the way I could have. So I watched and prodded from a place in the back, rather than right in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired to do something of value before I leave again, I am taking on a couple of responsibilities to get the group admin stuff moving again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to let go. I am happy there are others with similar views as me. I am happy knowing I made an impact on a group I feel is absolutely vital to my community.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-transition-team.html</guid></item><item><title>Another sick day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No vomiting this time thankfully. However right before I set out to a friend's place I felt so dizzy and nauseous I had to lie down. I did the off and on sleeping thing for about four hours. And after some food and gobs of water I began to feel better. It's 2am right now. I have to do things tomorrow. Ugh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-25:/posts/2018-01-25-another-sick-day.html</guid></item><item><title>Burning memorabilia while purging</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I burnt thousands of pages. A lot with sensitive medical data I would not like floating around. Others simply records of experiences I've lived in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This being the second time burning like this, I felt more prepared for the shift in perspective afterwards. Symbolically I destroy ties to the past I used to care deeply for. I will always be an archivist. However, my urges to do so with physical things is all but extinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me to thinking about what forms of physical archival fits my new perspective on life. Here's my list so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jewelry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tattoos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Film Pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trinkets small enough to enclose a fist over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical items (tools, storage, lifestyle enhancements)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the trend is keeping clutter out of life. Using small and or practical items to impart the symbol into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am feeling it is of little use to recall all of life with great detail. Distilling key memories and placing their importance into a small or  practical item is all that is needed to remember what made you the way you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you hold tightly to the memories, the less willing you may be to change. Too much focus on the past and you will stay there. Too much focus on the future and you may never get there. The present is the most practical place to be in any given moment. Although, never leaving the present makes it very difficult to grow and change with intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love change ^_^&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-21:/posts/2018-01-21-burning.html</guid></item><item><title>Stuck in MA for a bit.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-20-stuck.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't know what I will write during the rest of the month, but I figured I'd at least outline what the plan is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am stuck in MA for a while. Since my parents are planning to sell the house this summer, I am spending a large chunk of my time getting rid of my crap. Ripping DVDs, throwing out stuff, donating, giving away, putting up for sale, cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also putting a lot of energy into staying away from depression and depletion. It is so easy in the winter to hibernate and do nothing because of how the cold effects my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I plan to be social with people here. I've got some people I would like to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully everything goes okay, I get back on the road before February, and things keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-20:/posts/2018-01-20-stuck.html</guid></item><item><title>Life is not hard, dealing with your self is</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-15-live-is-not-hard.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Life itself is not hard. Every living creature figures out how to do it. Our body and minds are designed to keep living as long as we can. Some species have apparently survived for tens of thousands of years, and some over a million right? Life, living, not dying, is easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-against-the-world.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealing with your &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt; is hard. Why is it that two people can experience the same traumatic event but respond so differently? How can some bounce back while others stay crushed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/survived-every-day.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is to say, that life is not to blame. No outside force is going to save you, fix you. YOU ARE GOING TO FIX YOU. Because you can, and you will, because you fucking love yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/afraid-to-fail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is your life, this dark, scary, sad, horrifying, anxious, depressed, dissociated, mess of a life, why not do and try everything to find as much joy, happiness, playfulness, fun, love, light as possible? This is your only life! Make it what you will, not the result of giving in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-think-you-have-time.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All it takes is a spark, an unending flame that boils inside you to never give up, never give in, and never forget to keep pushing, to keep trying, and to explore the world and all of reality so you can find what feeds you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that spark ignites, you'll know. Once you find a way to keep that flame burning no matter how sad, depressed, anxious, or fucked up you feel, you'll know. Once you have that day, where you are down in the pits but remember, oh right, I've got this flame, this urge, this desire, this need to recovery, and take another step out, you'll know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/you-get-better.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-15:/posts/2018-01-15-live-is-not-hard.html</guid></item><item><title>Questions from after a suicide attempt</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-13-asking-questions.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was written in the midst of a partial hospitalization after a serious bout with suicidality. Never stop asking yourself questions. These questions helped bring me to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="life-is-not-hard-dealing-with-yourself-is"&gt;Life is not hard, dealing with yourself is.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billions of people have lived and died all with their own experience of life, reality. Is it that life is hard intrinsically or that your experience, your perspective, is what creates the challenges you face? Is it intrinsically difficult to alter the way you respond to the minutia of what life brings? Can we assess our attachment to certain behaviors, thoughts, reactions, and make choices regarding their relevancy? Have you ever watched someone succeed at something you fail at and wonder how they are so lucky? What causes us to respond to events the way we do? and how do you close the gap to respond desirably?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that some others do not struggle the way I do? Are my problems permanent? Which are conquerable? Which can only be managed? Can you approach your problems from many angles to determine which type your problems truly are? And how is it that others simply move forward after traumas, hardship, and problems? What do they know that you don't? Is it as simple as saying I will choose this response? What even makes an even something you will struggle with? How long does it take for you to generally get beyond the struggle and moved forward? Can you find the tools to help minimize the amount of time you struggle so you can move forward? Is this related to change and how we cope with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between your self and other selves? Is it possible to see how another responds to certain stimuli and calculate the distance between your response and theirs? How often is the distance merely a  formation of habit? Are habits all that hard to change? How often is the distance a gap in knowledge or awareness of a concept? Is it really hard to open yourself to learning something new?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dissociation-and-its-role-in-my-life"&gt;Dissociation and its role in my life.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of my memories from childhood contain dissociation. I always felt shuffled along by the whims of my kith, doing and being what they wanted me to be. This sense of always watching and always thinking led me to the conclusions I have formed and the perspective I have acquired. I have wisdom because I have never truly lived my life. My sharing is never just for my expression. I live in the windows of others and calculate language to account for them, not me. I try not to dissociate. My transition is about trying to take hold of my association. I only ever feel associated alone. I don't feel like I can ever get rid of my dissociation. What I am, what I know, has crafted such a foundation that cannot be rebuilt. My dissociation is me. Without it I would be someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="positivity"&gt;Positivity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose I have limited my dissociation some in the last three years. Before was a total haze. Proof I can make progress. But how much more do I need? I have eliminated my judgments of others. I have found my sympathy for myself. I can understand my language choices better to accurately reflect my understandings and be heard by others. I sometimes have gender euphoria! I have support from nearly all my kith. My kith appreciate what I have to offer despite my reservations of compliments. I can take compliments without them knocking me down or sounding ill-received.  I was able to participate on my first day at this program. However my engagement was nearly all removed from the actual group. I didn't shut down those that chose to talk to me. I did not panic.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-13:/posts/2018-01-13-asking-questions.html</guid></item><item><title>Sick day</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-11-sick.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A remarkable thing happened. I woke up at my mother's house the first day and felt nauseous. I threw up a couple times and spent all day in bed. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why? If this type of sick occurred in Vanessa it would have been horrifying. I am not prepared for that. I should be prepared for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I get myself back together for this week. I've got a ton of shit going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ugh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-11:/posts/2018-01-11-sick.html</guid></item><item><title>A very social month. Today I part north.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-05-a-social-month.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the last 38 days, I was social 29 of them. This is a lot for me. I have never spent so much time and energy meeting new people in my life. Van life gave me this month. Van life gave me all the growth I experienced the month of December. Oh and all the cool people I met too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights because of my openness to meeting new people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I performed in a concert!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went busking for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found a boy I was attracted to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found that sexuality doesn't have to hurt as bad as it used to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realized more confidence than I've ever had before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can now meet new people without anxiety (except cis girls, you scary yo ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel so different about what I am now. What I offer to the world. Who I am willing to be. Who I can be. So shit. Thanks Jacksonville, St Augustine, and Orlando Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never would have changed like this without Vanessa. In the face of so much change, without proximity of friends, I had to push to learn to make new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-3-vanessa"&gt;I &amp;lt;3 Vanessa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside my growth, I saw every single person I met grow too. New confidences found in every one of them. This makes me feel very good. Especially when I can have an impact on my trans sisters. Nothing makes me happier than seeing them grow, and find inner strength and happiness. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what I am now, thanks girl. I am so fucking grateful for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-cold-of-the-north"&gt;The cold of the North&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am beginning my ascent today. In six days time I shall be back in Mass enduring the insufferable hell of winter. Each day I will get colder and colder. And hopefully not depressed along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch out for some more posts. I'll have a lot of time to write this week. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-05:/posts/2018-01-05-a-social-month.html</guid></item><item><title>Integrating a CDN for image hosting part 1</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-01-cdn.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Super excited. I recently created an account at Cloudinary.com for their free account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really want to switch over to a CDN for image hosting because my git project should not host all those images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what I accomplished:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created an account which gives me enough free space to be fine for another good while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wrote a python script that allows me to parse through all my images and thumbnails and uploads them to the CDN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then I created a plugin for Pelican that parses all my files and replaces image references with the CDN domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are reading this article, then all images are being served from the CDN :D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate img upload script into build process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update .gitignore to never add the images again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove all images from the git repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whats left:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upgrade to new verion of Pelican to utilize symlink feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;update thumbnail creation script to account for symlink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure I only have one copy of image on my harddrive finally!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel very good I finally did this. It's been a long time coming. I don't think there are any other real big ticket items to do now :) OR I'm just high on pain and can't think more than the moment. Woo.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-01:/posts/2018-01-01-cdn.html</guid></item><item><title>New Years 2018</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-01-01-new-year.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This new years eve was better than any other year of my life! What I love the most is how today is today, and while I am recalling yesterday for the sake of history, I am here today and that's it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I played my violin and made $50. The weather was just nice enough to really enjoy myself. Two moments stood out to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple dressed rather nicely began taking photos in front of me while I played. Two other women watched as I played. I couldn't believe it. Here I am playing this weird music while the couple almost dances in front of me, seemingly with no clue I am transsexual. How incredibly validating! However I guess that assumes if they knew, they wouldn't take photos with me right? Sigh...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next moment was when I was packing up. A woman from the candle shop I was playing in front of came out and offered me a free candle! I was planning to say hi anyway since she came out, complimented me and gave me a dollar. We chatted for a bit. It was very nice to know my music was appreciated by at least one of the establishments I bothered with my music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I was finally ready for a second set waiting the arrival of my friend. I sat by another busker who dropped me a dollar earlier and asked if I would play with him! Exactly what I've been hoping to do. Exactly what I told my other musician friend I was going to work on! We played a few songs together and it was awesome and scary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second set went just as well. I made a total of $100. Then my friend and I got food, met up with his friends, and spent the time in a tipsy painful state barely keeping it together. It was kinda awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How am I so lucky?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-01:/posts/2018-01-01-new-year.html</guid></item><item><title>A long overdue update. The world is a weird place</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-12-26-long-overdue.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been up to so much in the last two weeks. I have hardly had time to write about it all. I will recap in this post, but I am thankful I still managed to write more than what you'll see here in a different place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I noticed was how I met so many people and told so many stories I forgot who I told what and had strange moments of deja vu and poor recollection. Everything outside of now felt so distant and unimportant. I don't fully understand what that means but it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here's what you missed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="reunion"&gt;Reunion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reconnected with the girl I met back in May. This was a very important reunion for me. During our first encounter she said to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't know what you are do you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"No and I like to keep it that way".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately after saying that I felt how sad it was. That I wanted to remain distant from what I am. This small part stuck with me the whole summer and played a big role in my progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the second night we hung out I rode her motorcycle which really fucked me up and I crashed in front of her. Embarrassing for me, but she was a sweetheart about it. I am grateful for her energy, presence, and impact on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="busking"&gt;Busking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I went to St Augustine and tried busking for the first time. Before I could go out I sat in a coffee shop and tried to get psyched up. I spoke with a younger kid about programming which boosted my confidence before heading downtown. It's saturday so free parking amok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I landed first at the end of St George st by the castle. I setup and started playing. IT was hard and cold. I made $18. Then I crashed for a bit and warmed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then wandered around looking for another spot and sat next to a guy who looked like a performer. He was. Trumpet. We spoke about busking and it made me feel quite good. I found my second spot at Treasury and Charlotte. I made almost $30 this time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so fucking proud of myself. Performing in the concert changed everything about my confidence. I am filled with joy and happiness because I can play again. I can play for me and in front of people! IT feels so fucking good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After beaming, I drove out to Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orlando"&gt;Orlando&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a whole week jammed into one. My mother had given me a week at a hotel using her timeshare for a break in the van.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first day, Sunday I met up with a girl who and chatted over coffee. She told me about a trans event later that week which I was really excited to go to. While checking in to the hotel I befriended an employee who invited me to drinks that night. She is very pretty. It was quite awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, Monday, I wake up and went to a sales presentation for timeshare stuff. A challenge for me to make sure I don't get pressured to spend money. I invited the boy at the end over for pizza which was rough. Very interesting meeting people I don't really connect with. I learn a lot about myself that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday I spent a long time on the computer and mosied over downtown for ad ate with a girl I met way back in April. She canceled however so I just went back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday I relaxed more and landed at the trans event. There I met a bunch of people, drank and ate food. One girl caught my eye and we connected. So I followed her to another bar then took her back the hotel and spent time in the jacuzzi. Such a sweetheart she offered to take me to Universal Studios on Friday! Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday I finally got to meet up with my violin inspiration. The girl I met at a violin shop who I came out to because of national coming out day. Since I knew I might see her, I pushed myself to go busking before we met up. The universe clearly wanted me to go busking. It was really nice filling in more about her from the few moments we shared almost six months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday I went to Universal with my friend. We walked around together and thoroughly enjoyed it. After she left for work I spent another four hours in the park pushing myself to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday I spent lying in bed recovering. I packed up and spent a little time with the employee I met my first day. Then I landed in St Augustine so I could busk during the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="christmas"&gt;Christmas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas Eve I woke up in downtown St Augustine determined to make some cash. I got myself out around 11am. I setup at Hypolita and Spanish street. I got real hot in the sun and made about $20. After a break I setup at Cuna and Charlotte. I made $50 in an hour! Holy shit. After another break I setup at St Geroge and Orange st. I barely played because I hurt so bad I couldn't play anoymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This crushed me so much I hobbled back to Vanessa. I made some food and lied in bed for a really long time before going to Walmart to sleep. I hurt so badly I could barely sleep. And I didn't. I woke up at 1am even after taking my meds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we're in Christmas day now. I can't sleep so I roll over to Seven Eleven to get something to drink. The employee was so nice to me. He gave me water, ice and free food. Then I crawled over to the pier at the ocean and waited for sunrise. I fell asleep again but got woken up by the same employee bearing more food for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I am up and watch the sunrise. It was beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked around trying to pawn all the extra pastries, but no one wanted them. Not surprising. Sugar pastries. Ya. Well I did have a good conversation with one of the men. He was really considerate and willing to offer advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got out busking at Cuna and St George. I was feeling pretty good buy also very vulnerable. So many people had access to my music without needing to get close. IT was a very different feel than the other spots. But I actually got plenty of money quickly. And I was having fun. Lots of eye contact and smiles. And then...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girl I messaged on OKCupid when I first got into St Augustine was standing in front of me! WHAT?! She had told me she wasn't feeling well enough to meet up in the morning so I was very surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a great time together. Coffee, walking, food. It was so cool to have such a spontaneous encounter with someone who truly captivated me. I spent the night in the parking lot of her apartment and we spent the morning together too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fin"&gt;Fin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woah right? I've been social like 21 of the last 23 days...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the streak continues with events upcoming. So eager for the future. Thank you universe. Thank you Luna for choosing to be the way you are and fighting to make it a reality. It is precisely the way I chose to be that invites such amazing experiences. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-26:/posts/2017-12-26-long-overdue.html</guid></item><item><title>St. Augustine Beach Pier [rise]</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-12-25.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/IMG_20171225_063544609.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="3-more"&gt;... +3 more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/IMG_20171225_064728922_HDR.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/IMG_20171225_065037472_HDR.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/sun/IMG_20171225_070219918_HDR.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-25:/posts/2017-12-25.html</guid></item></channel></rss>