<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sometimes I think my chronic pain is a lie, today I felt better about it</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I spent a couple hours picking up trash at my favorite outlook. I tried my very best to bend properly, go slow, and take care of my body. It was exhausting and I needed a nap after. Turns out, I also worked out a lot of muscles grown weak during the winter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I felt the burn. I felt all the glute, quad, hamstring muscles sore. It was a lot of muscles at once and impacted my walking pace and stair climbing noticeably. This is normal and expected. Muscles get sore when you work them out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went for a short walk and sat on the ground with a friend. In an effort to be impressive and flirt, I sat in position which were painful to me. I had taken a painkiller in preparation for this experience kinda knowing it would be ruff so in the moment, I felt okay enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hours later and most of today I felt the consequences. I had a very real example of the difference between sore muscle pain, joint pain, and chronic pain. I am very happy to have had this moment. It makes me feel more validated in my experience of pain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like muscle soreness. It is a good feeling. Joint pain and chronic pain is not a good feeling. As I have said for years now "a body in motion hurts less". And today is seems more relevant than ever. Thanks body.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-25:/posts/2018-04-25-different-pains.html</guid></item><item><title>Dejection in my transition</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-23-empty.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't think I have written about this nearly as much as I should. Because I have gone off and on my hormone meds many times now I feel I have fucked up my transition to a point and it is very disheartening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so let's be clear, it's really just one thing that's deeply upsetting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i-have-lost-my-boobs"&gt;I have lost my boobs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the sense that four times my boobs have grown to an acceptable size, tiny sure, but notable. Four times they have shrunk back down to almost nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This breaks my heart in ways most don't seem to understand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stop my hormone treatment when I can't stand the pain any longer. This has always happened in the winter, when my tense cold body is tearing at my joints and it's too much. So I stop taking my spiro in an effort to reduce my side effects and try to hurt less. Every time I do this, I lose my breasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couple my pain with my inability to eat normally, my depressive episodes, and it seems inevitable I'd lose them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My greatest fear is that I've "spent" all my breast growth and I will never get boobs again. Thinking about this makes me tear up every time. What if I MUST get implants in order to have boobs, which I've had before and lost several times? I don't want that reality. I really don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="so-what-can-i-do-about-it"&gt;So what can I do about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to focus again on how I can fix this problem. I've been wallowing a lot lately. Mostly because it is still cold in MA so I'm not mentally prepared to go back on my Spiro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to doctor about other chemical to suppress testosterone other than Spiro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've heard of trans women using:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finasteride&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyproterone Acetate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flutamide/Bicalutamide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lupron&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back in the day they used to "brute force" T suppressing with Estradiol Injections. But, I was on a rather large dose of injection and nothing happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am seeing my doctor in a couple weeks. I'm quite certain I will be saying to him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to seriously consider other options than Spironolactone for my anti-androgen, and if you can't, or won't, please be candid with me because I need to find someone who will. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I saw him I meekly tried to talk about this. His response was "I'll ask around" and "have you considered an orchiectomy?" After much consideration, I am not ready to move towards surgery, so no orchi for me yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i-hate-this"&gt;I hate this&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know some girls can't take HRT for health reasons, but I have been unable to find any online who have had the same issue as me. To grow and lose them many times is crushing me. I really wish I could express how devastating this is. I had real boobs that made me happy for these brief moments. And I keep fucking losing them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day someone tried to get frisky with me and as soon as they touched my chest I nearly started bawling right there. It killed the mood for me completely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not be defined by my body. I will not be defined by my body. I will not be defined by my body. 😢&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-23:/posts/2018-04-23-empty.html</guid></item><item><title>A day in the sun cleaning up</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-22-cleaning-up.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Warmth is finally coming. We had a warm day today, so I took Vanessa up to my old outlook where I did some cleaning up while basking in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cleaned Vanessa's wheels, they were so gross. I also finally finished replacing the weather stripping on the plastic cover for the air filter. It is a damn good seal now. haha. Vanessa smells way better now, and I think I can stop worrying about it. I concluded the reason she smelt bad was because I failed to put that cover on properly once and bam, smelly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spent some time picking up trash in the area. This spot has a strong place in my heart. Each chapter of my life I have memories here and I like to keep it clean. I still have a lot more to pick up, the last time I did it was a while ago. But, it made me feel good when I saw a family, and later some kids, try to sit around the areas I had already cleaned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to have something to do with no pressure and also makes me feel like I did something good. I filled 5.5 grocery bags of trash, not including the shoe and car floor mat. I bet there is another 3-5 bags left.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-22:/posts/2018-04-22-cleaning-up.html</guid></item><item><title>A moment of clarity</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-09-some-clarity.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I awoke from something awkward and awful. Half past five in the morning is a lovely time to be filled with dread and unknowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I envisioned my behavior at my last job as toxic. I wanted to be a good monkey, but I failed. Then I found my way inside the last two years. I see myself from a rather disappointed place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start and stop my medications. I feel invigorated and productive only to crash into binge watching and internet lurking. I am sociable and friendly before cowering alone. I hold hope tightly then let it spill across the bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="i-try-and-try-again-to-find-firm-ground-but-sink-every-time"&gt;I try and try again to find firm ground, but sink every time.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I a bipolar sociopath?&lt;br&gt;
A depressed emotionally detached chronic pain addict?&lt;br&gt;
A ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come across intelligent and capable. I suppose those things are true, but I mean to imply I hide my chaos very well. I position myself as this caring, empathetic, selfless soul who must help others. Any hope at living selfishly is rejected in a heartbeat. I must remain trapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should hold tightly to the fact I have only been real for a year. That's it. This sensation of connection with my life is that young. As my friend said "the rest will come". I am filling in the spaces now. Finally. And I do have proof of that. So I suppose this moment is expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="does-that-mean-i-am-getting-better-slowly"&gt;Does that mean I am getting better slowly?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt this moment will amount to any obvious change quickly. It may not even be defining. Maybe it is another step of many similar moments which I am building my recovery. Maybe by writing this down, and making sure I capture this moment in my mind by writing about it I will help ensure it gets added to the glue. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-09:/posts/2018-04-09-some-clarity.html</guid></item><item><title>What I've been up to</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-08-what-im-up-to.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I figured I would actually share what's going on, because I haven't been writing about this stuff enough. Partly because I am depressed. Partly because I don't know how I feel yet about sharing this stuff on the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been helping my mother pack up the family house. We're selling. May parents are getting divorced and everything is finally ending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have wedged myself into my support group again and trying to have an impact. Hopefully a positive one. We'll see about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two things are taking a considerable amount of my energy. And they're also things I don't really want to talk about much on the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couple in the fact that it's still way too cold for me to be comfortable and I don't do anything worth writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot wait until it gets warmer here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-08:/posts/2018-04-08-what-im-up-to.html</guid></item><item><title>Voices want to sound like robots again and so what</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-04-04-robot-voices.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Voices, whether analog or digitial are again sound like they have a robot filter on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/oTeq-3Nucc4?start=1037'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happens less in analog, but I'm starting to think it is related to how much pain I am experiencing. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-04:/posts/2018-04-04-robot-voices.html</guid></item><item><title>Living for myself</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-31-for-myself.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have felt for quite some time now that I cannot live for myself. Every time I try to figure it out I end up feeling my only choice would be to end my life. Now, almost a year into reality I am questioning again if it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to believe all my actions have some other benefactor in mind which is unlikely. I tend to claim I have no friends and suck at making them. Aside from a few people, cisgender people are a strong source of envy for me so I don't end up befriending them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who reads this drivel is likely shaking their head at my bullshit. Which is fine. I don't really care. But it does make me think about what my life is actually like. To be someone in my shoes, with my bullshit, it's a lovely show isnt't it? All I ever wanted in life was to be a barefoot prancing little wood fairy but I cannot be any of those things. So this is what I settle for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I am to survive all this I'm quite sure I will need to find a reason to live for myself. Will that day ever come?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-31:/posts/2018-03-31-for-myself.html</guid></item><item><title>hrt 4 year anniversary</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-24-four-years-hrt.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I forgot about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes me sad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My perception of hrt has changed from a hopeful uplifting positive thing to a dark torturous painful requirement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate this. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-24:/posts/2018-03-24-four-years-hrt.html</guid></item><item><title>Is this really the life I'm stuck with?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what I'm doing. I have this drive to be something of a martyr, a public figure or at least a devout public servant. All of me screams in anger about my situation while dragging my stupid life towards this goal of living with a purpose designed to serve others and not myself. I am fine with this aim. I've never expected much for my life, at least not in a real way. I had small hopes before but nothing like this. This I am because a future in this body is bleak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pain limits me from having the life I always dreamed of. I'm capable of that dream, but not with this pain. I can't simply power through the pain. My prognosis is slow decay. And while I am trying hard to be as healthy as possible I cannot change everything at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write laying in bed wondering if I will conquer this. If I will find myself in another two, five years laughing with my hands on my hips pain free and able to live the life I always dreamed of. Maybe I'm just getting one step closer to acceptance of the life I am trapped in. Pushing myself beyond limits for everyone but myself. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-15:/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</guid></item><item><title>My Transition... so far</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-12-my-transition.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven't been writing about transition specific things, and I figured I should. So here is an introduction to my transition...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-use-the-word-transsexual"&gt;I use the word transsexual&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is very important to distinguish between gender(expression) dysphoria, and body(sex) dysphoria. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expression dysphoria is about the outside, how we present ourselves to the world. Sex dysphoria is about the relationship with the body. In the cases where they seem to overlap it is even more important to determine which of these dysphoria roots the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I like to remind people, the universe is free to experience all kinds. There are some people with no sex dypshoria, some people with a little, and some with a lot. Combine that idea with expression dysphoria and we can have a huge spectrum of how people relate to their body and the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I feel my primary issue is my relationship with my body, I use the word transsexual to describe this facet of my life. Expression, while important and I want to get better at it, has not felt like the driving cause of this change in my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-hate-expression"&gt;I hate expression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But mostly because I suck at it. I wish I Was good at it, but I don't think that is my purpose in life. I still struggle with buying clothing, sharing my feelings, and generally allowing who I am to exist in the world. Thanks DPDR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try actively on a regular basis to fight this. I want to be expressive. I wish I could dance, and simply put my emotions in the world. But it's pretty fucking hard. I can't even buy clothing for myself without it being a major thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason expression is hard is because I still see myself as male mostly, in mirrors. My lack of breasts also effects my relationship with expression. Because it is so difficult to remain on my medications, I have grown and lost my breasts four times now. And they may never come back now. We'll see. It is not that I have small breasts, there is quite literally so little tissue on my body you wouldn't know I had breasts. It breaks my heart and makes me feel inadequate. I never wanted a large chest, I just wanted A chest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bleh"&gt;Bleh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to not read the narrative. It's boring and unintseresting. But I figured I'd right it down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I write a bit more about my transition. I hope it pushes me to make more progress because I don't want to remain stagnant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-narrative"&gt;My narrative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst acknowledging my chronic pain for the first time in early 2012 I began exploring my strugles with expression. After a number of months it became clear to me I was drawn to what we call "feminine" expression. In the following months I drew out the reality that, it was my body not being female which distressed me. I then knew I would need to medically transition from male to female. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first thing I was confident about was my distaste for facial hair. I started laser hair removal treatments. It took another handful of months before I could get access to hormone treatement. Spring 2014 I started Estradiol and Spironolactone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following year was mostly okay. I had quit my job and was focusing on my transition. However an unwarrented arrest and the increase of my chronic pain threw shit into the trenches. January 2015 I tried to end my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully a friend of mine was willing to take the responsibility of sending me to a hospital. Through her insistence I was registered as female, that event is a major factor in my recovery. I spent a month or so in a partial hopsitalization program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after I left that program, I worked for one more year at a startup, learning later it was a true pity hire. But I was fired because my health deteriorated and they sucked at communcation and management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that year of working, I played with my hormone dose a lot. I had attempted to end my life because I had found out my hormone treatment made my chornic pain worse. After trying all kinds of dosing options I concluded I needed to stay on hormones despite the increase of chronic pain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I left my job, I was beginning my new chapter of van life. I bought a van in late spring 2016 and spent the summer converting it to a livable space. I did a trip to Nova Scotia, a trip to the Carolinas. I spent the winter in MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 I left for Florida at the beginning of spring. It was on this trip I became real. For the summer in MA, I began injections for my estrogen. I was very happy with the switch. I felt good. I made another trip to Florida in the end of fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 I came back to MA in January. Here I shall stay until the summer and what's next I don't know. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-12:/posts/2018-03-12-my-transition.html</guid></item><item><title>I just had a glimpse of how I might gain weight</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-11-glimpes-of-fat.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I adore empathy. In turn this really means I love imagination. It is through using my imagination and wholly attempting to live it, I am able to create such empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after gourging on food, I went out for another snack. As I was eating I realized my stomach was still mostly full, but I was cramming it in anyway. But I wanted to eat. I was compelled to eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it flashed before my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hate being skinny, so I finally pushed to be a person who eats a lot so I can gain weight. I start the habit of eating more and more. Eventually I can't stop. I have been so skinny my whole life I don't really care I now have a little too much weight. And suddenly, I'm well overweight but still sitting down and eating another food because in my mind, I am so satisfied I am not underweight. I will never be underweight again. Ever. So I eat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if this means I am going to start the path of finally gaining weight. Not exactly in the extreme way this day dream played out, but still. Or is this simply a bout of fleeting imagination which will result in nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to see it as a sign, but I'd rather make it sign.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-11:/posts/2018-03-11-glimpes-of-fat.html</guid></item><item><title>Mew, give it time.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-09-mew-doodle.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Mew doodle do, I&amp;#39;m thinking of you.
I hope that today you&amp;#39;re feeling less blue.
Cause in a couple days everything will be alright!
The clouds will clear and you will jeer, 
FUCK THAT&amp;#39;S SO BRIGHT!
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-09:/posts/2018-03-09-mew-doodle.html</guid></item><item><title>Stuck in MA</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-05-stuck.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So, due to many reasons, I have decided to stay in MA until the summer hits. I know. SADFACE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the plan is to focus on selling stuff, getting my kitchen built in Vanessa, and continuing my other plans as much as I can while still in MA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do plan to bug out sometimes. I have some places in New England I should see, and hope I have the money and time to do that. But I'll have to wait until at least May to do anything like that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a shift in plans, but I shall make the best of it. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-05:/posts/2018-03-05-stuck.html</guid></item></channel></rss>