<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>I sold my old car!</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-09-sold-mazda.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, I sold the car I should have sold 2 years ago after getting Vanessa. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made out okay, not as good as I would have if I sold it right away though. Sadly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did market research. I looked at Kelly Blue Book, got the car looked at for problems, and looked at the current market for my kind of car in my kind of range. This gave me an idea of what might sell the car fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used craigslist. I first listed it higher than I thought would sell. Every week I lowered the price if I did not get a buyer. I also adjusted the language after the 2nd lowering. I added MUST GO to the title of the post. The title had loads of details, the body had plenty of information and was totally honest, and I have very nice pictures of a very clean car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I hit the sweet spot number for a listing price I got many interested buyers. In three days I have five people look at it. I received my first offer after 4 days. I worked it out with that buyer and it was gone on the 7th day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt good about being able to haggle about the number, but given my impending desperation and my fears, I accepted a number $200 lower than I had hoped. We did do a back and forth on number. I think in the end I got a very good number considering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not disappointed at all in how any of it went down. My shame was at bay. When I goofed I fixed it. When I realized I had to prep the car better I did it. If I wasn't so desparate I might have done more, haggled more, or waited for a better offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a rearview mirror air freshner in that car sicne as long as I owned it. A painted bottled with a wooden top and string to hold it in place. It was never a good air freshner. After taking it down I realized, the reason it sucked was because I never actually opened it! I was supposed to twist off the wooden top and remove a plastic plug. HAHA. Turns out to be a very refreshing smell and I am excited to add it to Vanessa. Should help with the exhaust smells. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-09:/posts/2018-09-09-sold-mazda.html</guid></item><item><title>The end of summer recap</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-07-end-of-summer.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been in Massachusetts for a very long time. In this post I think I'll recap as much as I can before I get tired of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally came back in January to deal with some medical stuff. That switfly turned into a total overall of my year, deciding I would stay to help my mother sell the family home. This shift inspired me to commit more energy to my local support group. I spent the spring focusing on the group, and trying to stay happy. Once warmer weather began pouring in I committed energy to the house. A few months of effort and the hosue was sold. Now three weeks after the house is sold, I have prepped a bunch for my departure. Only a few final thigns to button up. I should be out of here before September 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="support-group-efforts"&gt;Support Group Efforts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I became more involved in a local support group than I expected. I took on some responsibility which included holding a key to the building we use. When I left in Vanessa I did not properly pass on the responsiblity to someone else. I also started a website and new process for accepting new members. In my absense, the website went down for a time, and no one responded to incoming members for a period of almost 9 months. I was determined to setup a process to ensure this never happened again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found someone new to take on the legal responsibility and key bearing. With this new person we began devising a system to support the most important functions of the group. We decided to use Values-Based Consensus. This system seems alright and theoretically removes power from individuals greatly. We began implementing this system and bi-monthly consensus meetings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so shocked by everything that has happened. There has been conflict. There has been progress. There has been people coming in and out, producing different levels of effort and interest. What has impacted me the most, is the amount of vulnerability it takes to be a leader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to be less visible than the other primary person because I always knew my tenure would be brief. I had thought if I was less visible the group would lose less momentum and motivation when I depart. I hope this is the case. Because of this, the extent of my involvment has not been clear to everyone which also created some issues. I knew taking this one would push me with regards to my leadership skills, interpersonal skills, openness, and vulnerability. I was certainly tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What brings me some pride has been my ability to bring people together. In the few conflicts which occured, I feel I was able to help find resolution without contempt. Everyone involved has always had an interest to do good, but our own struggles and fears get in the way sometimes. I hope I never forget the impact these events have had on me, and I continue to expand on what I learned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="selling-the-house"&gt;Selling the house&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told my mom as my energy began to come back that someone needs to take ownership of selling the house. It has to be their responsibility. Well, I finally got inspired once my hormones began to settle on a proper level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I planned and executed a yard sale. We made about $1000. It was a ton of work, but got rid of a bunch of stuff. After that I scheduled a dumpster to arrive. We got rid of a lot of hazardous waste, donated a ton of stuff and cleared out the basement all within two weeks time because of my planning. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what effort that was! The day after we emptied the basement someone came in with an offer. From there it was a race to the finish. We had just over a month to finish everything. Two more dumptsers were ordered, weeks of effort cleaning, organizing, and moving took place. The very last day there was a last burst of effort to clean the insides and we made it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process taught me a lot about discipline. My owernship in the process came barely a week after my first year of being real. And in that realness there was more engagement in life than I have ever had before. I was motivated to get things done because others depended on me, because if we didn't finish I could never leave, and if I never left I would never see the people and experiences I was looking for. I had to engage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this I pushed my body more than I had in a very long time. I spent many days in a ton of pain, almost crying while working because the pain was so bad. But I had to continue. There was great satisfaction when we hit milestones. And disappointments when I had to stop because of my body. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also keen on this because if we no longer have a family home, I no longer have a "home base" I can always return to. I have used this house the last two years as a rest from vanlife. And to cope with winters when I ran out of money or something. Now this is gone. While I have plenty of people willing to support me in many ways, this conceptual change feels very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="getting-ready-to-leave"&gt;Getting ready to leave&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am about two or three weeks from leaving. I have had a lot to do. Still a lot to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a phew really big tasks ahead. Sell my old Mazda, decide what to do with Vanessa, deal with all my stuff, and finish up work at the support group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today I accepted an offer on my car and I have two parties interested in the fridge. I can't wait until they are gone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanessa was a tougher choice. I had thought it was time to get a different van. But then the reapirs I had to do were safety related. Once I did them Vanessa felt like a whole new van. So I have decided to keep her until at least March. Depending on how well she does during the winter will decide whether I keep her or not. But before I can leave I am also replacing the windshield, getting the rust repaired and hopefully adjusting the door so the contacts work again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the support group. Things seem stable enough. I have planned my outro with a gathering. More people are coming than I expected. Honestly my engagement in the group and how others seem to view me is still hard to handle. I intellectually undertsand why I am appreciated at the group and by other trans people. That does not overpower my own internal bullshit however. It is easy for me to focus on my failings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="on-being-real"&gt;On being real&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being real is huge. Everything is so different. Everything keeps getting different. I continue to get more playful. I enjoy sharing myself with others, being myself, as odd as that sounds. I feel very little shame now. Shocking really. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have reinvigorated my interest in my music visualizer again. I got winamp installed on my laptop with Wine, and currently watching it while I type. There is something deeply satisfying about having it in my life again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also feel a much deeper peace with my femininity. Or at least, the amount of femininity I need to express at the moment. I am eager to find a wardrobe I am happier wearing, and I see that getting filled with more fun and playful clothing than I have now. I am not surprised I was wrapped with so much shame growing up because, if there is such a thing, my natural femininity is on the far side of things it seems. But again, it may just be for a time I need to spill it all over the world before I settle somewhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am eager to finish getting ready. Get back on the vanlife road. To stop beating up my body on a regular basis. To find out more about who I am. And eager as all fuck for my tits to grow back 😖&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-07:/posts/2018-09-07-end-of-summer.html</guid></item><item><title>Kitchen building, day 1</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-08-25-kitchen-day-1.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am finally building a kitchen unit in my van!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to do a fun thing and put the stove in a drawer. This way I don't ruin my countertop and space with a dumb looking thing. I am using an old large stainless steel mixing bowl for my sink. Because my mom is donating her old RV fridge to me, the unit is going to look odd, but that's okay. Free stuff and really cheap materials = good to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures from the first day, and the sketchup design we slapped together. The trick part is going to be securing the unit to the inside. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-08-25:/posts/2018-08-25-kitchen-day-1.html</guid></item><item><title>I am free!</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-08-22-freedom.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The house sale is over. I am done. Hasn't fully set in, but I am very happy to get back to my own life.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-08-22:/posts/2018-08-22-freedom.html</guid></item><item><title>Stopping obsessive thoughts, another hopeful rant</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-08-15-another-hopeful-rant.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the internet, someone asked about how to stop obsessive thoughts and I went on a rant. So I figured I would share the outcome here. Sure some of it is repeat, but always a new way of saying the same thing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="find-a-focus"&gt;Find a focus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to try and find something you can deeply focus on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overactive mind is a symptom of an under utilized body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hobby, a sport, an instrument, a book. If it involves physical activity great. If it involves a fine tuned skill great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're trapped in observing mode. It's hard to get out of. But we can train. We can change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had DPDR for most of my life. At least a decade. Focused attention was the only safe place to be. That wasn't the only thing that got me out of DPDR. I still had to address my traumas. What I am suggesting is a good step. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="do-not-believe-everything-you-think"&gt;Do not believe everything you think.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not my body. I am not my thoughts. I am something more than this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DPDR, we already learn to feel disconnected from the world, and sometimes our thoughts. Or at least from certain thoughts. But it is easy, regardless of this to believe all that you are is your thoughts. That "I" is nothing more than the never ending stream of thoughts. Should you stop thinking, you would stop being. But this isn't really the case. There is more going on than your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the attempt to not believe every thought you have. Trying to sit back and be an observer to your thoughts, is part of the concept behind meditation. It is sad really, how it appears like meditation and the search for enlightenment look similar to DPDR. But they are different. Now that I am real, I can still sit back and observe my thoughts, I can let the bad thoughts roll by. I can catch myself when I get caught up in a horrible pattern that's only bringing me down. But I am now also able to live inside the stream of consciousness and let myself exist with analyzing. I can simply be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore OKAY to have all kinds of thoughts. Weird thoughts, repetitive thoughts, anxious thoughts. The more you can separate yourself from the thoughts, the more you might be able to "feel" to yourself (or interrupt your thoughts with other thoughts) that you don't want to believe those thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="narrating-your-own-life"&gt;Narrating your own life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once observing your thoughts, and no longer feeling like all you are is your thoughts, it begins to be easier to make a choice about how you narrate your own life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This speech captures much of this section - &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PhhC_N6Bm_s"&gt;This is water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have a story we believe of ourselves. A version of who we are we think we are. When you make a mistake do you tell yourself &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a piece of shit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fucked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you tell yourself &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gosh I tried hard, but next time I will do better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do we fall Bruce, so we can learn to get back up again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes happen, should I apologize for something?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hard as it seems to change our thoughts, which story we tell ourselves helps inform how we feel, and then act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is not hard. Dealing with your self is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could take a hundred people and put them through the same challenge. No two person will respond the same way. Living, staying alive, breathing, is not the hard part of life. The hard part is coping with you, dealing with you and yourself. We are our biggest critic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we can choose to change the story we believe about ourselves. I can go from thinking I am a piece of shit when I fail, to thinking failure only comes when you didn't try your best, for when you try your best it is not truly a failure and I will try again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult part of this is the beginning.  Which is where the next section comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-habits-fit-in"&gt;How habits fit in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding how habits work, are formed, and dismantled really helped me overcome a bunch of my obsessive thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is a great read or listen - &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.charlesduhigg.com/the-power-of-habit/"&gt;The Power of Habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part of changing habits in my eyes, is being able to zoom out and look at yourself, and your life from the perspective of years. I spent over a decade in DPDR. Therefore I should expect it to take me years to recover fully. Is it practical for me to think I could come back in just 6 months?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deeper you can instill this notion, that recovery is slow and not a straight line, the more likely you are to be nice to yourself when you falter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my 6 years of recovery, I have slipped back into depression 5 times. I restarted smoking 3 times. I fucked up taking my medications 4 times. I felt close to giving up many times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I zoomed out, and looked at my whole story, I realized this was how it all worked. I would make progress, but stumble, I would go slowly, because of where I started, and I could envision a future where I overcame it all. I would try to imagine what a recovered version of myself would look like 5 years from now and aim for that. And I would feel better. I would feel okay that today, I slipped up. But so long as I keep trying, going back to trying. I would get there eventually. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respect the process. Accept the process. Find any way you can to enjoy today because once you are "recovered" you'll never get to experience the joy of watching yourself recover again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope any of this is helpful my friend.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-08-15:/posts/2018-08-15-another-hopeful-rant.html</guid></item><item><title>The weight I feel</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-16-weight.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am feeling just how heavy all the important things are in life. The responsibility I could take on should I choose to. And this is a good feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am at my happiest it seems I am eager to take on the responsibilities of life. I am happy to be part of the ever expanding network of souls all interconnected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people find most of life mundane, repetitive, boring. I see every moment of life sacred, huge, and exhilerating... When I am taking my medications properly. haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously this post is about taking your meds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have proven to myself five times now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I simply cannot be happy if I am not taking my medications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a failing of mine. I am not bad for needing medications. IT just so happens the medication I need is related to a hormone disorder. So long as I take my medications I believe I can conquer every hurdle, every challenge, every fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep at it!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-16:/posts/2018-07-16-weight.html</guid></item><item><title>We have a buyer for the house!</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-15-buyer.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday last week someone put in an offer. After a quick we settled on a price. A week later we agreed on a terms sheet!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-house-is-sold"&gt;The house is sold!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are confident the new owners will have no issues with the banks, and we will do our part to vacate properly. The chances of the deal falling through are very minimal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="its-over"&gt;It's over.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packing, prepping, and emptying my childhood home is the reason for my snail pace in posting. So much energy focused on it. Combine that with my depression from winter and hormone imbalance and I didn't feel very good about life for a while. But with the summer, hormones, and success with the house I can't wait to finish up the summer. So much to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I can reflect over the first half of this year and build some solid reminders or mantras to help me stay more stable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-15:/posts/2018-07-15-buyer.html</guid></item><item><title>So I never forget</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-13-to-never-forget.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Four times now in the last four years I have gone on this horrible cycle of staying on hormones for 8 months or so, then falling off the trail. This means four times I have learned this lesson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I start hating expression, my hormones are off balance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time it was all too apparent. I saw how my body not acting female, and too low of a dose caused me to feel dissociated, hating the world and expression. It manifests as frustration at how the world is, and incessantly asking the question "why". Why am I this way, why do I like this, why can't I have a choice in the matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news, is that since I conquered injections, I have never missed a dose. What I learned during my last blood work is that my current dosage of estrogen alone is putting my levels in a good range. I don't have to take an anti-androgen. Now, if my body still doesn't do the right thing after some more time I may start Lupron, or try Progesterone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means if I can stick to sticking a needle in my leg once a week I should never have to learn this lesson again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I never go through this again. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-13:/posts/2018-07-13-to-never-forget.html</guid></item><item><title>Amanda Palmer - In My Mind</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-10-in-my-mind-palmer.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q9WZtxRWieM'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-10:/posts/2018-07-10-in-my-mind-palmer.html</guid></item><item><title>Sorrow</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-10-sorrow.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;A quiet night stares
closed eyes and everything touches you
the humid air engulfs your skin
the smell of swamp burns
it doesn&amp;#39;t have to be this way.

Another step away from them
twigs snap, bones ache
and all I ever wanted was me
not because of them
fucking in spite of them
but that&amp;#39;s never felt right either

I guess I never stopped walking
cause that sun is up and I&amp;#39;m sweating
colors everywhere trying to say
hello there, fancy a bit of joy?
hesitant, peer pressure, who cares, why not
It doesn&amp;#39;t have to be this way.

Walking still I seem to have lost the night
the comfortable, friendly, painful night
it&amp;#39;s what i wanted, right?
I got what I wanted, right?
I got me, but what good is that?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-10:/posts/2018-07-10-sorrow.html</guid></item><item><title>Help people, not ideas</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am offering some time and money to someone in my life who is heavily involved in a church. As I considered if they had enough help I played a quick story in my head where I volunteered my time on a regular basis. Yes, I am not religious and have no interest in becoming so. But I still would want to help this person out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then concluded that I like to help people and not ideas. This is a nifty little nugget I think I should hold on to. It does a good job describing me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another conversation I had described a philosopher as someone who presents ideas but does not hold to them. Someone who may put together new ideas but not be attached to them. My friend rejected this notion. I don't care who is right, only that I think I was describing me and my situation. I enjoy knowing many perspectives on the same issue so I can help people, not promote a specific idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say I don't have my own feelings on issues, but that my general approach is to engage with people on their terms not against my own beliefs or ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I can be friends with the person who voted for trump, the anarchist, the socialist democrat, the non politically correct. It is why I have always seen my value in this life as a stepping stone for others. But don't follow me. I am not trying to make a value judgement on my way of life. I wouldn't recommend other people live like me or think like me. I am not very good at taking care of myself. I put everyone else before me. I struggle to understand who I am, what I want, what I like, and where I want to go. I expect and practically seek solitude. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think this phrase, I help people, not ideas, is a solid phrase to help others understand why I am the way I am. And apparently I am writing about it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-07:/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</guid></item><item><title>A year of realness: thoughts for long term sufferers of DPDR</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After 29 years of life I finally became real. In my one year of realness I have changed significantly, some ways desirable, many ways I'm still horrified of. I wanted to share some thoughts on how my long term depersonalization has impacted my entrance into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost I am still generally afraid to make changes of conviction in my life. My decades of unreality stripped me of my sense of self, desires, preferences. Today, when my mind tries to tell me what I'm attracted to or desire my first reaction is to retract and understand WHY I want that. Contrary to how I'm told I should behave, it feels deeply unsettling to me to make a choice unless I know it's my REAL choice. Sadly I learn over and over I can never know enough about me and the universe to fully comprehend the cause for my preferences. If your DPDR prevents you from self expression, I'd expect it to continue for some time after reality. The length I think will depend on how long you were unreal. I couldn't even buy a new pair of socks without freaking out when I was in DPDR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another consequence of my longevity in limbo seems to be a general susceptibility to ideas. I felt this in my unreality that any idea could infect me so I became rather timid about what I took in. My new sense of realness made me feel empowered to explore but I have suffered the consequences. I still have yet to form a strong enough conviction and fortitude to withstand confronting unhealthy ideas for any extended period of time. Be wary about your path. Respect the power of ideas. Learn intently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more personal issue stems from empathy. Since I had no sense of self nearly all my thoughts were directed toward others. This habit of thinking gave me some great insights into human behavior but also gave me some blind spots. As I've become more self oriented in my thoughts I've found more anger, selfishness, frustration, and pettiness. It sucks. Is it more than what the average person experiences? Will these emotions settle into the landscape and not feel so prominent over time? Regardless I feel pretty bad a lot of the times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate feeling anger but I think it's my surest sign of self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still unsure if being real is better. I spent so long in nihilism and suicidal ideation that I still don't see a way for me to have a fruitful or positive life. But know that this is not necessarily because of my DPDR experience. I am transsexual with a genetic chronic pain condition which is exacerbated by my hormone treatment. While my brain obviously operate more effectively on estrogen my body does not. This conflict makes me feel undeserving, useless, and unattractive. People fall for my personality because I hide the truth of my pain so when they later learn the reality of how I suffer they just feel bad for me instead of running away. I don't know if I wish they ran away or not. Most of the time I wish they did. I am no longer suicidal but I desperately want life to kill me. Would I be able to weather this storm easier if I hadn't had DPDR? Certainly. Was my DPDR caused by my transsexuality and chronic pain as a defense mechanism? Likely. Do I fear my life may still end at my own hand? Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are suffering from DPDR or recently found reality please look at a calendar and remind yourself how long you were unreal as you grow. I spent 9,940 days unreal. I have been real for 395 days. I have been real for only 4.1% of my life. That's it. I'm gonna be messy for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will not be a fast recovery if you spent five, ten, twenty years in DPDR. The fact that you got out is remarkable. Never forget that. Here's to hoping this post makes me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-06-23:/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</guid></item><item><title>Approved for Lupron</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a month now I have been waiting for my doctor to see if I could get my insurance to cover Lupron as my primary anti-androgen. I was told a week ago or so that I was approved and I will start taking Lupron injections soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting because Lurpon acts in either a monthly or quarterly dose. It would be very hard for me to miss my doses and fuck up my hormones again. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am also trying to not get my hopes up. I have no boobs again and what if this doesn't work again? What if the side effects are worse? What if? So I am just waiting patiently until the end of the month when I have my appointment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I am hoping it goes very poorly. But, I think that's just my dysphoric depression eating at me. And if it goes well, I will be ecstatic and happy to be girl again. I can't wait to get back on the road.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-06-21:/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</guid></item></channel></rss>