<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stopping obsessive thoughts, another hopeful rant</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-08-15-another-hopeful-rant.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the internet, someone asked about how to stop obsessive thoughts and I went on a rant. So I figured I would share the outcome here. Sure some of it is repeat, but always a new way of saying the same thing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="find-a-focus"&gt;Find a focus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to try and find something you can deeply focus on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overactive mind is a symptom of an under utilized body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hobby, a sport, an instrument, a book. If it involves physical activity great. If it involves a fine tuned skill great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're trapped in observing mode. It's hard to get out of. But we can train. We can change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had DPDR for most of my life. At least a decade. Focused attention was the only safe place to be. That wasn't the only thing that got me out of DPDR. I still had to address my traumas. What I am suggesting is a good step. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="do-not-believe-everything-you-think"&gt;Do not believe everything you think.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not my body. I am not my thoughts. I am something more than this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DPDR, we already learn to feel disconnected from the world, and sometimes our thoughts. Or at least from certain thoughts. But it is easy, regardless of this to believe all that you are is your thoughts. That "I" is nothing more than the never ending stream of thoughts. Should you stop thinking, you would stop being. But this isn't really the case. There is more going on than your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the attempt to not believe every thought you have. Trying to sit back and be an observer to your thoughts, is part of the concept behind meditation. It is sad really, how it appears like meditation and the search for enlightenment look similar to DPDR. But they are different. Now that I am real, I can still sit back and observe my thoughts, I can let the bad thoughts roll by. I can catch myself when I get caught up in a horrible pattern that's only bringing me down. But I am now also able to live inside the stream of consciousness and let myself exist with analyzing. I can simply be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore OKAY to have all kinds of thoughts. Weird thoughts, repetitive thoughts, anxious thoughts. The more you can separate yourself from the thoughts, the more you might be able to "feel" to yourself (or interrupt your thoughts with other thoughts) that you don't want to believe those thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="narrating-your-own-life"&gt;Narrating your own life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once observing your thoughts, and no longer feeling like all you are is your thoughts, it begins to be easier to make a choice about how you narrate your own life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This speech captures much of this section - &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PhhC_N6Bm_s"&gt;This is water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have a story we believe of ourselves. A version of who we are we think we are. When you make a mistake do you tell yourself &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a piece of shit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fucked up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you tell yourself &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gosh I tried hard, but next time I will do better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do we fall Bruce, so we can learn to get back up again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes happen, should I apologize for something?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hard as it seems to change our thoughts, which story we tell ourselves helps inform how we feel, and then act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is not hard. Dealing with your self is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could take a hundred people and put them through the same challenge. No two person will respond the same way. Living, staying alive, breathing, is not the hard part of life. The hard part is coping with you, dealing with you and yourself. We are our biggest critic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we can choose to change the story we believe about ourselves. I can go from thinking I am a piece of shit when I fail, to thinking failure only comes when you didn't try your best, for when you try your best it is not truly a failure and I will try again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult part of this is the beginning.  Which is where the next section comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-habits-fit-in"&gt;How habits fit in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding how habits work, are formed, and dismantled really helped me overcome a bunch of my obsessive thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is a great read or listen - &lt;a class="external" href="https://www.charlesduhigg.com/the-power-of-habit/"&gt;The Power of Habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part of changing habits in my eyes, is being able to zoom out and look at yourself, and your life from the perspective of years. I spent over a decade in DPDR. Therefore I should expect it to take me years to recover fully. Is it practical for me to think I could come back in just 6 months?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deeper you can instill this notion, that recovery is slow and not a straight line, the more likely you are to be nice to yourself when you falter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my 6 years of recovery, I have slipped back into depression 5 times. I restarted smoking 3 times. I fucked up taking my medications 4 times. I felt close to giving up many times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I zoomed out, and looked at my whole story, I realized this was how it all worked. I would make progress, but stumble, I would go slowly, because of where I started, and I could envision a future where I overcame it all. I would try to imagine what a recovered version of myself would look like 5 years from now and aim for that. And I would feel better. I would feel okay that today, I slipped up. But so long as I keep trying, going back to trying. I would get there eventually. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respect the process. Accept the process. Find any way you can to enjoy today because once you are "recovered" you'll never get to experience the joy of watching yourself recover again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope any of this is helpful my friend.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-08-15:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-08-15-another-hopeful-rant.html</guid></item><item><title>The weight I feel</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-16-weight.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am feeling just how heavy all the important things are in life. The responsibility I could take on should I choose to. And this is a good feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am at my happiest it seems I am eager to take on the responsibilities of life. I am happy to be part of the ever expanding network of souls all interconnected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people find most of life mundane, repetitive, boring. I see every moment of life sacred, huge, and exhilerating... When I am taking my medications properly. haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously this post is about taking your meds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have proven to myself five times now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I simply cannot be happy if I am not taking my medications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a failing of mine. I am not bad for needing medications. IT just so happens the medication I need is related to a hormone disorder. So long as I take my medications I believe I can conquer every hurdle, every challenge, every fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep at it!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-07-16:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-16-weight.html</guid></item><item><title>We have a buyer for the house!</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-15-buyer.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday last week someone put in an offer. After a quick we settled on a price. A week later we agreed on a terms sheet!
[sumamry end]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-house-is-sold"&gt;The house is sold!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are confident the new owners will have no issues with the banks, and we will do our part to vacate properly. The chances of the deal falling through are very minimal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="its-over"&gt;It's over.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packing, prepping, and emptying my childhood home is the reason for my snail pace in posting. So much energy focused on it. Combine that with my depression from winter and hormone imbalance and I didn't feel very good about life for a while. But with the summer, hormones, and success with the house I can't wait to finish up the summer. So much to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I can reflect over the first half of this year and build some solid reminders or mantras to help me stay more stable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-07-15:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-15-buyer.html</guid></item><item><title>So I never forget</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-13-to-never-forget.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Four times now in the last four years I have gone on this horrible cycle of staying on hormones for 8 months or so, then falling off the trail. This means four times I have learned this lesson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I start hating expression, my hormones are off balance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time it was all too apparent. I saw how my body not acting female, and too low of a dose caused me to feel dissociated, hating the world and expression. It manifests as frustration at how the world is, and incessantly asking the question "why". Why am I this way, why do I like this, why can't I have a choice in the matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news, is that since I conquered injections, I have never missed a dose. What I learned during my last blood work is that my current dosage of estrogen alone is putting my levels in a good range. I don't have to take an anti-androgen. Now, if my body still doesn't do the right thing after some more time I may start Lupron, or try Progesterone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means if I can stick to sticking a needle in my leg once a week I should never have to learn this lesson again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I never go through this again. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-07-13:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-13-to-never-forget.html</guid></item><item><title>Amanda Palmer - In My Mind</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-10-in-my-mind-palmer.html</link><description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="100%" height="100%"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q9WZtxRWieM'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-07-10:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-10-in-my-mind-palmer.html</guid></item><item><title>Sorrow</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-10-sorrow.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;A quiet night stares
closed eyes and everything touches you
the humid air engulfs your skin
the smell of swamp burns
it doesn&amp;#39;t have to be this way.

Another step away from them
twigs snap, bones ache
and all I ever wanted was me
not because of them
fucking in spite of them
but that&amp;#39;s never felt right either

I guess I never stopped walking
cause that sun is up and I&amp;#39;m sweating
colors everywhere trying to say
hello there, fancy a bit of joy?
hesitant, peer pressure, who cares, why not
It doesn&amp;#39;t have to be this way.

Walking still I seem to have lost the night
the comfortable, friendly, painful night
it&amp;#39;s what i wanted, right?
I got what I wanted, right?
I got me, but what good is that?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-07-10:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-10-sorrow.html</guid></item><item><title>Help people, not ideas</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am offering some time and money to someone in my life who is heavily involved in a church. As I considered if they had enough help I played a quick story in my head where I volunteered my time on a regular basis. Yes, I am not religious and have no interest in becoming so. But I still would want to help this person out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then concluded that I like to help people and not ideas. This is a nifty little nugget I think I should hold on to. It does a good job describing me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another conversation I had described a philosopher as someone who presents ideas but does not hold to them. Someone who may put together new ideas but not be attached to them. My friend rejected this notion. I don't care who is right, only that I think I was describing me and my situation. I enjoy knowing many perspectives on the same issue so I can help people, not promote a specific idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say I don't have my own feelings on issues, but that my general approach is to engage with people on their terms not against my own beliefs or ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I can be friends with the person who voted for trump, the anarchist, the socialist democrat, the non politically correct. It is why I have always seen my value in this life as a stepping stone for others. But don't follow me. I am not trying to make a value judgement on my way of life. I wouldn't recommend other people live like me or think like me. I am not very good at taking care of myself. I put everyone else before me. I struggle to understand who I am, what I want, what I like, and where I want to go. I expect and practically seek solitude. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think this phrase, I help people, not ideas, is a solid phrase to help others understand why I am the way I am. And apparently I am writing about it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-07-07:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-07-helping-people.html</guid></item><item><title>A year of realness: thoughts for long term sufferers of DPDR</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After 29 years of life I finally became real. In my one year of realness I have changed significantly, some ways desirable, many ways I'm still horrified of. I wanted to share some thoughts on how my long term depersonalization has impacted my entrance into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost I am still generally afraid to make changes of conviction in my life. My decades of unreality stripped me of my sense of self, desires, preferences. Today, when my mind tries to tell me what I'm attracted to or desire my first reaction is to retract and understand WHY I want that. Contrary to how I'm told I should behave, it feels deeply unsettling to me to make a choice unless I know it's my REAL choice. Sadly I learn over and over I can never know enough about me and the universe to fully comprehend the cause for my preferences. If your DPDR prevents you from self expression, I'd expect it to continue for some time after reality. The length I think will depend on how long you were unreal. I couldn't even buy a new pair of socks without freaking out when I was in DPDR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another consequence of my longevity in limbo seems to be a general susceptibility to ideas. I felt this in my unreality that any idea could infect me so I became rather timid about what I took in. My new sense of realness made me feel empowered to explore but I have suffered the consequences. I still have yet to form a strong enough conviction and fortitude to withstand confronting unhealthy ideas for any extended period of time. Be wary about your path. Respect the power of ideas. Learn intently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more personal issue stems from empathy. Since I had no sense of self nearly all my thoughts were directed toward others. This habit of thinking gave me some great insights into human behavior but also gave me some blind spots. As I've become more self oriented in my thoughts I've found more anger, selfishness, frustration, and pettiness. It sucks. Is it more than what the average person experiences? Will these emotions settle into the landscape and not feel so prominent over time? Regardless I feel pretty bad a lot of the times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate feeling anger but I think it's my surest sign of self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still unsure if being real is better. I spent so long in nihilism and suicidal ideation that I still don't see a way for me to have a fruitful or positive life. But know that this is not necessarily because of my DPDR experience. I am transsexual with a genetic chronic pain condition which is exacerbated by my hormone treatment. While my brain obviously operate more effectively on estrogen my body does not. This conflict makes me feel undeserving, useless, and unattractive. People fall for my personality because I hide the truth of my pain so when they later learn the reality of how I suffer they just feel bad for me instead of running away. I don't know if I wish they ran away or not. Most of the time I wish they did. I am no longer suicidal but I desperately want life to kill me. Would I be able to weather this storm easier if I hadn't had DPDR? Certainly. Was my DPDR caused by my transsexuality and chronic pain as a defense mechanism? Likely. Do I fear my life may still end at my own hand? Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are suffering from DPDR or recently found reality please look at a calendar and remind yourself how long you were unreal as you grow. I spent 9,940 days unreal. I have been real for 395 days. I have been real for only 4.1% of my life. That's it. I'm gonna be messy for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will not be a fast recovery if you spent five, ten, twenty years in DPDR. The fact that you got out is remarkable. Never forget that. Here's to hoping this post makes me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-06-23:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-06-23-another-year-retrospective.html</guid></item><item><title>Approved for Lupron</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a month now I have been waiting for my doctor to see if I could get my insurance to cover Lupron as my primary anti-androgen. I was told a week ago or so that I was approved and I will start taking Lupron injections soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting because Lurpon acts in either a monthly or quarterly dose. It would be very hard for me to miss my doses and fuck up my hormones again. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am also trying to not get my hopes up. I have no boobs again and what if this doesn't work again? What if the side effects are worse? What if? So I am just waiting patiently until the end of the month when I have my appointment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I am hoping it goes very poorly. But, I think that's just my dysphoric depression eating at me. And if it goes well, I will be ecstatic and happy to be girl again. I can't wait to get back on the road.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-06-21:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</guid></item><item><title>I am one year real</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-28-one-year-real.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday was the day. I had a party where I invited some people close to me to come out and play in a park by the ocean. It was easier than I expected to have them all in the same place. Unfortunately some of the people I really wish were there couldn't be because of distance. But I was happy with how many were close enough to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still feel real. I know I am real. I have the kindling to a sense of self. But the flame is still weak and I have a long way to go. I still despise and suck at self expression. What I want to express is always dictated by others and feels irrelevant to me. I still don't know who I am. And I am disgusted at the process. But I do it because I must. I am human after all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this realness I have gained a lot of new skills. I can now say no better. I can test people and ideas. I can protect myself more. I can allow myself to experience life without overwhelming empathy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is honestly hard to reflect in a meaningful way lately/right now. I am so busy trying to help my mom, trying to keep moving forward. I know that's supposed to be a good thing. It is such a strange thing however, because I spent so much time reflecting, thinking abstractly and philosophically, that to merely exist feels like folly. OR something. It's just strange in a way I used to denigrate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="one-thing-is-clear"&gt;One thing is clear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have conquered the thought habits of shame. I am more hopeful than not. I am more flexible than not. I am more open to the idea of survival than not. And that is the most important thing. That is the foundation for all my future progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-05-28:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-28-one-year-real.html</guid></item><item><title>Why must I keep trying?</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-17-wishing-for-progress.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been on the verge of wanting to make more progress in my transition. I am still trapped by so many things. I want to keep moving forward. I want to become stronger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I get right in front of one of my walls it is always the physical pain I experience that laughs at me. I can no longer tell if I want to learn how to be expressive, or if I should give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be expressive, to have gender, to be able to look at cis people without assuming something negative. But I feel my chronic pain is a never ending tunnel into all the old ways of being. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't I just accept this is my limit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fucking hate this shit. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-05-17:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-17-wishing-for-progress.html</guid></item><item><title>My experience on the victim mentality</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-15-victim-mentality.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having come from the undercarriage of social life, the depressed anxious shamed part of society I was surrounded by the victim mentality for a large part of my conscious life. I held it, the victim mentality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people are born into situations either physical or social that lends them to learn towards victim rather than say, survivor. Not everyone is so lucky. I had to build my way out of the victim mentality and it is no small feat. Almost two decades of anxiety and depression were battled, a lifetime of self shaming and fear to overcome, an amalgam of bad habits wrestled with. I spent at least fifteen years in chaos. It took me six years to hit the tipping point. &lt;strong&gt;Six years of concerted, committed, careful, effort&lt;/strong&gt; to finally overcome the victim mentality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I finally committed to recovery, I wanted help, I sometimes looked for help, but I never knew what to do with it. &lt;strong&gt;I was too ashamed, stuck in too dark a place.&lt;/strong&gt; I wasn't quite ready. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say the help you receive before you are ready has little to no impact. I disagree. While a single instance may not amount to much, a long history of people being supportive makes the process a little smoother, a little easier once you finally take hold. If my memories were filled with people who were unsupportive it might have taken an even deeper amount of effort to figure it all out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="taking-control"&gt;Taking control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know lots of people talk about how to inspire that moment where you finally take hold of your own life and never let go again. I write for myself, and mostly so I never forget the process. I really believe this archival habit of mine is a strong element to my continued success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I have always been an archivist. I journaled here and there, but never deleted, never trashed. My digital journal alone began it's journey in later 2011. I finally gained steam around early 2013 and since then I have written on 50% of all days since 2013. That's a lot of writing. A lot of self reflection. And I am proud of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a quote from the very first entry on my digital journal from October 29th 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i think i did ok today despite having played games for multiple hours. i wonder how i will curb that mental trap. in fact, right now i want to play it again. maybe get high and slam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that might be ok. i need to put in place a schedule/regiment of when/how long i can play video games. hopefully it gets less and less as time goes on and then i play no games at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proud to say that I have all but given up video games. They rarely consume my time and when they do, I am intentional about it. So maybe it took seven years but whatevs. I made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="from-a-poem-i-wrote-a-number-of-years-ago"&gt;From a poem I wrote a number of years ago:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="internal" href="vanessa-luna.life/posts/2016-05-02-lifeismoreinterestingthanthat.html"&gt;Life is more interesting than that&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impossible it seems to be understood wholly,&lt;br&gt;
To feel less alien and more human.&lt;br&gt;
Each of us orbiting in and out of relationships&lt;br&gt;
causing cataclysmic shifts in the arc of our lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you bump into someone here you are affecting not just the other person, but yourself as well. You choosing to interact does something to you however small. Every moment is sacred. Every interaction a cosmic mess and that's okay. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-05-15:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-15-victim-mentality.html</guid></item><item><title>Happy 2 years Vanessa 😍</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the love so far, the experiences, and more to come. I'm sorry you were hurt recently, please trust I will take care of you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2018-05-13:vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</guid></item></channel></rss>