<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inanis  Umbra - shadows</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pansexuality</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-12-11-attraction.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This trip has taught me a lot about who I am attracted to. What I am willing to do, and how I feel about myself. I am amazed at what I've discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I truly am a pansexual kind of human. Someone where gender does not play a significant role in who I am attracted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are still so many kinds of people I have not had experiences with, I am certain my enjoyment from physical experiences comes not from some sort of internal identity satisfaction with a type, but connecting with the human in front of me, who's trying just as I am, to be human and authentic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluntly, I am still afraid of vaginas. I am worried about envy and dysphoria. However I am getting so much better at expressing certain needs at the outset so I don't do things I really won't do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so happy to finally be understanding myself. I can't wait to see where I end up. &lt;em&gt;WHAT?!?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, so I had a sexy experience this night. And guess what... I ORGASMED. For the first time. First girl orgasm. I am elated. I can't wait for more. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-11:/s/posts/2017-12-11-attraction.html</guid></item><item><title>Let the anger flow</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-11-27-anger.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I fucking hate this life. I suck at being a friend to the healthy and happy. Because I have nothing to offer to others. All of my existence is focused on my recovery and staying away from the darkness. So all I have to give is hope and bullshit support. I am nothing more compelling as a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else is there to give as a friend? To all those who are mostly fine with life, or at least stay away from the existential questions of life but for a few moments here and there, I wish I knew how to befriend you. Your normality is enviable. I wish I had a sense of identity, a sense of continuity of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to be a well of windows, ever drifting through realities, always grasping for my own, which, while in sight, is never anchored. I try so deeply to have an island of my own that's worth visiting. But my island is smothered in hope-phrases, trap pits, and waterfalls of sadness. To let you see my world is to see a life ready for death. Patiently completing her bucket list so she can tell everyone "See! I lived my fucking life, so let me die, please!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My whole life is a fucking lie. My entire life was a game of pretend. I was nothing of myself. And so, as soon as I knew I was going to break off that path and attempt for authenticity, I had my bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I fucking end it once I finish it. I hope I don't waver. It would break my heart.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-27:/s/posts/2017-11-27-anger.html</guid></item><item><title>Hollow habits</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-11-08-hollow-habits.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't know why this is a shadow. But it is. I am empty feeling. In the sense that I see just how much of my time is spent following hollow habits. Empty nothings that waste my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fighting the urge to browse the internet, watch videos, and play video games. These three things are how I escape. And shit I can dump so much time into them for no good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I'm reminded of how often the only other choice I have is reading a book. Bed ridden and trying desperately to stay sane inside my pain, what else can I do? Unfortunately all I have been reading is self-help/educational books. And I can only read so much of those at a time. Literally. Too much and I don't soak in the message. So maybe I need to figure out my fiction niche... young adult female coming of age books? Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll suck someone into a super long convo just to waste time. So I truly appreciate the connections with others. I can't wait to get better at enjoying moments with people silently, showing emotion towards people who inspire it, and expressing physicality in a whimsical way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the pain I'm feeling now is inspiring this as a shadow. Maybe I don't want to be seen as over-posting so I hide this one a bit. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-08:/s/posts/2017-11-08-hollow-habits.html</guid></item><item><title>Life is indiscriminate</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-10-26-all-kinds.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The universe is free to experience any kind of all kinds that it can. This means that all forms of death will and can occur. All forms of stories will find a way at one time or another. Some people die from old age, some of cancer, accidents, heart failure, murder, and suicide. That is okay. That is not tragic. It merely is. Trying to categorize the tragic weight of one kind of death over another should lead to the idea that all death is tragic, and therefore it is also not tragic. The choice is yours in how you see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult for me to start there and continue on. In one hand I'd like to talk about how I hope my death comes at my own hand; for any other option would seem like running from it. On the other hand, I want to write about how this very abstraction, is what allows for a person like me to exist. This empathic, loving, tranny wrapped in pain and lack of identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like admitting here, for some reason, a level of my truth I so rarely speak of. So I hope only a few choice people stumble across these shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bucket-list"&gt;bucket list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I'm going to be stuck in chronic pain my whole life I might as well stop hiding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been living off a bucket list since I began my transition. It all began here. I added a few items onto the last, a list of three basic elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;share as much as I can because people seem to value it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do as much as I can for others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experience as much of life as you can, as a girl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scary part is how close I am to finishing this list. After almost six years I have only two left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will die happy after I complete it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what will happen once this list is finished. I have not added to this list in over three years. And I am slated to complete it in the next two years. When I get there I imagine the final confluence dumping into the vast ocean. Suddenly, there will be no rails. No guide. No purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A part of me wants to set a pact that if I am still in pain by then, to end my life. Another part wants me to set no plans and see what comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will live in this responsibility forever. For that is what I am and what I must be. People say to accept yourself. That is what I am doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-26:/s/posts/2017-10-26-all-kinds.html</guid></item><item><title>The life I could have had versus this fucking thing</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-10-21-the-life-i-could-have-had.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am not shy about admitting how much envy I hold in my heart. Envy has been a best friend for my whole life. Maybe if I could let go of it, I could look forward without a mouthful of sawdust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I tried to uncover what I was hiding over five years ago, I knew, I felt how much of who I should have been was lost. All those years trapped in that hell sucked me farther and farther away from my self. I saw all my relationships built on false foundations, vapid connections, all because I could not be who I am. But now who I can never be who I should have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine, say that this is who I should have been because this is who I am. Well Fuck that. I have been stripped of identity in a way that most humans will never know. Then, when I try to discover that identity I find I must now live in more physical pain. Like the universe is saying "Nuh uh. You don't get to be happy."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still grieving. I don't know how long this is going to take. Maybe this will be the last one before I can finally let go of envy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But who am I kidding?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't ever get out of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My past, my future, is all caretaking and suffering. All the joy I feel is fabricated for the sake of others. So other people can experience a jolly person in their day. So others can feal some hope in their life. Does that make it real for me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate this life. I can't wait until it's over.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-21:/s/posts/2017-10-21-the-life-i-could-have-had.html</guid></item><item><title>A different kind of alone</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-10-14-a-different-kind-of-alone.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Something, so starkly different lines the void in my heart right now. A bleak lens focused on pitiful pats and fleeting lights. Without the false hope of rekindled flames I am now forced to face my prospects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I may write here is steeped in bias, stereotypes, and anecdotes, but so would any other perspective. The only true thing is my possibilities are endless, but most unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="who-ive-had-to-become"&gt;Who I've had to become&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew years ago, I had to leave everything if I am to hope at becoming real. I did it. I live a nomadic, vagabond, outskirts kind of life because I am not suited for any other. I rot within cultural normities. The confluence of my biggest issues has driven who I am allowed to become. I fight upstream, fuck do I fight upstream. I don't want to succumb to this raging river. But there is only so much I can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent years in a support group because my greatest social value is hope giving; a gift my kith have pulled out of me my entire life. I struggle to maintain real friendships because I cannot turn off therapist mode. I work on my gaff project as an extension of my empathic qualities: If I cannot save my own life, I hope to help save others. I live in Vanessa because I am best served as a temporary entity. I come into your life, show you light, and hopefully lift your soul. Too much of me, and you'll be crushed by my lack of identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tagline of this site has real meaning for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reflection of your experience: as moonlight is a reflection of sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personality you see from me, is a direct extension of your own. I exemplify the very things you need the most, and provide insights for you to ponder. The moon light you see in Luna is not moon light. It is sunlight reflected. Your sunlight. your sun. Put me in a large group and I shut down because I have nothing to offer a group. I seek no attention. My desire is to do as little as possible to not make it worse. I become a raw example of a wallflower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-i-might-have"&gt;What I might have&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People seem to love me, and easily. And maybe one day I may find myself healthy enough to find a person I can create a bridge with. I hope I don't destroy it before it starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I change all the time now. I'm barely real. I suppose I should celebrate intensely on my next birthday. After writing to this point I find the hope piling back into my heart. I cannot finish the original darkness which spawned this post. I don't have to, not for my sake at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cry though, for all the crappy people I will meet in my life. The people who fetishize me, objectify me, tokenize me, disrespect me and speak condescendingly to me. The people who want so badly to be the person who can love a trans person, only to leave seeking normalcy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cry for all the fear I must fight with public bathrooms, less accepting areas, attraction to any cis person, the medical industry, the police, employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cry because all I want is to be a waffle, but I will always be french toast. I want so badly to be a waffle. I wish I could rip out my past in myself and my family so I could simply be who I should have always been. I feel I can see who I would have been so clearly. But I cannot be that person. In large part because my hormone treatment has caused such intense physical pain. The burden of a constant reminder that you are forever fucking french toast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fuck"&gt;Fuck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope, I have the will to live the rest of my life so fast, so bright, so recklessly, so the universe can kill me. There's no other point to my story. All I cared about before I came out to myself was helping others. Then I spend half a decade caring for myself, only to realize I am the most hated, suicidal, minority, and transitioning brought on so much more physical pain. So I go back to caring about everyone else. This with a little more concern for myself. But fuck I want life to kill me. So fucking bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I ever kick this feeling? Is it possible for me? I reall hope not.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-14:/s/posts/2017-10-14-a-different-kind-of-alone.html</guid></item><item><title>Grieving patiently</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-10-06-grieving-patiently.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I shouldn't be writing about this here. But I am. Grieving is tough. Grief can be so consuming you forget there was life outside it. And in some ways it really is easier to stay inside grief. Never Let Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's fascinating me in this moment, is how differently I process grief now. In most cases, I see grief as a sign I am on my way to letting go. If I was not grieving, then I didn't start the process yet. I would still be stubbornly holding on to something. Unwilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fine. When I'm not fine, I am learning something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This resonates so deeply within me now. Thankfully, I truly believe in the power of this phrase. Grief, sadness, crying, over something is a sign I will most likely let go of it. Seeing it in these terms helps me find something to let go of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had to admit to an old love that I could not stop fantasizing about a possible reuinion. For a few years we have been spending time together. Since the beginning, I knew my projections were unhealthy and unfounded. But I could not figure out where they came from or why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="my-theories-were-shit-at-best"&gt;My theories were shit at best.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only after talking with them about it did I discover their root. I wanted a chance to show them what it would have been like dating the real me. Not some fucking shadow. If they could have loved me as a shadow certainly they could love me now right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact every major relationship I had, I fantasized about and revisited in this way. And in every case I ended up befriending them. Maybe partly because I really want to show them what I am like. Partly because I still really like them. Partly because their friendship helps marry my past and present in such a powerfully healing way I could not have otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="yet-here-i-am-still-crying"&gt;Yet here I am still crying.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crying over that lost chance of knowing what that relationship could have been like if I had been real. Crying for days off and on. Knowing that this is part of a process really changes grief. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting go is not fun. Letting go is hard. Letting go is the most important thing you'll ever do.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-06:/s/posts/2017-10-06-grieving-patiently.html</guid></item><item><title>On the other side</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-09-30-on-the-other-side.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In my last shadow post I wrote about doing a big thing. I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still unsure how I feel about writing this personal when it involves someone else but this isn't something I can avoid writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reconnected with an old flame from high school about three years ago. I never stopped caring about this woman. I had ended our relationship during her senior year because I didn't want to ruin her life as I saw myself slipping into madness. I still believe it was the right thing to do and it hurts every time I think about it. Above all I thought this person deserved an amazing life and I knew I couldn't be a part of that while being swallowed by shame. Shame that I am transsexual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I had to confront her about what I've experienced during this new chapter of our story. Most importantly, acknowledge the role she played in saving my life. As I had assumed, she had figured out my plans with Vanessa. The last thing I asked of her before I left this spring was to help me find a dress to wear to the dance performance I saw in April. We went shopping and found something simple, that fit well enough, and I didn't feel horrible in. At the end of that visit she gave me a hug I won't ever forget. In that moment I knew she knew and I cried as soon as it was safe to do so. Fast forward to the day of the dance performance and I'm sitting in Vanessa staring at the dress. I did not predict how important this moment would be to me. Having her association to the dress, her acceptance of me, her telling me it is okay to be in the present while simultaneously washing my past of shame and guilt, empowered me deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also needed her to tell me that there was no chance of intimacy for us. As much as I knew this, I had spun such a web of fantasy and false hope over the years because she was the last person to love me before I collapsed into nothing. Thankfully she gave me that and I feel ready and clean to let go. After all, I care much more about being in her life. It's not like I haven't befriended an old love before... Nor that I have a shortage of opportunities with future lovers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I ache somewhat tonight about being alone, with no false hopes to squelch that feeling, I am mostly overwhelmed with joy. I was able to bring forth into the world something I needed saying. I pushed into a dark territory for me without crashing under its weight and flopping about. She made me feel my presence in her life was just as valuable as hers is in mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my fantasy world I have cried into her hug for days out of gratitude, relief, joy. I am real. I am no longer suicidal. I am becoming a person again. She is a huge component to helping me get here. Thank you so fucking much. Thank you thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-09-30:/s/posts/2017-09-30-on-the-other-side.html</guid></item><item><title>Actively watching plot points of your life.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-09-29-watching-plot-points.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I am doing something that feels really big. Every reason why it is big is unique to my own story. For others, it may not be as big. Such is the nature of individual experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight I am signifying my triumph over my favorite meal. Drunken Noodles at this on place that does it really well. While there I will spin over all I have done to get here. What I truly hope to get out of this experience. All I hope to do after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching your life happen as you make it so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how others experience these events? You've decided to do something big? What feelings do you have as you get right up against it? What do you think of? Do you imagine how this event may change the course of your entire life? Maybe that's why so many people call me a romantic. Because I often think of universal time. That and I am intensely symbolic and sentimental. Duh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy these moments. For when I get to them I am often finally calm and collected. I shed my cloak of fears and step forward into something very uncomfortable. It is such a remarkable experience despite its possible negative outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see myself in this moment. I see what I am. I am reminded of why I hate my life: I hate my power. I don't want responsibility unless someone gives it to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a post eh?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-09-29:/s/posts/2017-09-29-watching-plot-points.html</guid></item><item><title>Exploring sexuality sucks</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-09-23-sexuality-questions.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I know, that I have a strong need to explore submissive tones of sexuality. And I'm thankful for the times that I get that opportunity. But I'm struggling against those questions. Where do I truly lie? What do I truly want? What can I live with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I really like being bottom. But not necessarily a passive bottom. I don't know if that means I have then be a power bottom, but I don't mind participating in these acts. But I haven't been with someone who wanted me to top in quite a while. The last time's I have weren't horrifying. So I don't often find myself attracted to men, but they are most likely to give me the dominance I often anticipate when I want to be bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very attracted to women, but is that because I like them or want to be them? In the past, wanting to be one turned into being attracted to them and initiating relationships. OR so I think? But I am less likely to find a woman who's more dom than sub. And while I think I can be switch I think we're now riding against the other big issue with my sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pain has totally changed how I can interact. Because of my fatigue, pain, and terrible joints, I am inclined to simply stay lying down. I hope the partner I have understands the consequences of sex and graciously affords me the comfort of not needing to do physically demanding work. How is this effecting what I think I can do in bed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be honest. At this moment. I hope to end up with a cis girl. Maybe that's because I would like to have kids? I do have sperm saved. Maybe it's because cis girls are the people I've mothered most in my life so it feels natural?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in likelihood, I'll end up with a boy. Maybe he'll have to be queer, non-binary, or otherwise not totally cis. Maybe we'll appreciate our own struggle to find who we are amidst such strong expectations and be happy we found it for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe, I should focus on exploring more so I can figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-09-23:/s/posts/2017-09-23-sexuality-questions.html</guid></item><item><title>Why can't I ever get the good ones?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-09-15-why-cant-i-have-the-good-ones.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been with enough people to see the difference between those who truly captivate me, and those who I am happy with for now. I think we all need both in our lives, and that's okay. But something that's frustrating me is how all the truly captivating ones slip away from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is my fault. I slink away because I am unworthy. But most of the time it happens the other way around. For one reason or another I am pushed away. I think it mostly stems from the "I am unworthy" bullshit. I know for certain at least two of mine were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It pains me because in the past, I had always expected to die, so I merely accepted their fear as truth and left. Even though I might have known full well what they were doing. Pushing me away subconsciously, or actively seeking sabotage. Since my desire for death led me to beleive I didn't want to fuck up anyone's life anyway I wouldn't pursue. And so most of the amazing people in my life are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some I came back to too late. Some we hang in the balance unsure because of distance. Some are right at my fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I am real I am damn sure going to handle things differently. No more of this passive bullshit. I am going to beat into my head that despite my transsexuality, chronic pain, and propensity for depersonalization, I am worthy of love. I am going to find at least on intimately significant relationship as a girl before I die. I promise.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-09-15:/s/posts/2017-09-15-why-cant-i-have-the-good-ones.html</guid></item><item><title>The consequences of fun; my hopes of an early death</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-09-04-swimming-consequences.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am no longer plagued by a nagging gremlin of suicide. My efforts on shame, vulnerability, and transition have cured me of that. Now I am learning to live with the where my path has taken me thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blend of my two lives has left me still hoping for death. However it's settled into some of those sayings about how to live life. "Live as if you'll die tomorrow" crap. I really am pushing myself to complete my bucket list. To follow through on my goals. Because if I am going to die there are things I need to do before then. So I do them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swam in the ocean two weeks ago for an experience I will never forget. But now I suffer the consequences. My rib cage has yet to heal and I must accept it may never. But still I go on. I push to have these experience I know will cause me deeper chronic pain. I will not sit idly by away from the life I should have lived only so I may live longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only so many things one can change about themselves. Easy it is, to fall into a new place. Doubly hard to find your way out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a duchess of dark, fleet footed fairy, truth seeker, well of windows, shadow of the moon. These things are what I must be for today. Tomorrow, I can only do so little to try and change or add. I am stuck in these roots with direction as my only the choice of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these roots there is so much death seeking I cannot leave it. It cannot leave me. I want to get my shit done and die. Life will find a way. Or life will find a way for me to keep living and I will have to keep fighting this fucked up feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If death were ever to come face to face, I hope I sit back and accept it. Fighting it, and winning, would make me feel even more bitter.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-09-04:/s/posts/2017-09-04-swimming-consequences.html</guid></item><item><title>Will I ever find someone I can be me with?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-08-28-relationships.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lol. I can see in this moment how others see I'm hidden and know what's inside is captivation. What I let out already is. And how lucky they feel when I open up, or if I happen to feel something strong for you. I can see some of the ways I'm different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think something that's always bothered me is the disproportionate number of people who like me versus me liking them. And I mean romantically/sexually. Few people have captured my heart.I don't even know what it takes to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this normal? What percentile am I in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not withstanding that the people I immediately connect with scare the crap out of me. And it's always girls. Gotta love the whole "do I like her or want to be her" thread of being a trans woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope for now is that being in Vanessa will bring me forward in the directions I want. But recently I've been worried it isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bucket list item:&lt;/strong&gt; Have a emotionally and physically significant relationship with another human&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-08-28:/s/posts/2017-08-28-relationships.html</guid></item></channel></rss>