<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inanis  Umbra - shadows</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>grieving over and over</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-04-07-grief.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't know how I am going to make it. I don't know why I even should. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seriously want to know when engough is enough. When have I tried long and hard enough? How many will scoff at my weakness? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not want to live life with my body like this. And I am mentally unable yet to take care of my body in others ways. I can't eat regularly, sleep or bathe, or take my meds regularly. The fucking self defeating cycle. The least everything has been issue is when I am in Vanessa, in the warmth, alone, with no one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I always going to have this dark inner narrative I try to hide from the world? Will it ever go away? Could I banish it? Could I recover so deeply it never comes back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone loves me and I have a lot to offer everyone else. Is that alone enough of a reason to keep living? Am I only feeling this way because it's cold and I'm trapped here? &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-04-07:/s/posts/2018-04-07-grief.html</guid></item><item><title>I don't know what I want.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-03-26-lack-of-personality.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've become more active in my old support group recently. I am now more vulnerable than ever as I attempt to rally people into making significant and fundamental changes so my support group can be a better place overall and for a long time. Having thse experiences now is showing me just how much of who I am is not me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there never was me, it feels. Everything I push myself towards feels like I do it to better my trans siblings. I am sure I have written about this before. It never seems to change. I have no idea how to live for myself. And I don't want to anymore. Why bother? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I am writing is because of a frustration I have. I try to talk about this with people. Online, in person, on the phone, with friends, strangers, a therapist. I never get any kind of useful support. Everyone wants to push me towards living for me, and fixing me. Which is absurd because they have no idea what it's like to not feel real for nearly your entire life, nor to have had life tell you over and over again your most valuable skill is helping other through their emotions, or to live in a world of persistent unending pain and you have to choose between less pain or significantly easing sex dysphoria with hormones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want someone to help me accept what I am and help me lean into it. I want to find a way to truly give up my self for the greater good of my trans siblings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to leave behind my desires for family, love, self fulfillment. Or rather, reinterpret their meanings. My family is my trans community. My love is for everyone. My self fulfillment is now actualizing this path of altruism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always wish I could have friends for friends sake, but that never seems to work. I don't know how to do that. The only people I care to listen to end up being those who need me. And those who have been in my life long enough know I suck at listening and helping after a while. I wish I could see what I am missing. If anything. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-26:/s/posts/2018-03-26-lack-of-personality.html</guid></item><item><title>my body, my pain</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what I'm doing. I have this drive to be something of a martyr, a public figure or at least a devout public servant. All of me screams in anger about my situation will dragging my stupid loose towards this goal of living with a purpose which serves others and not myself. I am fine with this aim. I've never expected much for my life, at least not in a real way. I had small hopes before but nothing like this. This I am because a future in this body is bleak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pain limits me from having the life I always dreamed if. I'm capable of that life. But not with this pain. I can't simply power through the pain. My prognosis is slow decay. And while I am trying hard to be as healthy as possible I cannot change everything at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write laying in bed wondering if I will conquer this. If I will find myself in another two, five years laughing with my hands on my hips pain free and able to live the life I always dreamed of. Maybe I'm just getting one step closer to acceptance of the life in trapped in. Pushing myself beyond limits for everyone but myself. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-15:/s/posts/2018-03-15-my-body-my-pain.html</guid></item><item><title>Am I living for purpose? Or as a sacrifice?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-03-09-purpose-or-martyr.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I think I've finally figured out what I've been struggling with the last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the while I feel I have always led my life with purpose. My hope of finding a way to truly and deeply help my teams siblings, and reduce their suffering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My whole life seems built for this purpose. I've been given intense empathy, intellect, and the influence of a selfless mother. My missing sense of self fostered a curiosity about why people are the way they are. These qualities in me led others to trust their emotions with me, when I began building my skill of supporting others. As I left high school, my social life crumbled. I was lost and aimless. With only myself to live for I sank deeper into anxiety and shame. Helping others was one way I slowed my descent into madness from my physical pain and dysphoria. As soon as I realized I am transsexual I knew I would have to give my life to others. This stark, yet clear, realization, that should I act selfishly and transition, I MUST give the rest of my life to a purpose. I think this is mostly inspired by the idea "be who you needed when you were younger." I then spent about three years at a support group recovering and learning to give better. Then in an act of desperation I left everything to find myself. My most selfish act yet. Knowing I would need to solve more of my problems so I could better help people I pushed myself farther again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems all of my selfish personal developments have always held the hand of knowing I need to be healthy so I can better serve others, so I can be an example, so I practice what I preach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been struggling with three relationships. The struggle is, I have no desire or need to support these three. I simply want to be connected with them. I want friendship, companionship, connection, and intimacy. But I find myself lost in them. Without the driving force of supporting someone, I don't know how to be. I feel out of place. I feel undeserving. I feel uninteresting. I feel without preference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="am-i-sacrificing-myself"&gt;Am I sacrificing myself?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am concerned I have it all wrong. I'm not living with purpose but shamefully avoiding myself in an unhealthy way. I can't even have friends for my sake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I have it all wrong? &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-09:/s/posts/2018-03-09-purpose-or-martyr.html</guid></item><item><title>What can I do if I'm done trying anymore?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-02-06-what-left.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm 6 years into recovery, 4 years on hrt. I've got so much recovery under my belt I'm seen as a poster. I pass regularly and blend in always. I recovered from lifelong DPDR and anxiety. I survived suicide. I quit my life and became nomadic. I reconnected with music and art. I quickly bond with others while being truthful. I quit smoking. I have friends and family who take care of me. On the outside my life looks good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still stuck with my chronic pain. Whole body arthritis is exhausting, especially when hrt makes it worse. My never sense of identity from DPDR has made all progress on expression a bust. I've learned to cope with the pain but only by living so deeply in the moment I am unable to function in society. My empathy and lack of identity have created a great mirror. I am this example of recovery and happiness while trans because that is who I want others to have the chance to see. Underneath lies nothing. A collection of perspectives and a toolkit for Socratic reasoning. I do the bare minimum to survive so I can go on helping others. But don't mistake it for unhealthy behaviors. Trust me if I had a self to show the world I would have done it by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished my bucket list. The one I started six years ago. I've helped more people in my lifetime than most ever will. Dedicated years to a support group and helping lift others up. Especially my trans siblings. I got to experience love as a girl. I had a successful career where my efforts largely contributed to an acquisition. I've seen many places and marveled at the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm done. I want out. What's left? Understand this is mostly about my physical health, but no small portion to dysphoria either. I can't function like this forever. But I'm stuck like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried to create values out of thin air. To find ways of holding on to life for a myriad of reasons. As it stands, the only reason I feel MY life is worth living, is to help others. It is the single most valuable currency I have, and the only purpose I can realistically fulfill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### What should I do now?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-06:/s/posts/2018-02-06-what-left.html</guid></item><item><title>Will I step up again?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-02-05-stepping-up.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a bad day. Attempting to plan my next trip, finish up tasks, all in the cold of winter. I am not doing well. I thought I was going to have this figured out by March, it will now take until maybe July. This extra three months is fucking with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost called someone for support. I almost broke down. But I didn't. Why? Because I can't. I can't let anyone see me express suicidality ever again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuck. It's funny how writing it down, and then reading it back jolts me. If my family or close friends ever read this they would be horrified. I hate how I will effect them all should I ever end up dying.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-05:/s/posts/2018-02-05-stepping-up.html</guid></item><item><title>I guess I'm not so sneaky</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-02-03-not-so-sneaky.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spent time with someone I only interacted with a few times before I began my nomadic life. While catching up I learned something I never considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, they were worried about me before I left. So, telling everyone you're going on a long trip can... trip up certain people who are aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I was doing a great job with most people hiding my true intentions. I guess I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still processing this information. It hangs me heavy, that's for sure. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-03:/s/posts/2018-02-03-not-so-sneaky.html</guid></item><item><title>Wishing to leave and hoping to stay</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-01-25-leaving-and-loving.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I want to leave this life. I really do. For all that I could be, what's left due to chronic pain is so disappointing. The people I want most to be with are people I would only hold back. I don't want to ruin someone's life by letting them get sucked in to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it appears I am finding some acceptance of this story. So long as I focus my life on supporting others I can still go on right? Fuck the cis people. All I need to know is my trans siblings are closer to happy than yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I want to figure it out. I want to find a way to live without suicide. I want to have people in my life on a regular basis. I want to feel I can contribute and make someone's life undeniably better. I don't know if I want a life long partner, but I am curious to find out if I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only follow the path in front of me. And I know it is not over yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-25:/s/posts/2018-01-25-leaving-and-loving.html</guid></item><item><title>Ugh dysphoria and cis envy</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-01-18-dysphoria.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am what I am, I am who I am, and I can only change so much at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is why I generally avoid life and society altogether. I live in a van, travel, avoid as much social media as I can, and spend a lot of time searching for other trans people to meet up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I found myself in a corner of youtube that suggested these creative, feminine, singer songwriter girls. I felt like shit afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this is a problem for me. And it's likely why my whole life is designed around helping trans people. So I can fucking avoid the cissies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because when envy strikes, it's like a shortcut right to suicidality. Dysphoria comes rolling in. Flashes of lightning cascade through the valley. The moment between desperation and action feeling smaller and smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know if I will ever truly conquer this. Or if I will die once my duties fulfilled. Would it even matter either way?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-18:/s/posts/2018-01-18-dysphoria.html</guid></item><item><title>Dreaming in pain</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2018-01-02-dreaming-in-pain.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What a remarkable thing. Dreaming in pain. This never used to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking in a warm bed, my lower half aching, my shoulders crinkling, my heart at the  bottom of a pit from my dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sit again wondering when I will get this life over with. When I will finish my bucket list so I can end this. And why I seem to think I will still want to follow through with ending my life after I live through it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few short chilly days I will be driving north into the hell of winter. For at least two weeks I will be trapped, trying my hardest to not get sucked into the dark depression of frigid tense hell. And I'll need to borrow more money in order to get back south after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want this hell over with.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-01-02:/s/posts/2018-01-02-dreaming-in-pain.html</guid></item><item><title>Pansexuality</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-12-11-attraction.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This trip has taught me a lot about who I am attracted to. What I am willing to do, and how I feel about myself. I am amazed at what I've discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I truly am a pansexual kind of human. Someone where gender does not play a significant role in who I am attracted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are still so many kinds of people I have not had experiences with, I am certain my enjoyment from physical experiences comes not from some sort of internal identity satisfaction with a type, but connecting with the human in front of me, who's trying just as I am, to be human and authentic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluntly, I am still afraid of vaginas. I am worried about envy and dysphoria. However I am getting so much better at expressing certain needs at the outset so I don't do things I really won't do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so happy to finally be understanding myself. I can't wait to see where I end up. &lt;em&gt;WHAT?!?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, so I had a sexy experience this night. And guess what... I ORGASMED. For the first time. First girl orgasm. I am elated. I can't wait for more. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-12-11:/s/posts/2017-12-11-attraction.html</guid></item><item><title>Let the anger flow</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-11-27-anger.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I fucking hate this life. I suck at being a friend to the healthy and happy. Because I have nothing to offer to others. All of my existence is focused on my recovery and staying away from the darkness. So all I have to give is hope and bullshit support. I am nothing more compelling as a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else is there to give as a friend? To all those who are mostly fine with life, or at least stay away from the existential questions of life but for a few moments here and there, I wish I knew how to befriend you. Your normality is enviable. I wish I had a sense of identity, a sense of continuity of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to be a well of windows, ever drifting through realities, always grasping for my own, which, while in sight, is never anchored. I try so deeply to have an island of my own that's worth visiting. But my island is smothered in hope-phrases, trap pits, and waterfalls of sadness. To let you see my world is to see a life ready for death. Patiently completing her bucket list so she can tell everyone "See! I lived my fucking life, so let me die, please!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My whole life is a fucking lie. My entire life was a game of pretend. I was nothing of myself. And so, as soon as I knew I was going to break off that path and attempt for authenticity, I had my bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I fucking end it once I finish it. I hope I don't waver. It would break my heart.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-27:/s/posts/2017-11-27-anger.html</guid></item><item><title>Hollow habits</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/s/posts/2017-11-08-hollow-habits.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't know why this is a shadow. But it is. I am empty feeling. In the sense that I see just how much of my time is spent following hollow habits. Empty nothings that waste my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fighting the urge to browse the internet, watch videos, and play video games. These three things are how I escape. And shit I can dump so much time into them for no good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I'm reminded of how often the only other choice I have is reading a book. Bed ridden and trying desperately to stay sane inside my pain, what else can I do? Unfortunately all I have been reading is self-help/educational books. And I can only read so much of those at a time. Literally. Too much and I don't soak in the message. So maybe I need to figure out my fiction niche... young adult female coming of age books? Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll suck someone into a super long convo just to waste time. So I truly appreciate the connections with others. I can't wait to get better at enjoying moments with people silently, showing emotion towards people who inspire it, and expressing physicality in a whimsical way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the pain I'm feeling now is inspiring this as a shadow. Maybe I don't want to be seen as over-posting so I hide this one a bit. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-08:/s/posts/2017-11-08-hollow-habits.html</guid></item></channel></rss>