<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - transition</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Finding another surge of expression</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-30-clothes-makeup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is someone new I met at my group a few months ago. We finally started hanging out right before I leave and she did a wonderful thing for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She regifted me clothing that did not fit her. I've always struggled with clothing. I hated all forms of expression for so long, and I've had to force my way back into it. Even after six years of working on this shit I am still not good at clothing. I was less nervous than before when I arrived, but still timid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out much greater than I anticipated. Not only did I feel willing to try, but willing to play, and willing to let myself feel okay with the fact I was intentionally looking more femme. I guess femmephobia is still the right word for it. Also, her reactions to the clothing made me feel warm and fuzzy. I took more clothing than I thought I would. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there was the makeup. I have also struggled to get myself to do anything with makeup. Knowing this, she did a quick and simple walkthrough on my face with some makeup she was giving me. The last time I had this done was years ago all the way up in Canada. I remember so viscerally the feeling when I first looked in the mirror. I felt like a clown. I felt horrified. I felt disgust towards myself. I told my friends I felt I went from 0 - 100. They assured me it was 0 - 10. I could not believe them. That is until the husband spoke up and confirmed I looked great through his blushing embarrasement. Having a cis man struggle to hide his attraction to me knowing I am trans and he's married really struck me. The problem is totally me. Today, my reaction to the mirror was not so strong. Every minute that passed I felt more comfortable. Eventually I stopped recognizing myself and had brief moments where the person I saw was a really attractive girl with some style. Very new feeling indeed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I can find the commitment to both clothing and makeup. I want these things not to be a challenge anymore. I want to be unafraid and free to be anything. Keep it coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/chronograph/with-jessi.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-30:/posts/2018-09-30-clothes-makeup.html</guid></item><item><title>I did my shot "the right way"!</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-09-24-good-injection.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Okay so, last August I fucked up my shot and got scared. From then on I have been bad at giving myself a shot. With the help of my friend over the last two months I was finally able to give myself a shot, alone, the right way, without anxiety or undo stress! Huge deal for me &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YISSSSSS 🐍
&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-09-24:/posts/2018-09-24-good-injection.html</guid></item><item><title>So I never forget</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-07-13-to-never-forget.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Four times now in the last four years I have gone on this horrible cycle of staying on hormones for 8 months or so, then falling off the trail. This means four times I have learned this lesson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I start hating expression, my hormones are off balance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time it was all too apparent. I saw how my body not acting female, and too low of a dose caused me to feel dissociated, hating the world and expression. It manifests as frustration at how the world is, and incessantly asking the question "why". Why am I this way, why do I like this, why can't I have a choice in the matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news, is that since I conquered injections, I have never missed a dose. What I learned during my last blood work is that my current dosage of estrogen alone is putting my levels in a good range. I don't have to take an anti-androgen. Now, if my body still doesn't do the right thing after some more time I may start Lupron, or try Progesterone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means if I can stick to sticking a needle in my leg once a week I should never have to learn this lesson again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I never go through this again. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-07-13:/posts/2018-07-13-to-never-forget.html</guid></item><item><title>Approved for Lupron</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a month now I have been waiting for my doctor to see if I could get my insurance to cover Lupron as my primary anti-androgen. I was told a week ago or so that I was approved and I will start taking Lupron injections soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting because Lurpon acts in either a monthly or quarterly dose. It would be very hard for me to miss my doses and fuck up my hormones again. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am also trying to not get my hopes up. I have no boobs again and what if this doesn't work again? What if the side effects are worse? What if? So I am just waiting patiently until the end of the month when I have my appointment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I am hoping it goes very poorly. But, I think that's just my dysphoric depression eating at me. And if it goes well, I will be ecstatic and happy to be girl again. I can't wait to get back on the road.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-06-21:/posts/2018-06-21-lupron.html</guid></item><item><title>Why must I keep trying?</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-17-wishing-for-progress.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been on the verge of wanting to make more progress in my transition. I am still trapped by so many things. I want to keep moving forward. I want to become stronger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I get right in front of one of my walls it is always the physical pain I experience that laughs at me. I can no longer tell if I want to learn how to be expressive, or if I should give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be expressive, to have gender, to be able to look at cis people without assuming something negative. But I feel my chronic pain is a never ending tunnel into all the old ways of being. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't I just accept this is my limit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fucking hate this shit. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-17:/posts/2018-05-17-wishing-for-progress.html</guid></item><item><title>Starting Finasteride</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-12-finasteride.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I begun taking Finasteride as my testosterone suppressant. The spironolactone had fucked with me enough that I put my foot down to try something else. While, this chemical is not very effective, it is a stepping stone to trying Lupron. So I will try to track my progress with taking Finasteride to see if I notice a difference. But hopefully I well get on Lupron soon. That is much more appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope I get my tits back 😡&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-12:/posts/2018-05-12-finasteride.html</guid></item><item><title>Dejection in my transition</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-04-23-empty.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don't think I have written about this nearly as much as I should. Because I have gone off and on my hormone meds many times now I feel I have fucked up my transition to a point and it is very disheartening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so let's be clear, it's really just one thing that's deeply upsetting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i-have-lost-my-boobs"&gt;I have lost my boobs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the sense that four times my boobs have grown to an acceptable size, tiny sure, but notable. Four times they have shrunk back down to almost nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This breaks my heart in ways most don't seem to understand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stop my hormone treatment when I can't stand the pain any longer. This has always happened in the winter, when my tense cold body is tearing at my joints and it's too much. So I stop taking my spiro in an effort to reduce my side effects and try to hurt less. Every time I do this, I lose my breasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couple my pain with my inability to eat normally, my depressive episodes, and it seems inevitable I'd lose them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My greatest fear is that I've "spent" all my breast growth and I will never get boobs again. Thinking about this makes me tear up every time. What if I MUST get implants in order to have boobs, which I've had before and lost several times? I don't want that reality. I really don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="so-what-can-i-do-about-it"&gt;So what can I do about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to focus again on how I can fix this problem. I've been wallowing a lot lately. Mostly because it is still cold in MA so I'm not mentally prepared to go back on my Spiro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to doctor about other chemical to suppress testosterone other than Spiro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've heard of trans women using:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finasteride&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyproterone Acetate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flutamide/Bicalutamide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lupron&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back in the day they used to "brute force" T suppressing with Estradiol Injections. But, I was on a rather large dose of injection and nothing happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am seeing my doctor in a couple weeks. I'm quite certain I will be saying to him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to seriously consider other options than Spironolactone for my anti-androgen, and if you can't, or won't, please be candid with me because I need to find someone who will. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I saw him I meekly tried to talk about this. His response was "I'll ask around" and "have you considered an orchiectomy?" After much consideration, I am not ready to move towards surgery, so no orchi for me yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i-hate-this"&gt;I hate this&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know some girls can't take HRT for health reasons, but I have been unable to find any online who have had the same issue as me. To grow and lose them many times is crushing me. I really wish I could express how devastating this is. I had real boobs that made me happy for these brief moments. And I keep fucking losing them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day someone tried to get frisky with me and as soon as they touched my chest I nearly started bawling right there. It killed the mood for me completely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not be defined by my body. I will not be defined by my body. I will not be defined by my body. 😢&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-04-23:/posts/2018-04-23-empty.html</guid></item><item><title>hrt 4 year anniversary</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-03-24-four-years-hrt.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I forgot about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes me sad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My perception of hrt has changed from a hopeful uplifting positive thing to a dark torturous painful requirement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate this. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-03-24:/posts/2018-03-24-four-years-hrt.html</guid></item><item><title>My Transition... so far</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-03-12-my-transition.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven't been writing about transition specific things, and I figured I should. So here is an introduction to my transition...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-use-the-word-transsexual"&gt;I use the word transsexual&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is very important to distinguish between gender(expression) dysphoria, and body(sex) dysphoria. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expression dysphoria is about the outside, how we present ourselves to the world. Sex dysphoria is about the relationship with the body. In the cases where they seem to overlap it is even more important to determine which of these dysphoria roots the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I like to remind people, the universe is free to experience all kinds. There are some people with no sex dypshoria, some people with a little, and some with a lot. Combine that idea with expression dysphoria and we can have a huge spectrum of how people relate to their body and the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I feel my primary issue is my relationship with my body, I use the word transsexual to describe this facet of my life. Expression, while important and I want to get better at it, has not felt like the driving cause of this change in my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-hate-expression"&gt;I hate expression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But mostly because I suck at it. I wish I Was good at it, but I don't think that is my purpose in life. I still struggle with buying clothing, sharing my feelings, and generally allowing who I am to exist in the world. Thanks DPDR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try actively on a regular basis to fight this. I want to be expressive. I wish I could dance, and simply put my emotions in the world. But it's pretty fucking hard. I can't even buy clothing for myself without it being a major thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason expression is hard is because I still see myself as male mostly, in mirrors. My lack of breasts also effects my relationship with expression. Because it is so difficult to remain on my medications, I have grown and lost my breasts four times now. And they may never come back now. We'll see. It is not that I have small breasts, there is quite literally so little tissue on my body you wouldn't know I had breasts. It breaks my heart and makes me feel inadequate. I never wanted a large chest, I just wanted A chest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bleh"&gt;Bleh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to not read the narrative. It's boring and unintseresting. But I figured I'd right it down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I write a bit more about my transition. I hope it pushes me to make more progress because I don't want to remain stagnant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-narrative"&gt;My narrative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst acknowledging my chronic pain for the first time in early 2012 I began exploring my strugles with expression. After a number of months it became clear to me I was drawn to what we call "feminine" expression. In the following months I drew out the reality that, it was my body not being female which distressed me. I then knew I would need to medically transition from male to female. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first thing I was confident about was my distaste for facial hair. I started laser hair removal treatments. It took another handful of months before I could get access to hormone treatement. Spring 2014 I started Estradiol and Spironolactone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following year was mostly okay. I had quit my job and was focusing on my transition. However an unwarrented arrest and the increase of my chronic pain threw shit into the trenches. January 2015 I tried to end my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully a friend of mine was willing to take the responsibility of sending me to a hospital. Through her insistence I was registered as female, that event is a major factor in my recovery. I spent a month or so in a partial hopsitalization program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after I left that program, I worked for one more year at a startup, learning later it was a true pity hire. But I was fired because my health deteriorated and they sucked at communcation and management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that year of working, I played with my hormone dose a lot. I had attempted to end my life because I had found out my hormone treatment made my chornic pain worse. After trying all kinds of dosing options I concluded I needed to stay on hormones despite the increase of chronic pain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I left my job, I was beginning my new chapter of van life. I bought a van in late spring 2016 and spent the summer converting it to a livable space. I did a trip to Nova Scotia, a trip to the Carolinas. I spent the winter in MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 I left for Florida at the beginning of spring. It was on this trip I became real. For the summer in MA, I began injections for my estrogen. I was very happy with the switch. I felt good. I made another trip to Florida in the end of fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 I came back to MA in January. Here I shall stay until the summer and what's next I don't know. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-03-12:/posts/2018-03-12-my-transition.html</guid></item></channel></rss>