<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - vandwelling</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Happy 2 years Vanessa 😍</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the love so far, the experiences, and more to come. I'm sorry you were hurt recently, please trust I will take care of you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-13:/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa got in a minor accident</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-11-accident.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My mother was driving, we were shortly off the highway and a merging truck did not yield to us. My mother had no option to change lanes and the clipped my slider door and scraped toward the back. Very minor, but damn am I pissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not been in an accident since I was sixteen. I have no clue what's happening or whether they can even repair Vanessa back to original without simply replacing parts. And of course that's what I'd prefer because fuck them for their claimed blatant arrogance in assuming we were going to move over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it's time to deal with another thing on my plate that is full of uncertainty and I'm sure, more hassle than I imagine... I'll post pictures after it's all over. Sigh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-11:/posts/2018-05-11-accident.html</guid></item><item><title>Stuck in MA</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-03-05-stuck.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So, due to many reasons, I have decided to stay in MA until the summer hits. I know. SADFACE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the plan is to focus on selling stuff, getting my kitchen built in Vanessa, and continuing my other plans as much as I can while still in MA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do plan to bug out sometimes. I have some places in New England I should see, and hope I have the money and time to do that. But I'll have to wait until at least May to do anything like that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a shift in plans, but I shall make the best of it. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-03-05:/posts/2018-03-05-stuck.html</guid></item><item><title>Drive Shaft Bearing</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-03-01-drive-shaft-bearing.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sigh. so the Wheel bearings didn't fix the issue I was feeling. Turns out it was the center drive shaft bearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had made assumptions it would be the bearings, instead of investigating deeply. And while I needed to do that bearing anyway, I felt disappointed. Anyway, Vanessa is all fixed now :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-03-01:/posts/2018-03-01-drive-shaft-bearing.html</guid></item><item><title>Time to fix those bearings...</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-02-23-bearings.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A while back a mechanic informed me I will need to repack my bearings in my front right wheel. Now is the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've begun making sound and I've scheduled to get that repaired. I hope they can repack and reseal, but thankfully it's not that expensive to do 😁&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-02-23:/posts/2018-02-23-bearings.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa is back</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-01-31-vanessa-back.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have Vanessa back. Things were fine. It was the belt tensioner. I should have seen this coming. I heard light squeaking in the belt the last month or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway. I got in and drove off. I parked, opened the door. But Vanessa kept beeping at me like I forgot something. I check. The lights are off, the key is out, why won't she shut up!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does she really miss me that much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems like there is a short somewhere, which is preventing the warning beep from stopping. I worry it's part of the ignition circuit. But it could be related to a jolt when the belt was first tossed. Maybe I have fried a fuse somewhere. I shall dig soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I am very happy to have Vanessa back in my arms.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-01-31:/posts/2018-01-31-vanessa-back.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa threw her belt twice :(</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On my way home, I felt it. The heat stopped coming out. The cold creeped in quickly. I noticed the battery light on the dash. The steering felt stiff, barely noticable at highway speeds but unmistakable. And finally, the temp gauge began to rise fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had thrown my drive belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened before. But not in the winter. I was already exhausted. But I found a place to stop and took out a spare belt and tools. Inside the engine bay I noticed the other belt wasn't severely damaged, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With great effort I put on the new belt. In the cold this took a while. I got in the cockpit. Key in, engine turning, and I felt something off. I go back to the engine bay and the new belt was off already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give up. It's too cold, I can't do more. I'm calling a tow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what why she can't hold a belt?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</guid></item><item><title>A very social month. Today I part north.</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-01-05-a-social-month.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the last 38 days, I was social 29 of them. This is a lot for me. I have never spent so much time and energy meeting new people in my life. Van life gave me this month. Van life gave me all the growth I experienced the month of December. Oh and all the cool people I met too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights because of my openness to meeting new people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I performed in a concert!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went busking for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found a boy I was attracted to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found that sexuality doesn't have to hurt as bad as it used to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realized more confidence than I've ever had before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can now meet new people without anxiety (except cis girls, you scary yo ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel so different about what I am now. What I offer to the world. Who I am willing to be. Who I can be. So shit. Thanks Jacksonville, St Augustine, and Orlando Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never would have changed like this without Vanessa. In the face of so much change, without proximity of friends, I had to push to learn to make new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-3-vanessa"&gt;I &amp;lt;3 Vanessa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside my growth, I saw every single person I met grow too. New confidences found in every one of them. This makes me feel very good. Especially when I can have an impact on my trans sisters. Nothing makes me happier than seeing them grow, and find inner strength and happiness. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what I am now, thanks girl. I am so fucking grateful for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-cold-of-the-north"&gt;The cold of the North&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am beginning my ascent today. In six days time I shall be back in Mass enduring the insufferable hell of winter. Each day I will get colder and colder. And hopefully not depressed along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch out for some more posts. I'll have a lot of time to write this week. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-01-05:/posts/2018-01-05-a-social-month.html</guid></item><item><title>Trip 4: The Fall</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2017-11-06-the-fall.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finally departed for my next trip in Vanessa! Took way too long, but after support from my kith and kin I am off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trip I should still make it down to Florida again, but I must return in January. That's the sad part. So this is really, half the fall trip. But that's okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-i-accomplished-this-summer"&gt;What I accomplished this summer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installed new bright LED light&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;redid wiring for existing lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix my shoe-rack style organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replaced the blower motor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;re-adhered my ceiling insulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;got brand new brake lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm rather proud of my ceiling insulation trick. I found some rather large hex bolts and drove them through the insulation so the head of the bolt faced the floor. Then, I used a magnet on the end of the bold to hold the insulation to the metal ceiling. This creates an air gap about 1/4 - 1/2 inch. So I glued some mylar sheeting onto the insulation I had hoping it might have some effect. Thanks for the idea Brittany!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="other-summer-learnings"&gt;Other Summer Learnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thankfully had many experiences this summer, and it's so cool to look back at how much I changed through it. I went on dates! Can you believe that? Me, on a real date. Damn. I worked a lot of my sewing project. And I cannot wait for the spring so I can show it to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a lot more grounding in myself. I think being physical with a few people really helped me with that. I learned just how much physical touch can alleviate my pain. And if I'm not careful I might addicted to it. It is a remarkable feeling, allowing yourself to feel worthy of attention, affection, and pleasure. It was definitely jarring at first though. But now, I can't wait to find out more about how I want physicality in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also truly began to understand why people like me. Oh and truly believing that people see me as a girl. I glimpse more of the reality others see in me. I think this means I am also beginning to accept what I am. I can be this person I was fated to be. And I can direct her story too. I have made some bold statements in the last month I never thought I would ever say. Damn. I am proud of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="food"&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suck at food. I used to hate food, hate eating, and feared eating. So today on my first day, going to the grocery store and not hating the whole process, and feeling empowered in a new way was awesome. I will slowly work myself into a slightly chubby wubbly mess and I'll love it! I can't wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got to make sure I get me lots of them fruits and veggies while also stuffing myself with crap. MMMmmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rolling-on"&gt;Rolling on&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I am off to visit friends and family for the rest of the month. Then off to Florida for December. See you there :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-11-06:/posts/2017-11-06-the-fall.html</guid></item><item><title>New drawers for Vanessa!</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2017-09-28-new-drawers-for-vanessa.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My wonderful friend helped me install new drawers in Vanessa. Totally maximizing some of the space in the rear beneath my bed. I am super excited about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left side, which is empty for now, will hold a removable plastic drawer storage solution. This is so I can continue to remove my long board if I ever use it again. If I didn't have that pesky thing I might have filled the entire rear with drawers. Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="design"&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are basic construction. The drawers are 4 panels glued and screwed together on the sides. The drawer base is inset into the wood 1/8 of an inch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frame is to walls with two small back plates to stop the drawers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reused drawer slides from an old ikea dresser I had. The slides are mounted onto the side walls and inset into the drawers as deep as they can go.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-09-28:/posts/2017-09-28-new-drawers-for-vanessa.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa's brakes are fixed!</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2017-09-26-vanessa-brakes-fixed.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it. I found the people and got them to fix the brake lines. I am very happy about that. I realize my original estimates of repair costs were extreme. That's partly because the mechanic I found I trust most is at a dealership. Partly because I am essentially out of money and was on my approach to depression. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-09-26:/posts/2017-09-26-vanessa-brakes-fixed.html</guid></item><item><title>Update on Vanessa's brakes</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2017-09-12-vanessa-brake-update.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I went to another mechanic to ask for quotes about the things my other mechanic suggested. OF course they're willing to do for less, but I'm concerned. I really need to get on this if I'm going to leave for the winter. And yet I'm trolling along like the sun will never set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mechanic, did not give me anything other than a lump sum quote. Which is not what I wanted. I had asked about my outer tie rod and bearings and guess what. They came back with "your ball joints are shot". I brought out the document from Mercedes describing that traditional ball joint tests are not applicable. He cited his 30 years experience and did not fully read over the document. Next time, if I talk to any mechanic about my front end, I'm showing them this. And likely printing out other pertinent comments from the forums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When questioning about the brake lines it was a real chore. The guy sucks at communicating and took my curiosity hard, I think. Regardless I left feeling like I had to fight him for information, when all I wanted to understand were the options and what he was planning to do. I don't know who to turn to next. I don't want to have to ride out to Burlington for mechanics. But maybe I should turn to my friend's mechanics. Maybe I should ask my other mechanic about other options he's willing to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm so hesitant to move forward with this because I want it to fail. I dont' want to take money from others yet I have to if I'm to leave for the winter. Debt. Serious serious debt. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-09-12:/posts/2017-09-12-vanessa-brake-update.html</guid></item><item><title>Is Vanessa dead?</title><link>http://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2017-09-05-vanessa-is-dead.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I got word from my mechanic about my brake fluid leak. It is catastrophic. Vanessa needs over $4,000 of repairs. I only got one year and three months out of her. Not the two I had hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can hardly process this right now. I feel it's over. I don't think I've mentioned this, and I feel I shouldn't, but I have applied for disability. I am expecting a hearing sometime this winter. What will I do until then? To be stuck in my old car, in my old life, in my childhood house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as of now I need wheel bearings repacked, an outer tie rod, and new brake lines, load sensing valve and load sensing link. All critical things for safety. I cannot go on without repairing these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will never have this money. And even if people in my life want to pay for it I don't think I could accept. How could I. I have already been given so much. If I am awarded disability, I can wait until I save up my own money to fix or replace Vanessa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-09-05:/posts/2017-09-05-vanessa-is-dead.html</guid></item></channel></rss>