<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - vandwelling</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fixing the new van's coolant leak</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2019-06-17-fixing-coolant-leak.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I totally lucked out. This coolant leak issue really concerned me. Coolant goes everywhere in the van and a leak could be minor or catastrophic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I added water to the system to fill up the resavoir. Then I got the engine hot, stopped an opened the hood to see the most obvious leak ever coming out of the hose leading in to the auxillary water pump. Yeah these vans have two water pumps because the lines are so long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the screw clamp holding the hose on almost slipped off. And because the hose was not cut perfectly straight the clamp wasn't even totally around the hose. My first attempt to reseat it failed. The second time I totally reseated it properly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put water in the resivoir again and drove. Coolant low showed up again. I checked and no leak. So the thermostat must have opened and pulled in more liquid lowering the tank. I added more water. Things seem fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the transmission is also less noisy now. I wonder if coolant was never reaching the transmission and that effects the torque converter, or if I am overthinking it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I fixed my coolant leak all by myself. Now just time to do a flush and get it all back to normal. Super pumped about it. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2019-06-17:/posts/2019-06-17-fixing-coolant-leak.html</guid></item><item><title>Finally Fall - Leaving MA once again</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-03-finally-fall-left.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am waking up in Connecticut. I don't have much going on in my head or heart. I am ready. I am moving. And I have a plan for where to go and when. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am eager to get to get to warmer weather and feel more comfortable about showering. I am eager to learn the new logistics of having a sink and grey water. I am eager to see people with all this sense of self and reality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sad to have left all these people. People I've known for a long time. People I didn't get to know well enough. People who I just met. But since my heart is in Vanessa I am dragged away by a sense of adventure and purpose. I must finish this journey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="age-and-possiblity"&gt;Age and possiblity.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am thinking about age. In youth I heard so many people suggest their life was ruined, over, or void of possiblity. I felt that way. Even when I was doing interseting things I felt my life was going to be shit. Now I can see how most people's greatest acheivements occur after 30 after 35 even. It takes a long time to build enough to do those great things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 30 this year. I can see the goals I've had in mind for over a decade, and how I need more time to learn what I need to learn in order to actualize those goals. And so this journey I am on is a conscious choice to bring me closer to those goals in the way that I know how. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this chapter brings me more new. I am afraid after all, that I will stagnate. When I have so much to do I cannot. I need to heal. I need a better body. I need more practice. More skills. More interactions with different kinds of people. More challenges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us hope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/inspiration/angels-dont-worry.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-03:/posts/2018-10-03-finally-fall-left.html</guid></item><item><title>Kitchen Update for Vanessa: part 2</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-10-02-vanessa-updates.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. I am so pumped about the kitchen update to Vanessa. I still have things to finish up, but all the hard part, which I needed help from others, is done! Life is different now that this is complete. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="main-features-include"&gt;Main Features include:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="internal" href="#vanessa-kitchen-update"&gt;Just get me to the pics!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70" Countertop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12" Diameter Sink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 bruner propane stove-in-a-drawer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cabinet for 20lb propane tank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insulated Cooler Box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to write about the novel parts of this build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="materials-tools"&gt;Materials &amp;amp; Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some cheap things here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$1 office furniture peace which I reclaimed wood from. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A friend had some plywood lying around too. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x 4'x8' sheet of plywood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sink is a reclaimed mizing bowl from my mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continuous hinge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JBWeld + plastic hose coupling + vent hose for sink drain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4L flexible bag for grey water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized after we finished the reason why this furniture piece called out to me: it reminds me of my last apartment which had a similar 70's ish appearance. This made me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For tooling I had a TON of help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table saw, Jigsaw, Router, Nail gun, clamps, Electric Drills, Dremel all borrowed from friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost nothing was my own XD, except maybe sandpaper lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="general-construction"&gt;General Construction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predominantly, boxes are held together with nails and wood glue. Things are screwed together using screws. And screws and L brackets hold the unit to the van. Aside from the Router for the sink hole this is a very basic build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="insulated-cooler-box"&gt;Insulated Cooler Box&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a bunch of leftover insulation from when I insulated. I need a better food storage system. I also needed another seat/table. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took off the handle to the cooler, did some measuring, and cut insulation one layer at a time and dry fit them to make sure they would fit well. Afterwards I measured the the outer dimensions and cut the wood for the box using 1/2" plywood. Using wood glue and a nail gun, we then clamped it all together overnight to let the glue set and try to maintain a square box. There is NO bottom to this box. I figured it didn't need it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once set, I installed the hinge and realized the insulation could make a mess if I didn't do something. So I used masking tape to wrap the insulation to protect my food from any random bits falling out or something. The top layer was also such a tight fit I needed to make a handle out of tape to make it easier to take out. I plan to test what kind of difference this box makes for ice retention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I placed some weatherstripping around the edge of the cooler and the box. I did this on the cooler itself because, as a cheap cooler, it seemed some water evaporates tothe top, settles, and finds  cracks to fall out of in the seal. Hoepfully this will help all forms of air from transfering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sink"&gt;Sink&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sink was nightmare. Not have all the best tools made it very hard. WE wanted to use a drill press, but the press wasn't deep enough to get a hole in the center of the bowl, so we used a dremel tool to cut the hole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we tried to warp the metal so it had more of a slope. This was horrifying. Thick stainless sheet metal and improper heating tools made it impossible to change the slope of the bowl. We tried using Map/Pro fuel but it just wasn't enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this, I will have to fille a layer of resin of sorts in the bottom of the bowl, then sand to shape it into an effective slope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting the hole in the countertop was not too difficult, however because I wanted a snug fit, we had to keep making it a tiny bit wider over and over. STill it is not done so I can properly fit and seal the sink inside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="drain-hose-and-grey-water-tank"&gt;Drain, hose and grey water tank&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a real challenge to decide on. So many routes here. But I had a couple requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grey water tank MUST fit in my backpack so I can bring it into bathrooms for dumping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smallest profile possible in sink to have maximum space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led me to the idea of putting a coupling on the bottom glued into place. Because the sink isn't depressed for an average sink drain I didn't want to try and work around that, nore the challenge of sealing it all. Once I settled on this it became a test to find the right kind of hose. I found it in a vent hose which had the right type of adapters on the end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grey water tank option took a lot of research. The flexible bag option came up to me last and I was lucky this had lashe points. The bag is suspended using QuestionMark Hooks screwed into my wheel well box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cabinet-and-drawer"&gt;Cabinet and Drawer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothign too special here. I was very lucky the depth of the stove fit my max dimensions for hte cabinet, barely. We had to file out a groove in a wall of the cabinet to make room for the pin of the hinges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a simple box with nails and glue, the smallest drawer box possible for the stove, and a simple shelf for storage. We cut a hole in the bottom of the cabinet for the propane tank to sit in to help keep it stable. In hindsight I cut it too big and has some play in it. Might try to fill the edges with something to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-10-02:/posts/2018-10-02-vanessa-updates.html</guid></item><item><title>Kitchen building, day 1</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-08-25-kitchen-day-1.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I am finally building a kitchen unit in my van!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to do a fun thing and put the stove in a drawer. This way I don't ruin my countertop and space with a dumb looking thing. I am using an old large stainless steel mixing bowl for my sink. Because my mom is donating her old RV fridge to me, the unit is going to look odd, but that's okay. Free stuff and really cheap materials = good to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures from the first day, and the sketchup design we slapped together. The trick part is going to be securing the unit to the inside. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-08-25:/posts/2018-08-25-kitchen-day-1.html</guid></item><item><title>Happy 2 years Vanessa 😍</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the love so far, the experiences, and more to come. I'm sorry you were hurt recently, please trust I will take care of you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-13:/posts/2018-05-13-2-years.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa got in a minor accident</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-05-11-accident.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My mother was driving, we were shortly off the highway and a merging truck did not yield to us. My mother had no option to change lanes and the clipped my slider door and scraped toward the back. Very minor, but damn am I pissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not been in an accident since I was sixteen. I have no clue what's happening or whether they can even repair Vanessa back to original without simply replacing parts. And of course that's what I'd prefer because fuck them for their claimed blatant arrogance in assuming we were going to move over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it's time to deal with another thing on my plate that is full of uncertainty and I'm sure, more hassle than I imagine... I'll post pictures after it's all over. Sigh. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-11:/posts/2018-05-11-accident.html</guid></item><item><title>Stuck in MA</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-03-05-stuck.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So, due to many reasons, I have decided to stay in MA until the summer hits. I know. SADFACE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the plan is to focus on selling stuff, getting my kitchen built in Vanessa, and continuing my other plans as much as I can while still in MA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do plan to bug out sometimes. I have some places in New England I should see, and hope I have the money and time to do that. But I'll have to wait until at least May to do anything like that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a shift in plans, but I shall make the best of it. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-03-05:/posts/2018-03-05-stuck.html</guid></item><item><title>Drive Shaft Bearing</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-03-01-drive-shaft-bearing.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sigh. so the Wheel bearings didn't fix the issue I was feeling. Turns out it was the center drive shaft bearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had made assumptions it would be the bearings, instead of investigating deeply. And while I needed to do that bearing anyway, I felt disappointed. Anyway, Vanessa is all fixed now :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-03-01:/posts/2018-03-01-drive-shaft-bearing.html</guid></item><item><title>Time to fix those bearings...</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-02-23-bearings.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A while back a mechanic informed me I will need to repack my bearings in my front right wheel. Now is the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've begun making sound and I've scheduled to get that repaired. I hope they can repack and reseal, but thankfully it's not that expensive to do 😁&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-02-23:/posts/2018-02-23-bearings.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa is back</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-01-31-vanessa-back.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have Vanessa back. Things were fine. It was the belt tensioner. I should have seen this coming. I heard light squeaking in the belt the last month or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway. I got in and drove off. I parked, opened the door. But Vanessa kept beeping at me like I forgot something. I check. The lights are off, the key is out, why won't she shut up!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does she really miss me that much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems like there is a short somewhere, which is preventing the warning beep from stopping. I worry it's part of the ignition circuit. But it could be related to a jolt when the belt was first tossed. Maybe I have fried a fuse somewhere. I shall dig soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I am very happy to have Vanessa back in my arms.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-01-31:/posts/2018-01-31-vanessa-back.html</guid></item><item><title>Vanessa threw her belt twice :(</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On my way home, I felt it. The heat stopped coming out. The cold creeped in quickly. I noticed the battery light on the dash. The steering felt stiff, barely noticable at highway speeds but unmistakable. And finally, the temp gauge began to rise fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had thrown my drive belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened before. But not in the winter. I was already exhausted. But I found a place to stop and took out a spare belt and tools. Inside the engine bay I noticed the other belt wasn't severely damaged, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With great effort I put on the new belt. In the cold this took a while. I got in the cockpit. Key in, engine turning, and I felt something off. I go back to the engine bay and the new belt was off already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give up. It's too cold, I can't do more. I'm calling a tow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what why she can't hold a belt?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-01-26:/posts/2018-01-26-thrown-belt.html</guid></item><item><title>A very social month. Today I part north.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2018-01-05-a-social-month.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the last 38 days, I was social 29 of them. This is a lot for me. I have never spent so much time and energy meeting new people in my life. Van life gave me this month. Van life gave me all the growth I experienced the month of December. Oh and all the cool people I met too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights because of my openness to meeting new people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I performed in a concert!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went busking for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found a boy I was attracted to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found that sexuality doesn't have to hurt as bad as it used to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realized more confidence than I've ever had before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can now meet new people without anxiety (except cis girls, you scary yo ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel so different about what I am now. What I offer to the world. Who I am willing to be. Who I can be. So shit. Thanks Jacksonville, St Augustine, and Orlando Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never would have changed like this without Vanessa. In the face of so much change, without proximity of friends, I had to push to learn to make new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-3-vanessa"&gt;I &amp;lt;3 Vanessa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside my growth, I saw every single person I met grow too. New confidences found in every one of them. This makes me feel very good. Especially when I can have an impact on my trans sisters. Nothing makes me happier than seeing them grow, and find inner strength and happiness. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what I am now, thanks girl. I am so fucking grateful for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-cold-of-the-north"&gt;The cold of the North&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am beginning my ascent today. In six days time I shall be back in Mass enduring the insufferable hell of winter. Each day I will get colder and colder. And hopefully not depressed along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch out for some more posts. I'll have a lot of time to write this week. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-01-05:/posts/2018-01-05-a-social-month.html</guid></item><item><title>Trip 4: The Fall</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/posts/2017-11-06-the-fall.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finally departed for my next trip in Vanessa! Took way too long, but after support from my kith and kin I am off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trip I should still make it down to Florida again, but I must return in January. That's the sad part. So this is really, half the fall trip. But that's okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-i-accomplished-this-summer"&gt;What I accomplished this summer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installed new bright LED light&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;redid wiring for existing lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix my shoe-rack style organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replaced the blower motor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;re-adhered my ceiling insulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;got brand new brake lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm rather proud of my ceiling insulation trick. I found some rather large hex bolts and drove them through the insulation so the head of the bolt faced the floor. Then, I used a magnet on the end of the bold to hold the insulation to the metal ceiling. This creates an air gap about 1/4 - 1/2 inch. So I glued some mylar sheeting onto the insulation I had hoping it might have some effect. Thanks for the idea Brittany!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="other-summer-learnings"&gt;Other Summer Learnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thankfully had many experiences this summer, and it's so cool to look back at how much I changed through it. I went on dates! Can you believe that? Me, on a real date. Damn. I worked a lot of my sewing project. And I cannot wait for the spring so I can show it to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a lot more grounding in myself. I think being physical with a few people really helped me with that. I learned just how much physical touch can alleviate my pain. And if I'm not careful I might addicted to it. It is a remarkable feeling, allowing yourself to feel worthy of attention, affection, and pleasure. It was definitely jarring at first though. But now, I can't wait to find out more about how I want physicality in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also truly began to understand why people like me. Oh and truly believing that people see me as a girl. I glimpse more of the reality others see in me. I think this means I am also beginning to accept what I am. I can be this person I was fated to be. And I can direct her story too. I have made some bold statements in the last month I never thought I would ever say. Damn. I am proud of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="food"&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suck at food. I used to hate food, hate eating, and feared eating. So today on my first day, going to the grocery store and not hating the whole process, and feeling empowered in a new way was awesome. I will slowly work myself into a slightly chubby wubbly mess and I'll love it! I can't wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got to make sure I get me lots of them fruits and veggies while also stuffing myself with crap. MMMmmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rolling-on"&gt;Rolling on&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I am off to visit friends and family for the rest of the month. Then off to Florida for December. See you there :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-11-06:/posts/2017-11-06-the-fall.html</guid></item></channel></rss>