<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - writing</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mew, give it time.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-03-09-mew-doodle.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Mew doodle do, I&amp;#39;m thinking of you.
I hope that today you&amp;#39;re feeling less blue.
Cause in a couple days everything will be alright!
The clouds will clear and you will jeer, 
FUCK THAT&amp;#39;S SO BRIGHT!
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-03-09:/posts/2018-03-09-mew-doodle.html</guid></item><item><title>Endemic</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2018-02-14-endemic.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t have to shut my eyes 
I didn&amp;#39;t need to tell those lies
I should have been more honest
with myself

Caught staring beneath that light
Wishful thinking, I&amp;#39;ll be alright
I should have been more honest
with myself

My world may have gone a tumbling
I may have tried to end this fling
But I won&amp;#39;t stop this suffering
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2018-02-14:/posts/2018-02-14-endemic.html</guid></item><item><title>The last few sips</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-11-26-drinking-coffee.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;It ended slowly.
Coffee cools the fastest when we&amp;#39;re least interested.
The last few sips arduous, obligatory.
Didn&amp;#39;t mother always say finish your plate?
How rude to the universe lest you be grateful.
Didn&amp;#39;t Oliver teach us wanting more was forbidden?
How rude to the universe lest you be grateful.

Eyes up from the mug
the battered face of a weary angel
eclipses all else.
My soul sank beneath the stars, shattered.
Am I really that much trouble? I asked.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-26:/posts/2017-11-26-drinking-coffee.html</guid></item><item><title>Chronic Pain</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-10-22-chronic-pain.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;fucking sucks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is realizing your pain level 3 is other people's level 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is being excited when you get to spend the first couple hours of a day without significant pain when you did something right while you slept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is never escaping thinking about how many spoons you have left and getting better a categorizing actions in terms of spoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is knowing that there is no configuration of your body that doesn't hurt your more. Even lying down still adds to your pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is hiding it from those you care most about so you can have fun times together without casting your pain as a burden onto them. Sympathetic/Empathetic friends are the worst :p befriend sociopaths. haha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is not being able to take strong pain killers for fear of becoming suicidal at the thought of "this is what it feels like without pain?!?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is knowing that your decision to take estrogen and live as female is what makes your pain unbearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the few reasons some people condone suicide.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-22:/posts/2017-10-22-chronic-pain.html</guid></item><item><title>Modern Stoics</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-09-16-modern-stoics.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Such is the modern stoics claim
They&amp;#39;ve&amp;#39; evolved past emotional pain
Turn circles on all who pass
to force their logic down
until we care and admit we&amp;#39;re wrong.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-09-16:/posts/2017-09-16-modern-stoics.html</guid></item><item><title>[poem] You are worthy.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-07-18-poem-worthy.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;You are worthy. You are strong. You can do it. All night long!

In the shadows, through the night. The sun won&amp;#39;t rest, always rising to fight.

In harmony, it&amp;#39;s tough to be, when you believe, you&amp;#39;re unworthy.

but I see you different. I see you whole. And trust me, you&amp;#39;ve got a lovely soul.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-07-18:/posts/2017-07-18-poem-worthy.html</guid></item><item><title>This one problem. An old journal entry.</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-07-07-this-one-problem.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Intellectual Understanding vs. Actualized Integration. The process of normalization. Empathy as dissociation. Self awareness as dissociation. The ability to remove your conscious thoughts from the railroad tracks of your primary lifeline. Then jump back in with a fresh perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spent too much of my time removed, dissociated. My challenge is to learn to engage again. To step back on the rails and go. It seems that the majority of people never learn to step off sometimes. They spiral towards the path the tracks reveal for them. Quite often this leads to scary negative places. Their challenge is to dissociate and glean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite variable to all this is how much you share with the world. How often you choose to be vulnerable. A mind inside itself will become whatever it chooses. A mind outside itself will become whatever falls upon them. These are extremes and painted in a binary approach. But this is a variable that reaches to the depths of every choice and every action. It is flexible enough to apply in a complex web of ideas and experiences, where some is over shared and some under shared. We often hide some things and display others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I am stuck in a bout of dissociation. My actions serve the body in a cold, machine like way. I truly have severed my hold on me. I am lost to the whirlwind of faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="afterward"&gt;Afterward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I over use the word dissociation. In the mental health complex it means something different than how I use it. The issues I wrote about on this day some two years ago are still relevant to me today. I suppose I would like to unpack some of it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="intellectual-understanding-vs-actualized-integration"&gt;Intellectual understanding vs Actualized integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might also be able to approach this issue from "practice what you preach". As in, many of us intellectually understand a concept, and can point out when others do not seem to live by that concept, but we often fail to actually integrate that understanding in to our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, we may be able to point out sexism, intellectually understand sexism, but fail to not be sexist. Whether we be blind to the acts, or somehow unable to truly change our behaviors, there is often this gap between these two ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understood that most people were not judging me as harshly as I expected. However to actually live in that world, to actualize and integrate that understanding took me years of concerted practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="experiential-normalization"&gt;Experiential Normalization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process with which something new becomes part of every day life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite ideas. It is every where in our lives. A new thing enters and disrupts our lives, thoughts, behaviors, until we find a way to integrate it, normalize its presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that advertising billboards are not seen as "strange" is an example. They have been around so long they appear "normal". Conversely when you acquire a new gadget you are focused on the toy for quite a while until you get "accustomed" to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process can be slow or fast depending on how greatly this new thing disrupts your life. Sometimes it is a stressing thing, other times exciting, or banal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I find valuable about this idea is learning to recognize the phase you are in with a new thing. Are you still hyper excited by the new thing? Do you wish you could get to "normal" quicker? Is that hard thing ever going to get easier? Understanding this concept has allowed me to shift with the tides of life more readily. For I can recognize that what is stressing me will soon no longer be (as) stressful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="empathy-and-self-awareness-as-dissociation-the-train-tracks-of-everyday-life"&gt;Empathy and Self Awareness as dissociation, the train tracks of everyday life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think most of us can recognize those people who never seem to stop and think. Those who are always simply going with their default self, or on these railroad tracks I speak of. And also those who never seem to stop thinking, never doing, never going, often stuck in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should one never stop and step off the tracks, it may seem like life is one big roller coaster ride you have no control over. Never step on the tracks and it may seem like life never happens. It appears that self awareness and empathy are two very powerful tools to help manage stepping off those tracks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empathy, can serve to help you understand someone else's life, their tracks. Which in turn may expose new understandings for your own life. Empathy is precisely attempting to leave your own perspective to be with another's. Self awareness is a way of stepping back within your self. A tool to allow introspective thinking about yourself. Which is how many or most of us attempt to make conscious change within ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it is clear by now that when I say dissociation, I mean stepping off those tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="finally"&gt;Finally&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that I use these tools and descriptions as a way of describing a concept. Alone, these tools are not some "answer" to life or some "absolute". However they can serve as a guide to new ways of approaching or thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-07-07:/posts/2017-07-07-this-one-problem.html</guid></item><item><title>A short intentional poem for open mic Poetry</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2017-04-26-poem-for-open-mic-poetry.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;a swirling visage,
trapped within my gaze,
drowns out the voices

the window remains frosted,
an effervescent stream
screams out from the abyss

face pressed against the glass,
numb,
at least now visible.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-04-26:/posts/2017-04-26-poem-for-open-mic-poetry.html</guid></item><item><title>And on and on</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2016-11-06-and-on.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Stand in a majestic grove of tall pines.
Endless trunks surrounding
a blanket of burnt orange needles.
far apart they seem,
but this grove&amp;#39;s depth eludes you.

The sun wrestles to peak it&amp;#39;s way
through the dense fir
but the basking heat muscles it&amp;#39;s way through.
The day is welcomingly warm.

Birds orchestrate the background.
As you listen, the dance seems pleasantly serene.
As you drift, they seem tacky and repetitive.

Snap back to the moment,
intrigued by a large boulder up ahead.

One and only,
it appears ripe for a sitting.
an unfamiliar
but old feeling hits you. Sparked.

A small burst of energy
has you excited to
jump and climb up the rock,
eager only to get there.

Scramble huff but only notice
how wonderful it is
to feel this young.

Atop the boulder you tower.

Turn round slowly
peruse that landscape.

Such a simple vantage point
inspires a sense of wonderment.
What a few feet can do.

Satisfied, you find a good edge
and sit down on the rock.
No, your tapping heels do not annoy the rock.
I&amp;#39;m sure it doesn&amp;#39;t mind.
Probably because it knows you&amp;#39;ll move on eventually.
Can&amp;#39;t sit on the rock forever.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2016-11-06:/posts/2016-11-06-and-on.html</guid></item><item><title>#lifeismoreinterestingthanthat</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2016-05-02-lifeismoreinterestingthanthat.html</link><description>&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;This universe is free,
to experience any kind of all kinds that it can.
Where everything is a remix of something else,
think elementally and smaller.
On top of all that raw abstract stuff,
the most complex, varied, and deep contexts occur;
human lives occur.

Impossible it seems, to be understand wholly,
to feel less alien and more human.
Each of us orbiting in and out of relationships
causing cataclysmic shifts in the arc of our lives.

Without all the words and language,
all this is happening. Every life is living,
every particle participating in the cosmic dance.
No collection of images we call letters,
can truly expose the fullness of any moment.

We are capable of connecting more deeply with
the ability to experience life without language.
To step back from this tiny network of definitions
and gaze at the immensity of universal life.

Life is more interesting than to live inside
harrowing, limiting, binary, word boxes.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2016-05-02:/posts/2016-05-02-lifeismoreinterestingthanthat.html</guid></item><item><title>Finding the girl in the reflection</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/posts/2015-10-07-finding-the-girl-in-the-reflection.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A moment glimpsed in the slider door to the balcony of my sixth floor apartment. A girl blocked my view. She was on the phone with a friend who had just moved 600 miles away. It was one o'clock in the morning. She was pacing, brought out of bed by the call. Adorned in a tank top and underwear she seemed happy. A story unfolds in my mind's eye...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;... A recovering self abuser, blessed with an eating disorder. A chronic pain condition which her medication amplifies. Learning to stand on her own, not as the clunky costume played before but as the honest representation of her window, she is connected to so many things.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She feels in so many ways. Proud to be fighting instead of crumpling from the weight of depression. She is on her way to becoming not who, but what she always wanted. Her goals don't look so far away. She connects with others as if never knowing what friendship was like. She is happy. She feels attractive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Standing in front of this glass door she talks with a friend about all the new things in life. Outside looking in this girl seems on top of her game. Overcoming obstacles, and forcing herself to remember: This is hard because it is new. Keep doing it and it will no longer be new, and no longer hard...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet here I am still holding on to that thread of dysmorphia. Outside these small moments of gender euphoria, where blur and dim light allow a different view, the mirror holds an uglier truth. Each gradual day of change in the body, produced almost zero modifications in my perception. The person looking back, hasn't transformed at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How sad it is that my perception of my body plays such a role in my understanding of the world. All of the work finding out that I am a good, kind, empathetic, caring, and strong person does not shatter the blanket shadow of dysmorphia. This affliction must be some kind of comforting. Or maybe a protection. This thread reaches deep in the roots of my experience. I am very attached to this perception. I say I am not attached, but if I weren't wouldn't something have changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What could she tell me? If that girl, in the reflection of my slider door, was in the room with me what would she say?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, my imagination told me that she would talk of freedom. The freedom to interpret your reality as you see fit. The subtle shifts you can make by looking for different qualities of the events around you. How you can find the awareness to notice your own biases. And how you can change them. She does not speak of changing the unchangeable. The window that you see the universe through cannot be demolished for renovations, for that would cease your existence. We can choose its shutters, drapes, curtains, trimming, glass. Each deserving of different care and attention. This freedom to choose applies to all of us. To find that freedom takes accepting you will have to leave the reality you are in. Journeys forward call for change. Not in action, or thought, but of your essence towards life. The raw feeling of what life is to you. She says you can create that world if you only let go of the one you're in.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2015-10-07:/posts/2015-10-07-finding-the-girl-in-the-reflection.html</guid></item></channel></rss>