<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - experiments</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>A failed glue experiment: Tear Mender</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-16-glue-fail</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I tried using a glue called Tear Mender in attempt to glue the elastic to the fabric before sewing it. Mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did not work the way I hoped. I seeped deep into the fabric and wouldn't set. Then it pilled and didn't look good. So, not this kind of glue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, exciting post...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I had more help.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2017-11-16:vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-16-glue-fail</guid></item><item><title>Experiment using snaps instead of hook and eyes for the elastic</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-02-snaps</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, a friend had the materials for putting snaps on stuff so I tried making a gaff with snaps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised. It went well, looked good, and functioned fine. For at least two hours of sitting and standing everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am definitely going to get some people to try this out. Especially those who have tried the hook and eye style already.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2017-11-02:vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-02-snaps</guid></item><item><title>New Construction Method Experiment</title><link>vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-15-new-construction-method</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So I had an epiphany about how to construct the gaff while making one for a new person. So I thought I'd try it out. I am impressed and can't wait to keep experimenting with this to prove it's a solid construction method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm looking for a couple things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is is durable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it provide the same level of tucking quality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it take less time to construct?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very quickly I can answer, it takes WAY less time to make. It took 55 minutes for me to make one of these panels. I went from 6 stitches to 1 stitch. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful that the placement of the eye all the way up in the corner is a benefit, although that needs to be tested a bunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears the tuck is fine as well. However I am trying out new materials and it looks like I need to adjust my sizing for these other materials so they function perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More experiments with these fabrics coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:None,2017-10-15:vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-15-new-construction-method</guid></item></channel></rss>