<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>A failed glue experiment: Tear Mender</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-16-glue-fail</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I tried using a glue called Tear Mender in attempt to glue the elastic to the fabric before sewing it. Mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did not work the way I hoped. I seeped deep into the fabric and wouldn't set. Then it pilled and didn't look good. So, not this kind of glue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, exciting post...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I had more help.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-16:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-16-glue-fail</guid></item><item><title>Experiment using snaps instead of hook and eyes for the elastic</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-02-snaps</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, a friend had the materials for putting snaps on stuff so I tried making a gaff with snaps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised. It went well, looked good, and functioned fine. For at least two hours of sitting and standing everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am definitely going to get some people to try this out. Especially those who have tried the hook and eye style already.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-11-02:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-11-02-snaps</guid></item><item><title>Liner Gaff: Intro video</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-22-gaff-intro-video</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Look what I finished! The Intro Video!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="videobox"&gt;
    &lt;iframe
        src="//player.vimeo.com/video/53047508?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0"
        width="100%" height="100%" frameborder="0"
        webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-22:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-22-gaff-intro-video</guid></item><item><title>New Construction Method Experiment</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-15-new-construction-method</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So I had an epiphany about how to construct the gaff while making one for a new person. So I thought I'd try it out. I am impressed and can't wait to keep experimenting with this to prove it's a solid construction method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm looking for a couple things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is is durable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it provide the same level of tucking quality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it take less time to construct?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very quickly I can answer, it takes WAY less time to make. It took 55 minutes for me to make one of these panels. I went from 6 stitches to 1 stitch. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful that the placement of the eye all the way up in the corner is a benefit, although that needs to be tested a bunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears the tuck is fine as well. However I am trying out new materials and it looks like I need to adjust my sizing for these other materials so they function perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More experiments with these fabrics coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-15:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-15-new-construction-method</guid></item><item><title>First Gaff for another person in a while</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-13-first-in-a-while</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I met up with a cool girl I met online for a second time today. This time to make a gaff for her and see what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMG!!! DUDE! THIS THING IS SO PERFECT!&lt;br&gt;
I'm seriously shocked right now. This is like the tightest and most comfortable tuck I've ever had!&lt;br&gt;
Thank you so much!!!!!&lt;br&gt;
Seriously!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew. It took me a lot longer tha normal to make it so I wasn't there to get initial reactions. But I am very happy to have made another person this happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-13:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-13-first-in-a-while</guid></item><item><title>Pride in progress on the Liner Gaff</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-10-pride-in-progress</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am proud of all I have done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I explored and experimented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I faced my shame regarding tucking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I kept working at it even when I was disheartened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pushed myself to share it with people, regardless of how scary that was&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created a website to show people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am proud of how well this functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and how painless it is compared to its competitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I so easily fall into shame and fear when I want to tell people about my gaff. It's not perfect. The elastic is too thick right now. The hooks still often create tiny bumps because I haven't quite figured out the perfect placement. The back of the panel still bunches up and can sometimes pinch. I haven't found a way to resolve that yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I have done is remarkable, note worthy and worth sharing. One day I'll stop having to fight myself at all and purely believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for letting me share what I have to be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-10:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-10-pride-in-progress</guid></item><item><title>Introducing: The Liner Gaff</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.github.io/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-07-omg-liner-gaff</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Liner Gaff is a personal project I have been working on for a few years now to create a gaff that fits the needs of those who tuck daily/regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After trying nearly every kind of commercial option and do it yourself option, I was disenchanted. These options were expensive, cheap, bulky, ugly, or painful. So I began experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came up with a list of lofty features and kept aiming for them. As of today, I feel I have met these features more so than nearly all other gaff options out there. I hope by sharing this with the world it can get even closer to meeting those goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggle a lot with the balance of authenticity and veneer. I truly believe in the progress I have made with this gaff design and the improvements yet to come. However this ethical quandary of authenticity versus propaganda keeps my stomach churning. Do I sell? or undersell? How do I create realness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all this time, energy, and experimenting. As I grow out of shame, fear, and pain, I am ready to share my project with the world. I am so proud of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-to-expect"&gt;What to Expect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very happy to have this website up, and cannot wait to keep updating everyone with the progress I am making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want as much feedback as I can get so I can make something that valuable for all my siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll also see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts about theory and goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates about materials/design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compelling feedback from people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milestones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In person visits with people who try it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am preparing to head south for a couple months very soon. I will be on the road, and hopefully meeting up with as many people as possible, making gaffs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.github.io,2017-10-07:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-07-omg-liner-gaff</guid></item></channel></rss>