<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vanessa  Luna - updates</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>The importance of proper measurements</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2018-05-04-measurements-importance</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So, in my years on HRT now, I have gone up and down on my doses A LOT, and consequently, my junk has changed many times... 🤐 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point is, I have not worn one of my gaffs in a while for a couple reasons. I tried a couple on in the last few days and they do not fit as well before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it truly is important for me to have a way to measure how large your genitals are while flaccid in some way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this, is the whole reason I have struggled to finish this project. How the heck do you get the right measurements AND explain how to get them succinctly? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not over, just persistantly delayed. Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2018-05-04:/linergaff/blog/a/2018-05-04-measurements-importance</guid></item><item><title>Pride in progress on the Liner Gaff</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-10-pride-in-progress</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am proud of all I have done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I explored and experimented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I faced my shame regarding tucking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I kept working at it even when I was disheartened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pushed myself to share it with people, regardless of how scary that was&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created a website to show people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am proud of how well this functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and how painless it is compared to its competitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I so easily fall into shame and fear when I want to tell people about my gaff. It's not perfect. The elastic is too thick right now. The hooks still often create tiny bumps because I haven't quite figured out the perfect placement. The back of the panel still bunches up and can sometimes pinch. I haven't found a way to resolve that yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I have done is remarkable, note worthy and worth sharing. One day I'll stop having to fight myself at all and purely believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for letting me share what I have to be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-10-10:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-10-pride-in-progress</guid></item><item><title>Introducing: The Liner Gaff</title><link>https://vanessa-luna.life/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-07-omg-liner-gaff</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Liner Gaff is a personal project I have been working on for a few years now to create a gaff that fits the needs of those who tuck daily/regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After trying nearly every kind of commercial option and do it yourself option, I was disenchanted. These options were expensive, cheap, bulky, ugly, or painful. So I began experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came up with a list of lofty features and kept aiming for them. As of today, I feel I have met these features more so than nearly all other gaff options out there. I hope by sharing this with the world it can get even closer to meeting those goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggle a lot with the balance of authenticity and veneer. I truly believe in the progress I have made with this gaff design and the improvements yet to come. However this ethical quandary of authenticity versus propaganda keeps my stomach churning. Do I sell? or undersell? How do I create realness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all this time, energy, and experimenting. As I grow out of shame, fear, and pain, I am ready to share my project with the world. I am so proud of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-to-expect"&gt;What to Expect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very happy to have this website up, and cannot wait to keep updating everyone with the progress I am making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want as much feedback as I can get so I can make something that valuable for all my siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll also see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts about theory and goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates about materials/design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compelling feedback from people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milestones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In person visits with people who try it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am preparing to head south for a couple months very soon. I will be on the road, and hopefully meeting up with as many people as possible, making gaffs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Luna Umbra</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:vanessa-luna.life,2017-10-07:/linergaff/blog/a/2017-10-07-omg-liner-gaff</guid></item></channel></rss>